<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>MTG on Mischa van den Burg</title>
    <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/mtg/</link>
    <description>Recent content in MTG on Mischa van den Burg</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/mtg/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>I went to my first Magic The Gathering pre-release</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/mtg-first-prerelease-ixalan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/mtg-first-prerelease-ixalan/</guid>
      <description>Saturday I went to my first Magic: The Gathering event. It was the pre-release of the new set: Lost Caverns of Ixalan.
I went to Almere because a colleague is a regular participant of the events that are organized by the game store and I went with him. It was nice to have a familiar face on my first event. I arrived early and there were already a few people hovering around the game store.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Saturday I went to my first Magic: The Gathering event. It was the pre-release of the new set: Lost Caverns of Ixalan.</p>
<p>I went to Almere because a colleague is a regular participant of the events that are organized by the game store and I went with him. It was nice to have a familiar face on my first event. I arrived early and there were already a few people hovering around the game store.</p>
<p>When the store opened we received our pre-release packs and we walked to the event location. There you build a 40 card deck from the 6 draft boosters you received. I had planned to build a very simple deck with lots of creatures and some removal spells, but unfortunately my packs did not contain any dinosaurs or good big creatures but it contained a ton of complex artifacts and enchantments instead. When I was sorting through my cards I was feeling a bit overwhelmed.</p>
<p>At the beginning of the event I chatted with the organizer and told him this was my first event, and he very kindly offered me some deck building help. So I called for his help and with him we built a very cool artifact based red-white deck with lots of removal and a few sneaky flying creatures.</p>
<p>The event is run from the Magic Companion app. When the event starts you are assigned a table number and an opponent and then you play 3 games, and the best of 3 wins. I thought this was a very good system because it connects you to new people and you don&rsquo;t have to be afraid that you don&rsquo;t know anybody at the event because the matchup is done through the app. The app also takes your winrate into consideration so you are paired up to people of your own skill level.</p>
<p>The deck I built (with some help) turned out to work pretty well! My end result was 1 win, 1 loss and 3 draws. Sometimes I just had to play very defensively and cast a lot of removal but that seemed to have worked because it prevented me from losing and I even got a few wins. Even though it was not the deck I had expected or hoped to build I still had a lot of fun and I learned a lot about the old and new mechanics by playing this deck.</p>
<p>The day before the event I realized it was going to last from 9:30 to 17:30 and I was quite overwhelmed with that thought. Am I really going to be able to play with good concentration for 8 hours straight? I was already asking my colleague if it was possible to leave earlier.</p>
<p>It turned out very differently though. Like they say, time flies when you are having fun. We did not start building our decks until 10:30 and the first matches were played at around 11:30 so it was only the afternoon of actual playtime. And I noticed that when I had a few rounds with my deck under my belt I was quite cabable of thinking through the strategies every single turn until the last game. The thrill of the game was actually providing me with more energy as I played.</p>
<p>All in all it was a great experience. The people were all very friendly and welcoming to a new player like me. They were patient when I needed some time to think, they helped me when I didn&rsquo;t understand a mechanic and they even tolerated a few plays which were technically not allowed.</p>
<p>Participating in an event like this is part of getting out of my comfort zone. Being an introvert who loves to spend time alone, I&rsquo;m forcing myself to broaden my horizons and so far it has been an enriching experience. I&rsquo;m seeing more and more value in community and social interaction. A MTG event is perfect because we are all nerds, most of us introverts and outcasts in some way or another and we have a format and an activity to facilitate social interaction.</p>
<p>When I drove home I realized that I had expected to be very tired after the event but actually I noticed I felt quite energized because of all the learning and mental stimulation I received. This is definitely something I am going to explore more. Thank you Beeldverhaal Almere!</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202311121011</p>
<p>[[Magic the Gathering]]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m really getting into Magic: The Gathering</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/getting-into-magic-the-gathering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/getting-into-magic-the-gathering/</guid>
      <description>Only a few weeks ago I encountered Magic: The Gathering again because an old friend showed me his collection at his house. It rekindled an interest in me, because I had a small collection when I was a kid. My friend invited me to join a game night with him so I had to prepare a bit.
I started reading up on the internet and then I discovered MTG Arena where you can play Magic: The Gathering online for free.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Only a few weeks ago I encountered Magic: The Gathering again because an old friend showed me his collection at his house. It rekindled an interest in me, because I had a small collection when I was a kid. My friend invited me to join a game night with him so I had to prepare a bit.</p>
<p>I started reading up on the internet and then I discovered MTG Arena where you can play Magic: The Gathering online for free. I haven&rsquo;t been gaming at all for about a year, but as I wanted to introduce <a href="/zet/more-play">more play</a> into my life and become a little less rigid, I devoted some time to relearning the game and I am getting a lot of fun and relaxation out of it.</p>
<p>There are a few reasons why I think MTG is a great game for me:</p>
<ul>
<li>Online and IRL playability</li>
<li>Short games</li>
<li>Does not require a lot of time</li>
<li>Can tolerate long breaks</li>
<li>Tinkering with decks</li>
<li>Strategic thinking and reading opponents</li>
<li>Lots of data and statistiscs to look at and to analyze</li>
<li>Large playerbase and community</li>
<li>Way of connecting to friends and brother</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="mindfulness">Mindfulness</h1>
<p>A game of Magic is quite an intense affair. There are many variables that you need to hold in your mind. You need to remember all of the abilities of the cards on your current board, and you have to constantly watch every move the opponent makes. This keeps me in a state of high concentration and in the present moment.</p>
<h1 id="strategic-thinking">Strategic thinking</h1>
<p>I remember the game was quite overwhelming when I was younger. Now that I&rsquo;m older and have a better grasp of the rules and possibilities, I really appreciate how deep the strategy can go.The many phases of the turn allow you to time your spells perfectly, lure your opponent into traps or to completely mess your whole game up by one misplay.</p>
<p>Strategy also happens when you are building or selecting a deck. I don&rsquo;t have any good cards yet, but I love the idea of crafting a deck for a specific opponent because you know he likes a particular color or has a particular playstyle.</p>
<p>Another element of strategy is reading your opponent in game. You can see it when people get a little nervous and start shifting around, or when they are bluffing. There are so many elements to this that transfer to real life as well and I think it is a great exercise in reading people.</p>
<p>Lastly, the game forces you to think ahead and simulate all sorts of scenarios in your head in a matter of seconds. You have to plan which creatures you are going to play, when you are going to play them, and how your opponent is going to react. If you see that your opponent has a bit of mana left and a few cards in his hand, you can expect him to cast some sort of spell to remove your juicy 6/6 flying from the board the moment you cast it.</p>
<h1 id="online-and-irl-playability">Online and IRL playability</h1>
<p>It&rsquo;s very convenient that I can play whenever I want online and that I can test out different decks to learn the ropes. But I love that it is not <em>only</em> an online game but that I can meet up with others and play it in real life as well. My online gaming skills will transfer to the tabletop game and vice versa.</p>
<p>The ability to play this game in real life is very important to me. It will provide me with a new hobby, a way of connecting to others and to join a new community.</p>
<h1 id="short-games">Short games</h1>
<p>The games online are quite short, ranging from about 5 to 12 minutes, but sometimes you have a longer match when both oponnents play the long game. But it&rsquo;s nice that I can play a game here and there when I have some time, rather than having to devote larger blocks of time such as when playing an RPG or strategy game.</p>
<h1 id="does-not-require-a-lot-of-time">Does not require a lot of time</h1>
<p>You can go as deep as you want but the basics can be learned in an afternoon.</p>
<p>However, even though it does not require time, it can still be a time sink. Already I&rsquo;m reading a lot of articles and watching YouTube videos, which is something I enjoy doing.</p>
<p>It completely depends how nerdy you want to be about it, and I seem to be going full nerd these days.</p>
<h1 id="can-tolerate-long-breaks">Can tolerate long breaks</h1>
<p>The card sets rotate, but there are formats where all card sets are legal. I can easily take a break from this game for a while and come back to it, without fearing that everything has changed or that it needs a lot of time to get back into again. I haven&rsquo;t played magic in 15 years but it took me only an afternoon to get back into it.</p>
<p>It is harder to leave an RPG in the middle of the story, or a Paradox game. Strategy games by Paradox tend to undergo a lot of development and I&rsquo;ve found that I have to re-learn all of the mechanics after I take a break.</p>
<h1 id="tinkering-with-decks">Tinkering with decks</h1>
<p>This is more for the future because I&rsquo;m still a noob and have a lot of learning to do, but I love the idea of constructing decks around certain themes which deploy a certain strategy.</p>
<h1 id="lots-of-data-and-statistics-to-look-at-and-to-analyze">Lots of data and statistics to look at and to analyze</h1>
<p>When playing the online version I can use extensions to track my games, win rates and I&rsquo;m a sucker for gathering data. I&rsquo;m already doing it for my weight and running and it is so satisfying to see the graph curves go into the direction you want. I started using these extensions from day 1 and it is going to be very interesting to see my own progress.</p>
<p>You can also build your own decks and track how they do against certain other decks, I love it.</p>
<p>Then there is drafting where you pick out a card from booster packs and create a deck with it on the spot. There is an website called <a href="https://www.17lands.com/">17lands</a> entirely devoted to gathering data and tracking card win rates. I love the idea of using data as a strategic advantage when creating a deck during a draft.</p>
<h1 id="large-player-base-and-community">Large player base and community</h1>
<p>The game has been around for a long time and there are plenty of people playing it. My friend invited me into his group now, and I also saw there is a local group in my hometown which I&rsquo;ll contact. And it will be fun to participate in an event in the future, perhaps.</p>
<h1 id="way-of-connecting-to-friends-and-brother">Way of connecting to friends and brother</h1>
<p>Lastly, my brother also started getting into Magic when I showed it to him. We&rsquo;re playing online games together now, and for the past few weeks we&rsquo;ve been meeting up and playing our LOTR starter decks against each other.</p>
<p>It is proving to be a wonderful bonding activity between me and him because in-between matches we are having conversations and enjoying spending time with each other.</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>[[Magic the Gathering]]</p>
<p>[[mtg-drafting]]</p>
<p>202310142110</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
