<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Go on Mischa van den Burg</title>
    <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/go/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Go on Mischa van den Burg</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/go/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>I started to learn Go!</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/start-learning-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/start-learning-go/</guid>
      <description>For month&amp;rsquo;s I considered to learn Go, and today I finally started.
I doubted for a long time, because I figured it would be better to dive deeper into Python. However, when I reflected on it, I realized I&amp;rsquo;m able to do the things I want to do in Python. I can create scripts to manipulate data, and I can string different tools and libraries together if I need to. So how deep do I actually need to go as a DevOps Engineer?</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For month&rsquo;s I considered to learn Go, and today I finally started.</p>
<p>I doubted for a long time, because I figured it would be better to dive deeper into Python. However, when I reflected on it, I realized I&rsquo;m able to do the things I want to do in Python. I can create scripts to manipulate data, and I can string different tools and libraries together if I need to. So how deep do I actually need to go as a DevOps Engineer?</p>
<p>The breakthrough came when I discovered this website: <a href="https://goodfirstissue.dev/language/go">Good First Issue</a>. It&rsquo;s a collection of issues in open source projects which are suitable for people who are starting out. Scrolling through the available projects for Python and Go, I noticed I got a lot more energy from the things I saw in the Go list: Grafana, ArgoCD, Kubernetes. I probably have a long way to go before I can make any meaningful contributions, but my goal is to be able to contribute to open source in the future.</p>
<p>Additionally, I&rsquo;m going to focus my career in the direction of Kubernetes and CNCF, where Go is mostly used.</p>
<p>I have a week off before I start my new job so I&rsquo;m going to spend a few hours a day to get a good start, and when I&rsquo;m working full time again, my plan is to spend at least one pomodoro (25 minutes) a day on Go. Small increments will add up to something big over time.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
