<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Go on Mischa van den Burg</title>
    <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/go/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Go on Mischa van den Burg</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/go/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to continuously run a Go file while coding in the terminal</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/running-go-on-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/running-go-on-change/</guid>
      <description>I do all my coding and note taking in the terminal using tmux and neovim. I picked up a nice trick from Rob Muhlenstein today.
You can use this command in a split window to keep running a Go file. It will update when you save the file.
entr -c bash -c &amp;quot;go run main.go&amp;quot; &amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt; main.go
Entr runs commands when files change. Here we are feeding it only one file, but you can also feed it a directory like so:</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I do all my coding and note taking in the terminal using tmux and neovim. I picked up a nice trick from Rob Muhlenstein today.</p>
<p>You can use this command in a split window to keep running a Go file. It will update when you save the file.</p>
<p><code>entr -c bash -c &quot;go run main.go&quot; &lt;&lt;&lt; main.go</code></p>
<p>Entr runs commands when files change. Here we are feeding it only one file, but you can also feed it a directory like so:</p>
<p><code>find src/ | entr -s 'make'</code></p>
<p>Super handy to see the outcome of your code changes in real time.</p>
<p>I picked this up while going through Rob&rsquo;s Beginner Boost of 2022:</p>
<p><a href="https://youtu.be/kwrN3jbv4sE">https://youtu.be/kwrN3jbv4sE</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Go Day 1: Notes</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/go-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/go-day-1/</guid>
      <description>The CTO of my new company recommended the Udemy course &amp;ldquo;Go: The Complete Developer&amp;rsquo;s Guide (Golang)&amp;rdquo;. I started today and here are some notes I made.
Hello World in Go We start by writing a Hello World and studying all the elements.
package main import &amp;#34;fmt&amp;#34; func main() { fmt.Println(&amp;#34;Hello World!&amp;#34;) } How do we run code? go run main.go runs the program go build main.go compiles it to an executable</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The CTO of my new company recommended the Udemy course &ldquo;Go: The Complete Developer&rsquo;s Guide (Golang)&rdquo;. I started today and here are some notes I made.</p>
<h1 id="hello-world-in-go">Hello World in Go</h1>
<p>We start by writing a Hello World and studying all the elements.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"><code class="language-go" data-lang="go"><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="kn">package</span> <span class="nx">main</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="kn">import</span> <span class="s">&#34;fmt&#34;</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="kd">func</span> <span class="nf">main</span><span class="p">()</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="nx">fmt</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nf">Println</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s">&#34;Hello World!&#34;</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="p">}</span>
</span></span></code></pre></div><h3 id="how-do-we-run-code">How do we run code?</h3>
<p><code>go run main.go</code> runs the program
<code>go build main.go</code> compiles it to an executable</p>
<h3 id="what-does-package-main-mean">What does package main mean?</h3>
<p><code>package main</code></p>
<p>A package is a collection of common source code files.</p>
<p>One app is a package. If you have multiple files in a folder, such as helper.go or support.go, they should have <code>package main</code> to indicate that they belong to package main.</p>
<p>*Why do we call it main?</p>
<p>There are two types of packages.</p>
<ul>
<li>executable
<ul>
<li>generates file that can be run</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>reusable
<ul>
<li>used as &ldquo;helpers&rdquo;</li>
<li>reusable logic</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>When you call the package <code>main</code>, you are telling the compiler it needs to be compiled as an executable. If it  has a different name, it won&rsquo;t generate an executable. Main is sacred.</p>
<p>Any other name is a reusable or dependency type package (helper code).</p>
<p>Another important point is that whenever you create an executable package, it must always have a func called &lsquo;main&rsquo;.</p>
<h3 id="what-does-import-fmt-mean">What does import fmt mean?</h3>
<p>The import statement is used to give our package access to code written in another package.  You are saying &ldquo;give access to all code in fmt&rdquo;. Fmt is a standard library package included in Go. Short for format. Used to print out information to the terminal.</p>
<p>Other packages included in the standard library of go are debug, math, encoding, crypto, io.</p>
<p>golang.org/pkg for documentation on standard library packages for Go.</p>
<p>A lot of learning go is learning the standard packages and how they work.</p>
<h3 id="organizing-the-maingo-file">Organizing the main.go file</h3>
<p>It is the same for every go file, just like the code example at the top of the page. Package main, import fmt, and func main.</p>
<h1 id="variable-declarations">variable declarations</h1>
<p><code>var card string = &quot;Ace of Spades&quot;</code></p>
<p>var: we are about to create a new variable</p>
<p>card: name</p>
<p>string = telling the go compiler that only strings will be assigned to this variable</p>
<h3 id="alternatively">Alternatively:</h3>
<p><code>card := &quot;Ace of Spades&quot;</code></p>
<p>Here you are relying on the compiler to figure out what type it is.</p>
<p>Compiler will infer the type.</p>
<p>We only use this := assignment for <strong>new variables</strong></p>
<p>If you want to assign a value to a variable after it is declared, you just do <code>card = &quot;Five of Diamonds&quot;</code></p>
<h3 id="go-types">Go types</h3>
<p>Go is  a statically typed language.</p>
<p>Javascript, python are dynamically typed language. We don&rsquo;t care what value is assigned to a variable.</p>
<p>You always a assign a type to a variable in Go.</p>
<p>Basic go types:</p>
<ul>
<li>bool</li>
<li>string</li>
<li>into</li>
<li>float64 : a number with a decimal after it.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I started to learn Go!</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/start-learning-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/start-learning-go/</guid>
      <description>For month&amp;rsquo;s I considered to learn Go, and today I finally started.
I doubted for a long time, because I figured it would be better to dive deeper into Python. However, when I reflected on it, I realized I&amp;rsquo;m able to do the things I want to do in Python. I can create scripts to manipulate data, and I can string different tools and libraries together if I need to. So how deep do I actually need to go as a DevOps Engineer?</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For month&rsquo;s I considered to learn Go, and today I finally started.</p>
<p>I doubted for a long time, because I figured it would be better to dive deeper into Python. However, when I reflected on it, I realized I&rsquo;m able to do the things I want to do in Python. I can create scripts to manipulate data, and I can string different tools and libraries together if I need to. So how deep do I actually need to go as a DevOps Engineer?</p>
<p>The breakthrough came when I discovered this website: <a href="https://goodfirstissue.dev/language/go">Good First Issue</a>. It&rsquo;s a collection of issues in open source projects which are suitable for people who are starting out. Scrolling through the available projects for Python and Go, I noticed I got a lot more energy from the things I saw in the Go list: Grafana, ArgoCD, Kubernetes. I probably have a long way to go before I can make any meaningful contributions, but my goal is to be able to contribute to open source in the future.</p>
<p>Additionally, I&rsquo;m going to focus my career in the direction of Kubernetes and CNCF, where Go is mostly used.</p>
<p>I have a week off before I start my new job so I&rsquo;m going to spend a few hours a day to get a good start, and when I&rsquo;m working full time again, my plan is to spend at least one pomodoro (25 minutes) a day on Go. Small increments will add up to something big over time.</p>
<p>I created <a href="https://github.com/mischavandenburg/go">a new GitHub repo</a> where I&rsquo;ll be uploading all my practice code and projects.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
