<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Travel on Mischa van den Burg</title>
    <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/travel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Travel on Mischa van den Burg</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/travel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Started Using Tumblr for Travel Blogging</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/started-using-tumblr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/started-using-tumblr/</guid>
      <description>With the spring finally being fully released on the Netherlands, my wanderlust has awakened again after lying dormant for two years. In my 9 years in Norway I became a seasoned outdoorsman spending much time roaming the mountains and forests and always spending days or weeks out in the wild with my tent.
When I moved back to the Netherlands this has been put on hold for a couple of years while I focused on changing my career on IT.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With the spring finally being fully released on the Netherlands, my wanderlust has awakened again after lying dormant for two years. In my 9 years in Norway I became a seasoned outdoorsman spending much time roaming the mountains and forests and always spending days or weeks out in the wild with my tent.</p>
<p>When I moved back to the Netherlands this has been put on hold for a couple of years while I focused on changing my career on IT. Now that the career is rolling along nicely by the looks of it, I&rsquo;m super excited to start exploring the Netherlands and see what the outdoors life is like in an area where the nature is significantly less wild and abundant.</p>
<p>I needed a solution to post pictures quickly and easily because I want to start logging my trips as well. My hugo setup is great for text and techincal content but I need something where I can easily post straight from my phone and Tumblr seems like the best option. I&rsquo;ll also be posting more on Instagram from here on out.</p>
<p>Here is my first post:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.tumblr.com/mischavandenburg/717301155801235456/went-to-heemskerk-today-broke-my-running-record?source=share">https://www.tumblr.com/mischavandenburg/717301155801235456/went-to-heemskerk-today-broke-my-running-record?source=share</a></p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202305141505</p>
<p><a href="https://www.tumblr.com/mischavandenburg">https://www.tumblr.com/mischavandenburg</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
