<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>exercise on Mischa van den Burg</title>
    <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/exercise/</link>
    <description>Recent content in exercise on Mischa van den Burg</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/exercise/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Book Notes: Finding Ultra By Rich Roll</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/book-notes-finding-ultra-rich-roll/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/book-notes-finding-ultra-rich-roll/</guid>
      <description>Rich Roll has been a familiar face to me for many years. I first came across him about 7 years ago when I made my first explorations into plant based nutrition. I believe the documentary &amp;ldquo;Forks over Knives&amp;rdquo; was the first time I saw him. I recently read &amp;ldquo;Finding Ultra&amp;rdquo; by Rich Roll, which documents the journey from being an overweight and unhappy lawyer to becoming one of the world&amp;rsquo;s fittest men and a vegan ultra-endurance athlete.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Rich Roll has been a familiar face to me for many years. I first came across him about 7 years ago when I made my first explorations into plant based nutrition. I believe the documentary &ldquo;Forks over Knives&rdquo; was the first time I saw him. I recently read &ldquo;Finding Ultra&rdquo; by Rich Roll, which documents the journey from being an overweight and unhappy lawyer to becoming one of the world&rsquo;s fittest men and a vegan ultra-endurance athlete. I&rsquo;ve always appreciated his podcasts and his way of presenting himself, so it was great to learn about his journey.</p>
<p>In this book, Rich shares his story of how he overcame alcoholism, depression, and poor health by adopting a plant-based diet and a rigorous training regimen. He also describes his amazing feats of endurance, such as completing five Ironman-distance triathlons on five Hawaiian islands in under a week.</p>
<p>As someone who is already eating a plant-based diet, I still found this book very inspiring. It affirmed to me that you can be a high-performance athlete as a vegan. I have started running early this year and I have made a lot of progress. I recently ran 12 kilometres for the first time. This book has inspired me to clean up my diet even more and train harder and to search out my limits.</p>
<p>Here are some of the quotes from the book that I highlighted, which resonated with me:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;The solution is spiritual.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Safety isn’t just an illusion, it’s a cop-out.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;When you believe you’ve reached your absolute limit, you’ve only tapped into about 40 percent of what you’re truly capable of.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Bliss in depletion. I finally got it. It’s that beautiful place of ascetic purity that is permitted to bloom only when the mind is stopped dead in its tracks and everything else is stripped away, leaving your soul—or who you really are—to forge a connection with the truth.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;It’s not an exaggeration to say that my EPIC5 experience had been fueled in large part by avocados, grapeseed oil–based Vegenaise, and coconut water.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Some of the key takeaways that I learned from this book are:</p>
<ul>
<li>Change is possible at any age, but it requires commitment, discipline, and faith.</li>
<li>Plant-based nutrition can enhance health, performance, and recovery.</li>
<li>Endurance sports are not only physical, but also mental and spiritual challenges.</li>
<li>Finding your purpose and passion can give you the motivation and courage to overcome any obstacle.</li>
<li>Living authentically and gratefully is the ultimate reward.</li>
</ul>
<p>I highly recommend this book to anyone who is interested in personal growth, veganism, or endurance sports. It is a captivating and uplifting story that will make you rethink what you are capable of.</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202307240707</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcast Notes - Optimal Water Intake</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/optimal-hydration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/optimal-hydration/</guid>
      <description>Hydration Notes from Huberman Podcast For the first 10 hours of the day, consume 236ml for every hour awake
During exercise, follow Galpin equation: 2ml per kg of bodyweight every 15-20 minutes on average.
This does not mean you need to stop exercising and drink this amount. You can also consume it in a larger amount afterwards. It is recommended to drink during exercise though.
Use the normal recommendation to hydrate before exercise, this establishes a good baseline for heading into exercise.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="hydration-notes-from-huberman-podcast">Hydration Notes from Huberman Podcast</h1>
<p>For the first 10 hours of the day, consume 236ml for every hour awake</p>
<p>During exercise, follow Galpin equation: 2ml per kg of bodyweight every 15-20 minutes on average.</p>
<p>This does not mean you need to stop exercising and drink this amount. You can also consume it in a larger amount afterwards. It is recommended to drink during exercise though.</p>
<p>Use the normal recommendation to hydrate before exercise, this establishes a good baseline for heading into exercise.</p>
<h2 id="is-this-amount-of-water-on-top-of-the-baseline-hydration">Is this amount of water on top of the baseline hydration?</h2>
<p>If you exercise about an hour you can replace the number with the number from the Galpin equation.</p>
<p>In my case, 1 hour of exercise = 77 * 2 = 154ml every 20 minutes</p>
<p>154 * 3 = 462ml for 1 hour of exercise</p>
<h2 id="caffeine">Caffeine</h2>
<p>Offset caffeine drinks with a 2:1 water ratio.</p>
<p>So 1 240ml cup of coffee should be followed by 480ml of water.</p>
<h2 id="reducing-nightly-urination">Reducing Nightly Urination</h2>
<p>Urine secretion / filtration in the kidneys is highly dependent on the circadian rhythm.</p>
<p>It is normal to wake up once or twice to urinate during the night.</p>
<p>To reduce nighttime waking for urination:</p>
<ul>
<li>Ensure sufficient hydration during the day so you are not thirsty in the evening</li>
<li>Reduce fluid intake at night (provided you hydrated sufficiently during the day)</li>
<li>Consume no more than 180-240ml between 10 hours after waking and bedtime</li>
</ul>
<p>This means, waking up at 6am, only drink 1 cup of tea after 4pm.</p>
<p>But I drink 500ml at dinner time, so I should probably never drink after dinner from here on out, or just one cup of tea.</p>
<p>How quickly you secrete fluid is also partially determined by how quickly you drink that fluid. Gulping down a lot of fluid wil lead to quicker secretion.</p>
<h1 id="my-typical-day">My Typical Day</h1>
<p>1 hour exercise = 500ml</p>
<p>2 cups of coffee 500ml</p>
<p>10 hours = 2,4l</p>
<p>So I should be drinking about 3,25L in total a day!</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202305301905</p>
<p><a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/gb/podcast/huberman-lab/id1545953110?i=1000602925839">https://podcasts.apple.com/gb/podcast/huberman-lab/id1545953110?i=1000602925839</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Went on My First Camping Trip After Moving Back to NL From Norway</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/first-camping-trip-in-netherlands/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/first-camping-trip-in-netherlands/</guid>
      <description>It was a nice week. I had an extra day off on Asenscion day and I decided to go for a camping trip for the first time after I moved back to the Netherlands.
It was a great experience, and I wrote a couple of Tumblr posts with photos:
https://www.tumblr.com/mischavandenburg/718093517925367808/first-trip-in-the-netherlands-part-1?source=share
https://www.tumblr.com/mischavandenburg/718098930739593216/part-2?source=share
Links: 202305232005
[[outdoors]]</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It was a nice week. I had an extra day off on Asenscion day and I decided to go for a camping trip for the first time after I moved back to the Netherlands.</p>
<p>It was a great experience, and I wrote a couple of Tumblr posts with photos:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.tumblr.com/mischavandenburg/718093517925367808/first-trip-in-the-netherlands-part-1?source=share">https://www.tumblr.com/mischavandenburg/718093517925367808/first-trip-in-the-netherlands-part-1?source=share</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.tumblr.com/mischavandenburg/718098930739593216/part-2?source=share">https://www.tumblr.com/mischavandenburg/718098930739593216/part-2?source=share</a></p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202305232005</p>
<p>[[outdoors]]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exercise Stimulates Creativity And Motivation</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/exercise-stimulates-creativity-and-motivation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/exercise-stimulates-creativity-and-motivation/</guid>
      <description>I noticed multiple times now that during my workouts my mind is generating lots of new ideas for coding projects or blog posts. It is a well known fact that walking stimulates areas in the brain that which will in turn stimulate creativity. But I&amp;rsquo;m noticing that it starts to happen with strength workouts as well.
Although I don&amp;rsquo;t struggle with the motivation to get myself to the gym, I sometimes feel &amp;ldquo;guilty&amp;rdquo; for not spending that time on coding or studying.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I noticed multiple times now that during my workouts my mind is generating lots of new ideas for coding projects or blog posts. It is a well known fact that walking stimulates areas in the brain that which will in turn stimulate creativity. But I&rsquo;m noticing that it starts to happen with strength workouts as well.</p>
<p>Although I don&rsquo;t struggle with the motivation to get myself to the gym, I sometimes feel &ldquo;guilty&rdquo; for not spending that time on coding or studying. I&rsquo;m realizing now that this is a very irrational train of thought.</p>
<p>Exercise actually stimulates my creativity and will help generating new ideas or help me understand concepts better in the unconscious. It is also massively beneficial for health and general well being. When general well-being is enhanced I&rsquo;ll also be able to focus better and absorb information more quickly.</p>
<p>I should re-frame my thinking and actually put exercise as priority number 1. Exercise time is never wasted time. It indirectly contributes to my productivity and coding endeavours as well.</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202304011104</p>
<p>[[exercise]]</p>
<p>[[health]]</p>
<p>[[focus]]</p>
<p>[[productivity]]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I ran 5K for the first time in my life!</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/ran-5km/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/ran-5km/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I reached a significant milestone. I ran my first 5K!
I&amp;rsquo;ve always been on the heavy side. I did a lot of weightlifting from age 18 to around 27 and I was always rather bulky, but very strong. This meant I was very good at working in the woods or helping people move house, but I&amp;rsquo;ve never been able to do any running or endurance because my knees would start protesting very quickly.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday I reached a significant milestone. I ran my first 5K!</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve always been on the heavy side. I did a lot of weightlifting from age 18 to around 27 and I was always rather bulky, but very strong. This meant I was very good at working in the woods or helping people move house, but I&rsquo;ve never been able to do any running or endurance because my knees would start protesting very quickly. However, I always admired endurance athletes and I had the desire to be able to run more than a few minutes without feeling the urge to die on the spot.</p>
<p>Over the past 1,5 years I lost 20kg (~44 pounds) so I decided to give it yet another try.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve never been this lightweight so I decided to give running another try. I started small with only 10 minutes but over the course of two months I built it up gradually.</p>
<p>Last week I ran 4km and it felt pretty good, so I just decided to push a little bit more and try for my goal of 5k, and it went well! It feels like quite an accomplishment to me.</p>
<p>Now that I lost all this weight running actually feels good, and it is liberating to discover a whole new area of exercise that I haven&rsquo;t explored yet: endurance. Looking back to my progress over a couple of months, I&rsquo;m curious how far I&rsquo;ll come and what my limits are.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
