<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Video on Mischa van den Burg</title>
    <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/video/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Video on Mischa van den Burg</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/video/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Video: Deploying MkDocs To Azure Using With Azure DevOps</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/video-mkdocs-azure-webapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/video-mkdocs-azure-webapp/</guid>
      <description>In this video, I will walk you through the following steps:
Set up a repo in Azure DevOps with MkDocs files Set up a Static Web App in Azure portal and link it to the repo Configure the Azure DevOps pipeline for MkDocs deployment Configure a custom theme for the website Demonstrate the pull request workflow for updating the docs By the end of this video, you will have a fully functional MkDocs site hosted on Azure Static Web Apps.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_-D1Qz6jtEU" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<p>In this video, I will walk you through the following steps:</p>
<ul>
<li>Set up a repo in Azure DevOps with MkDocs files</li>
<li>Set up a Static Web App in Azure portal and link it to the repo</li>
<li>Configure the Azure DevOps pipeline for MkDocs deployment</li>
<li>Configure a custom theme for the website</li>
<li>Demonstrate the pull request workflow for updating the docs</li>
</ul>
<p>By the end of this video, you will have a fully functional MkDocs site hosted on Azure Static Web Apps. You will also learn how to use Azure DevOps and Static Web Apps to collaborate on your documentation projects.</p>
<p>MkDocs is a tool that lets you create beautiful documentation websites from plain text files. You can write your docs in Markdown, a simple and easy-to-use markup language, and MkDocs will convert them into a static HTML site. You can also customize the look and feel of your site with themes and plugins.</p>
<p>Azure Static Web Apps is a service that hosts static web content and serverless APIs. It automatically builds and deploys your web app from a GitHub or Azure DevOps repository. It also provides features such as authentication, authorization, custom domains, and SSL certificates.</p>
<p>Timestamps:</p>
<p>0:00 Intro
0:40 What is MkDocs?
2:00 Set up the repo
5:00 Create web app
9:25 Configure the pipeline
11:30 Adding a few documents
15:25 Adding a custom theme
18:00 Adding docs with a pull request
21:30 Outro</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202307281307</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video: Finishing Pipeline Setup  &amp; Working on KeyVault Template - Azure Kubernetes Lab Series</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/video-finish-pipeline-setup-aks-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/video-finish-pipeline-setup-aks-series/</guid>
      <description>Finish deploying keyvault using pipeline Get the random name generation to work Lessons Learned Subscriptions need to be registered with resource providers, apparently https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/azure-resource-manager/troubleshooting/error-register-resource-provider?tabs=azure-cli
acccesPolicies are mandatory on KeyVaults, but not when RBAC is enabled Assign contributor role to Azure DevOps service connection to be able to create resource groups from pipeline Achieved Setting up connection between pipeline and Azure subscription Assign correct rights to the service connection so it is allowed to deploy new resource groups (and other resources) Learned about provider registrations Made progress on creating unique names for resources Successfully deployed new resource group and key vault from the pipeline Next time: Look into random string creation with utcNow</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/eooZ3OHl5Mc" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<ul>
<li>Finish deploying keyvault using pipeline</li>
<li>Get the random name generation to work</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="lessons-learned">Lessons Learned</h1>
<ul>
<li>Subscriptions need to be registered with resource providers, apparently</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/azure-resource-manager/troubleshooting/error-register-resource-provider?tabs=azure-cli">https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/azure-resource-manager/troubleshooting/error-register-resource-provider?tabs=azure-cli</a></p>
<ul>
<li>acccesPolicies are mandatory on KeyVaults, but not when RBAC is enabled</li>
<li>Assign contributor role to Azure DevOps service connection to be able to create resource groups from pipeline</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="achieved">Achieved</h1>
<ul>
<li>Setting up connection between pipeline and Azure subscription</li>
<li>Assign correct rights to the service connection so it is allowed to deploy new resource groups (and other resources)</li>
<li>Learned about provider registrations</li>
<li>Made progress on creating unique names for resources</li>
<li>Successfully deployed new resource group and key vault from the pipeline</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="next-time">Next time:</h1>
<p>Look into random string creation with utcNow</p>
<p><a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/azure-resource-manager/bicep/bicep-functions-date#utcnow">https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/azure-resource-manager/bicep/bicep-functions-date#utcnow</a></p>
<p>or newGuid</p>
<p><a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/azure-resource-manager/bicep/bicep-functions-string#newguid">https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/azure-resource-manager/bicep/bicep-functions-string#newguid</a></p>
<p>Links:</p>
<p>202306281806</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202306302206</p>
<p><a href="https://youtu.be/eooZ3OHl5Mc">https://youtu.be/eooZ3OHl5Mc</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video: Setting Up A Simple Azure Pipeline To Deploy A Keyvault</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/video-aks-lab-pipeline-first-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/video-aks-lab-pipeline-first-setup/</guid>
      <description>Write KeyVault template Write pipeline code set up Azure DevOps pipeline Lessons Learned Always make sure to use az deployment group instead of az group deployment Because it has older Bicep version and will be deprecated Make sure to be in correct Directory to be able to sync subscriptions for service connection Links: 202306302206
https://youtu.be/WnA8V3uq7P8</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WnA8V3uq7P8" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<ul>
<li>Write KeyVault template</li>
<li>Write pipeline code</li>
<li>set up Azure DevOps pipeline</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="lessons-learned">Lessons Learned</h1>
<ul>
<li>Always make sure to use <code>az deployment group</code> instead of <code>az group deployment</code></li>
<li>Because it has older Bicep version and will be deprecated</li>
<li>Make sure to be in correct Directory to be able to sync subscriptions for service connection</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202306302206</p>
<p><a href="https://youtu.be/WnA8V3uq7P8">https://youtu.be/WnA8V3uq7P8</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video: Deploying an AKS Cluster with Bicep, GitHub Copilot and Neovim</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/video-deploying-aks-cluster-bicep-github-copilot/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/video-deploying-aks-cluster-bicep-github-copilot/</guid>
      <description>Inspired by a GitHub Copilot demonstration I witnessed at Microsoft, I wanted to see how quickly I could deploy an AKS cluster from Neovim with Bicep using Copilot. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t disappointed!
Links: 202306271706
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=l0B65FUfNBU
[[aks]] [[kubernetes]] [[neovim]] [[bicep]] [[coding]]</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Inspired by a GitHub Copilot demonstration I witnessed at Microsoft, I wanted to see how quickly I could deploy an AKS cluster from Neovim with Bicep using Copilot. I wasn&rsquo;t disappointed!</p>

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/l0B65FUfNBU" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202306271706</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=l0B65FUfNBU">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=l0B65FUfNBU</a></p>
<p>[[aks]]
[[kubernetes]]
[[neovim]]
[[bicep]]
[[coding]]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video: Introducing New Bicep Parameter Files - .bicepparam - No more JSON!</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/video-bicep-bicepparam/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/video-bicep-bicepparam/</guid>
      <description>The new parameter files use bicep style formatting instead of JSON, and they will make the lives of Cloud Engineers a lot easier. They have the following advantages:
More readable and editor friendly Cleaner and less lines of code VSCode integration Quickly convert from JSON or template file using VSCode In this video I introduce these new files. I go over the new formatting, and I also introduce the new features in VSCode for the .</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The new parameter files use bicep style formatting instead of JSON, and they will make the lives of Cloud Engineers a lot easier. They have the following advantages:</p>
<ul>
<li>More readable and editor friendly</li>
<li>Cleaner and less lines of code</li>
<li>VSCode integration</li>
<li>Quickly convert from JSON or template file using VSCode</li>
</ul>
<p>In this video I introduce these new files. I go over the new formatting, and I also introduce the new features in VSCode for the .bicepparam files.</p>
<p>Yes, you read that right, you&rsquo;ll be seeing a hardcore vim user switch to VSCode for this particular task!</p>

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6Gav1JpGAzo" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202306271706</p>
<p><a href="https://youtu.be/6Gav1JpGAzo">https://youtu.be/6Gav1JpGAzo</a></p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/Azure/bicep/releases/tag/v0.18.4">https://github.com/Azure/bicep/releases/tag/v0.18.4</a></p>
<p><a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/azure-resource-manager/bicep/parameter-files?tabs=Bicep">https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/azure-resource-manager/bicep/parameter-files?tabs=Bicep</a></p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/mischavandenburg/lab/tree/main/bicep/keyvault-parameters">https://github.com/mischavandenburg/lab/tree/main/bicep/keyvault-parameters</a></p>
<p>[[AKS]]
[[bicep]]
[[coding]]
[[kubernetes]]
[[azure]]
[[neovim]]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invest In Experiences For Happiness</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/invest-in-experiences-for-happiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/invest-in-experiences-for-happiness/</guid>
      <description>Happiness, Hedonic Adjustment, Experiences This was a very good video. I can honestly say that I am very happy and content, and I lead a very fulfilling life. I do not usually watch this kind of &amp;ldquo;happiness&amp;rdquo; content because I&amp;rsquo;m already happy. But this video did give me some very important insights which have influenced the way I approach money and happiness.
Memories as Dividends The main takeaway for me is to prioritize creating memories by investing in experiences.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/840iXuXwE4Y" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<h1 id="happiness-hedonic-adjustment-experiences">Happiness, Hedonic Adjustment, Experiences</h1>
<p>This was a very good video. I can honestly say that I am very happy and content, and I lead a very fulfilling life. I do not usually watch this kind of &ldquo;happiness&rdquo; content because I&rsquo;m already happy. But this video did give me some very important insights which have influenced the way I approach money and happiness.</p>
<h1 id="memories-as-dividends">Memories as Dividends</h1>
<p>The main takeaway for me is to prioritize creating memories by investing in experiences. The author phrases it very well here:</p>
<p>&ldquo;When you buy a shiny new car, every time you use it that shine wears of just a little bit. You hedonically adjust. With a memory, every time you think about it, you experience joy. Your brain cements the pathway to that memory, and you relive it in your brain, experiencing feelings of happines or nostalgia.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Hedonic adjustment happens when you become used to the things you like, and you need to have bigger and better things in order to get the same satisfaction. The Stoics, among others, counteracted this with forced deprivation: eating plain bread for a few days will make you appreciate your customary food.</p>
<p>Another very clever point which Damien makes is to see money spent on experiences as dividends:</p>
<p>&ldquo;Experiences and memories in this way are like investments in happiness, because we can call on them to release the happiness hormones in our brains that make us feel good.&rdquo;</p>
<p>They can be seen as happiness dividends. You get the initial experience and you get to re-live it again and again. And the best thing is that you don&rsquo;t hedonically adjust to these memories.</p>
<p>This definitely made me re-think my approach to fincancial happiness and independence. I am definitely going to prioritize experiences a lot more in the future.</p>
<h1 id="other-takeaways">Other Takeaways</h1>
<ul>
<li>Variety and anticipation of events or smaller purchases provides a large portion of the happiness, rather than the purchase itself</li>
<li>Make many smaller purchases rather than one big purchase</li>
<li>Take short weekend holidays rather than a big expensive 4 week holiday</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="norway">Norway</h1>
<p>A case in point is my upcoming trip to Norway. Ever since I decided on the date for the trip, I noticed my energy has increased because I&rsquo;m excited about the trip. I&rsquo;m getting a lot of joy out of the anticipation: I&rsquo;m reading up on areas to visit, going through all of my outdoor gear, and getting out into nature more because I want to connect to that Norwegian part of me. This is all rooted very deeply within me because I lived there for 9 years, and the anticipation of returning to Norway for a short time gives me so much joy.</p>
<p>By taking time off and purchasing the necesseties for my trip, I&rsquo;m investing in experiences that will create memories which in turn will provide me more happiness in the future as dividends.</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202305152005</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=840iXuXwE4Y">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=840iXuXwE4Y</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video: How I Write &amp; Publish My Blog Using Neovim &amp; Hugo From The Command Line</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/blogging-from-command-line/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/blogging-from-command-line/</guid>
      <description>I show my workflow to publish my Hugo blog from the command line using neovim and bash
Links: 202305091705</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bzkrmkGDQJA" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<p>I show my workflow to publish my Hugo blog from the command line using neovim and bash</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202305091705</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video: Creating A Command To Change Fontsize in Alacritty</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/video-custom-fontsize-command/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/video-custom-fontsize-command/</guid>
      <description>Links: 202305070805
https://youtu.be/Q8dxoqqMHAg</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Q8dxoqqMHAg" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202305070805</p>
<p><a href="https://youtu.be/Q8dxoqqMHAg">https://youtu.be/Q8dxoqqMHAg</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video: How To Read The News From The Command Line</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/reading-news-from-command-line/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/reading-news-from-command-line/</guid>
      <description>I use RSS feeds to read the news, and I use Newsboat as a RSS reader.
To in stall on MacOS: brew install newsboat
Integrate in already existing terminal workflow Free from distraction Control how content is rendered Carefully curate which content you consume Build your own &amp;ldquo;Social Media feed&amp;rdquo; No advertisements or suggested articles Newsboat uses RSS feeds which are generated by websites Links: 202304271004
https://newsboat.org/</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/08SxwJ7ZVyo" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<p>I use RSS feeds to read the news, and I use Newsboat as a RSS reader.</p>
<p>To in stall on MacOS: <code>brew install newsboat</code></p>
<ul>
<li>Integrate in already existing terminal workflow</li>
<li>Free from distraction</li>
<li>Control how content is rendered</li>
<li>Carefully curate which content you consume</li>
<li>Build your own &ldquo;Social Media feed&rdquo;</li>
<li>No advertisements or suggested articles</li>
<li>Newsboat uses RSS feeds which are generated by websites</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202304271004</p>
<p><a href="https://newsboat.org/">https://newsboat.org/</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
