<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal on Mischa van den Burg</title>
    <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal on Mischa van den Burg</description>
    <image>
      <title>Mischa van den Burg</title>
      <url>https://mischavandenburg.com/cloud-blue-logo.jpeg</url>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/cloud-blue-logo.jpeg</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.147.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Decided to split up into a technical and personal blog after all</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/splitting-to-personal-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/splitting-to-personal-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been struggling with this ever since I started blogging 2 years ago (can&amp;rsquo;t believe it&amp;rsquo;s already been that long). But I&amp;rsquo;ve finally made the decision: I&amp;rsquo;m keeping this blog at mischavandenburg.com as a tech and career focused blog where I share technical knowledge and notes, and I&amp;rsquo;m starting a new personal blog at &lt;a href=&#34;https://mischavandenburg.blog&#34;&gt;mischavandenburg.blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have fallen in love with blogging. Documenting my own life in writing has become a very therapeutic and valuable experience to me. Even if nobody reads what I put out into the world, it is incredibly satisfying to scroll through your own blog and go back in time to see what I was learning or doing or feeling at that time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m not journaling as often as I used to</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/not-journaling-as-often/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/not-journaling-as-often/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I notice that I&amp;rsquo;m not writing in my journal every day like I used to. I always wrote down what I did, what I felt, what my plans and ambitions were, every single day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During my holiday I started writing by hand in a notebook again which was really nice. It felt good to feel the pencil scratching on the paper again and to practice my cursive writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After I came back I first tried to keep journaling by hand again, but after a few days the journal remained untouched. I figured I would go back to my usual digital journaling again by writing daily notes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vacation Time!</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/vacation-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/vacation-2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve just finished my last workday and tomorrow I&amp;rsquo;m heading off to Norway! When I glance at the amount of posts I&amp;rsquo;ve made on my blog recently it&amp;rsquo;s obvious that it is time for a break from the entire routine. I&amp;rsquo;ve been tapering down to this moment for a while now, toning down the studying and prioritizing relaxation so I can enter the holidays with a clear mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now it&amp;rsquo;s time for lots of fresh air, mountains, many kilometres on the trails, and to pick up the connection to Nature I&amp;rsquo;ve made during the 9 years that I lived in the beautiful North.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Have A Personal Website?</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/why-personal-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/why-personal-website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Why bother with a personal website? Why not just write blog posts on LinkedIn?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to own my data. I want to have complete freedom. I want to write whatever I want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://matthiasott.com/notes/simple-truths-about-personal-websites&#34;&gt;This post captures it beautifully.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;202305171305&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://matthiasott.com/notes/simple-truths-about-personal-websites&#34;&gt;https://matthiasott.com/notes/simple-truths-about-personal-websites&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 Simple Japanese Habits</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/8-simple-japanese-habits/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/8-simple-japanese-habits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/04wZNnjdURE?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through YouTube I&amp;rsquo;ve been exposed to quite a bit of Japanese culture and I love many aspects of it. I love this list of habits, and I was surprised to see how many of them I already incorporate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clean the Toilet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many successful businessmen clean the toilet every day. It humbles you. Ajahn Chah also talks about this a lot. Check out &amp;ldquo;Toilets on the Path&amp;rdquo;. I&amp;rsquo;m also very focused on cleanliness and especially emphasize keeping my toilet clean. But I like the idea of cleaning it every day and I&amp;rsquo;m going to give it a try.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI Does Not Grow Exponentially, Thus, Less Scary</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/ai-does-not-grow-exponentially/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/ai-does-not-grow-exponentially/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/EKba_awaAkk?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I watch the whole AI craze from the sideline: I am interested in it but I do not spend a lot of time investigating it. But I do pick up a few things here and there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this Rich Roll podcast, Kevin Kelly argues that AI does not grow exponentially. It grows linearly, but not exponentially, because it is constrained by the infrastrucutre that we give it, and are able to give it. AI cannot grow by itself. We simply cannot provide enough computing power to enable exponential growth because the technology is not advanced enough yet, which means the growth is stunted.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Invest In Experiences For Happiness</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/invest-in-experiences-for-happiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/invest-in-experiences-for-happiness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/840iXuXwE4Y?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;happiness-hedonic-adjustment-experiences&#34;&gt;Happiness, Hedonic Adjustment, Experiences&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a very good video. I can honestly say that I am very happy and content, and I lead a very fulfilling life. I do not usually watch this kind of &amp;ldquo;happiness&amp;rdquo; content because I&amp;rsquo;m already happy. But this video did give me some very important insights which have influenced the way I approach money and happiness.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Ran 10k For The First Time Today</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/running-first-10k/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/running-first-10k/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I ran 10k for the first time in my life today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ran &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tumblr.com/mischavandenburg/717301155801235456/went-to-heemskerk-today-broke-my-running-record?source=share&#34;&gt;to the beach and back in Heemskerk&lt;/a&gt; on hardened forest roads, listening to the birds and feeling the spring sun on my face. I felt great and had a smile on my face most of the time. Lots of interesting thoughts popping up in the mind as I run and reflect. Hardly noticed that 77 minutes went by because I was having such a good time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Started Using Tumblr for Travel Blogging</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/started-using-tumblr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/started-using-tumblr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the spring finally being fully released on the Netherlands, my wanderlust has awakened again after lying dormant for two years. In my 9 years in Norway I became a seasoned outdoorsman spending much time roaming the mountains and forests and always spending days or weeks out in the wild with my tent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I moved back to the Netherlands this has been put on hold for a couple of years while I focused on changing my career on IT. Now that the career is rolling along nicely by the looks of it, I&amp;rsquo;m super excited to start exploring the Netherlands and see what the outdoors life is like in an area where the nature is significantly less wild and abundant.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I&#39;m Posting More on Social Media</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/why-post-on-social-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/why-post-on-social-media/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My recent &lt;a href=&#34;https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/everything-nothing-blog/&#34;&gt;post on E/N blogging&lt;/a&gt; led to a realization: posting on social media will be something I do for myself, instead of doing it for others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Facebook came out when I was 16 I posted quite a lot on social media. 5 years later I found it very embarassing to read back through those posts and I deleted everything, and since then I have been been holding back on social media posting and deleting my accounts several times.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Blog Is Turning Into And Everything / Nothing Website And It Feels Good</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/everything-nothing-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/everything-nothing-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Read an interesting post this morning about &lt;a href=&#34;http://sawv.org/en.html&#34;&gt;E/N websites.&lt;/a&gt; Apparently a phenomenon from the early days of the web, E/N websites meant everything to the publisher, but maybe nothing to the rest of the world. The term may have been the predecessor of the term &amp;ldquo;weblog&amp;rdquo; which was shortened to blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;E/N description: The website&amp;rsquo;s author covers a myriad of topics. It&amp;rsquo;s not narrowly focused. The author writes about everything or at least everything that&amp;rsquo;s important to the author. The site might contain something useful for anyone who visits. The content means everything to the publisher, but it could mean nothing to the rest of the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Plan For The D2R Ladder Reset</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/d2r-ladder-reset-may-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/d2r-ladder-reset-may-2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Diablo 2: one of those games in life I keep returning to. Started playing it when I was 12, and I know it inside out. Roughly once every 1,5 years I&amp;rsquo;ll have a phase where I want to play some.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m in such a phase right now. I haven&amp;rsquo;t been gaming since the Victoria 3 release, and frankly, I don&amp;rsquo;t have much time to spend either. Something will be sacrificed. Currently this will be study time. I&amp;rsquo;ve been studying for several hours a day for nearly two years, but with my current increased focus on health and weight loss, I feel I need a break and allow myself some leasure.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Saw Sabaton Live Yesterday!</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/sabaton-concert-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/sabaton-concert-2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Had a great time at the Ziggo Dome in Amsterdam yesterday. Went to see Sabaton live. This was my second time seeing them live, and it was a great show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love Sabaton because all of their material revolves around history and warfare. They are one of my favourite bands. I was super happy they played some of my favourite songs: &amp;ldquo;Carolus Rex&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Stormtroopers&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;To Hell And Back&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been a lover of metal music ever since childhood, but I had a break from metal music for about 5 years where I hardly listened to any music at all. But over the past 1,5 years I&amp;rsquo;ve been really enjoying metal music again.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vacations In The Soviet Union</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/vacations-in-soviet-union/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/vacations-in-soviet-union/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Read an interesting article this morning. Apparently the Soviet Union introduced paid time off well before other industrialized countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, but not unexpectedly, the state determined how and with whom you spent that vacation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As members of a collective, citizens were expected to spend their free time in a manner the government and its leading theorists considered beneficial to society as whole, regardless of an individual’s preferences.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever since the 1930s, it had been customary for Soviet citizens to travel in groups of 25 to 40 people randomly put together by their trade unions. When adults relaxed at resorts or embarked on tours, their children were sent to summer camps managed by state-run youth groups like the Young Pioneers or the Komsomol.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Power of Writing</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/power-of-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/power-of-writing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ah, writing. It&amp;rsquo;s one of the skills that I&amp;rsquo;ve consistently been praised for throughout my life. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty good at it, and I think that&amp;rsquo;s because I enjoy it. It led me to getting an academic degree in English Literature and Culture, simply because I was following the things I was naturally good at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, just like any other skill, you can only become better at it through consistent practice. This morning I read a wonderful little blog post &lt;a href=&#34;https://herman.bearblog.dev/on-writing-regularly/&#34;&gt;on writing regularly&lt;/a&gt;, and I was touched by his words:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Video: How To Read The News From The Command Line</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/reading-news-from-command-line/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/reading-news-from-command-line/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/08SxwJ7ZVyo?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use RSS feeds to read the news, and I use Newsboat as a RSS reader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To in stall on MacOS: &lt;code&gt;brew install newsboat&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integrate in already existing terminal workflow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Free from distraction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Control how content is rendered&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Carefully curate which content you consume&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build your own &amp;ldquo;Social Media feed&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No advertisements or suggested articles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Newsboat uses RSS feeds which are generated by websites&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;202304271004&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New job!</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/new-job-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/new-job-2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week I accepted a job offer! I&amp;rsquo;ve been hired as a DevOps Engineer by &lt;a href=&#34;https://fullstaq.com&#34;&gt;Fullstaq&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fullstaq specialises in Kubernetes and Cloud Native, so I&amp;rsquo;m really happy I could join their team. I&amp;rsquo;ll be doing projects for a variety of clients, and I think it will be a great place to learn and gain more experience in the Kubernetes and CNCF space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fullstaq has been delightfully welcoming and great to work with so far. The future looks bright!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How This Blog is Created, Written and Hosted</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/articles/how-this-blog-is-created/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/articles/how-this-blog-is-created/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/bzkrmkGDQJA?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I alluded to in my &lt;a href=&#34;https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/articles/obsidian-introduction&#34;&gt;article about Obsidian,&lt;/a&gt; I am very fond of editing my text in neovim. Naturally, if you want to edit in neovim, you need to have your text as local files. I keep all of my personal notes in markdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previously I was using WordPress, but the editing and writing experience became torture which I could not endure any longer. I looked for a different solution that would allow me to edit my files locally instead of in the browser.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Starting a Project</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/starting-a-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 21:00:11 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/starting-a-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m starting a project with a friend. Developing an application. We make a good team, he&amp;rsquo;s great at coding and knows the backend too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He&amp;rsquo;ll do the development, I&amp;rsquo;m in charge of hosting. We&amp;rsquo;re setting everything up in Azure DevOps, so it is a great way to practice my Azure skills and apply the things I&amp;rsquo;ve learned in my recently obtained &lt;a href=&#34;https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/articles/az-104-study-guide/&#34;&gt;AZ-104&lt;/a&gt; Azure Administrator certification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though it is a small scale hobby project, I still plan to approach it as if it was an enterprise production application. I&amp;rsquo;ll set up a full CI/CD pipeline with testing in a secure manner. Credentials stored in an Azure key vault and images pushed to a private registry.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Going to Publish Smaller, and More Often</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/move-to-zet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 20:52:50 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/move-to-zet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve transitioned my note taking system towards a Zettelkasten system. I still use directories for folders and make copious links, but more often than not I put them in the larger generic 00-zettelkasten directory in my &lt;a href=&#34;https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/articles/obsidian-introduction/&#34;&gt;Obsidian&lt;/a&gt; vault.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concept of &amp;ldquo;atomic notes&amp;rdquo; is also very important in Zettelkasten methods. Notes should be small and concise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up until this point I&amp;rsquo;ve been publishing full articles on my blog. I came across &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rwxrob&#34;&gt;Rob Muhlestein&lt;/a&gt; yesterday and I was very inspired by his setup and public zettelkasten. I think I&amp;rsquo;ll move to a similar approach. Still planning to write and publish full articles as well, but also including atomic notes and personal status updates.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Book Notes: Ikigai: The Japanese Secret to a Long and Happy Life</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/articles/ikigai-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/articles/ikigai-book/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I came across this little book while doing some research for my &lt;a href=&#34;https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/articles/jiro-sushi&#34;&gt;Jiro Dreams of Sushi article.&lt;/a&gt; While scanning the book&amp;rsquo;s description, I was intrigued by this sentence: &amp;ldquo;the happiness of always being busy.&amp;rdquo; Although I work hard every day, I also enjoy ticking off the last item on my to-do list and enjoying some rest. Is there more happiness in being in constant activity?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ikigai&#34;&gt;Ikigai&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;He who has a why to live for can bear with almost any how.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m In Love with my Work: Lessons from a Japanese Sushi Master</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/articles/jiro-sushi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/articles/jiro-sushi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week I watched &amp;ldquo;Jiro Dreams of Sushi&amp;rdquo; again. It must be the eighth time I revisited this piece of art. I have very little interest in sushi, but there is much more to this documentary. It was first recommended to me by my good friend Anders more than five years ago, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t grasp its underlying life lessons the first time around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though I couldn&amp;rsquo;t fully understand the message, I was intrigued by it and kept returning to the documentary. Over the years, I managed to grasp more of its deeper meaning. The documentary is about Jiro: one of the best sushi chefs in the world. His tiny restaurant, located in a subway station, even received a 3 Michelin star rating. So how does a man operating from a subway restaurant become the best in the world? And what can a DevOps Engineer learn from a sushi chef?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building my Own OS: Linux as a Creative Activity</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/articles/linux-creativity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 12:22:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/articles/linux-creativity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NOTE: In this article, I use a rather broad definition of “Operating System.” I do not intend to appear as if I wrote and compiled my own Linux kernel, nor do I understand the inner workings of the kernel written in C. Instead, with “building my OS from scratch,” I intend to convey that I used a minimal Linux distribution as a starting point and started building from there.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started using GNU/Linux as a daily driver about six months ago, and I have not regretted the decision ever since. There has not been a single use case where I needed to use Windows for anything at all.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I Chose a Bear as a Logo</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/why-i-chose-a-bear-for-my-logo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 11:53:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/why-i-chose-a-bear-for-my-logo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I always struggled with finding an online nickname for myself. I was never given one, and over the years I used a few here and there, ranging from Nordic gods to my favourite fantasy character: Gandalf the Grey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I intended to create a tech blog to document my journey ever since I started my career change. But for months I was stopped by trying to decide on a name. (That’s me in a nutshell), because it needed to be perfect. Eventually I decided to just use my full name.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
