<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal on Mischa van den Burg</title>
    <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal on Mischa van den Burg</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My Blog Is Turning Into And Everything / Nothing Website And It Feels Good</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/everything-nothing-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/everything-nothing-blog/</guid>
      <description>Read an interesting post this morning about E/N websites. Apparently a phenomenon from the early days of the web, E/N websites meant everything to the publisher, but maybe nothing to the rest of the world. The term may have been the predecessor of the term &amp;ldquo;weblog&amp;rdquo; which was shortened to blog.
E/N description: The website&amp;rsquo;s author covers a myriad of topics. It&amp;rsquo;s not narrowly focused. The author writes about everything or at least everything that&amp;rsquo;s important to the author.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Read an interesting post this morning about <a href="http://sawv.org/en.html">E/N websites.</a> Apparently a phenomenon from the early days of the web, E/N websites meant everything to the publisher, but maybe nothing to the rest of the world. The term may have been the predecessor of the term &ldquo;weblog&rdquo; which was shortened to blog.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>E/N description: The website&rsquo;s author covers a myriad of topics. It&rsquo;s not narrowly focused. The author writes about everything or at least everything that&rsquo;s important to the author. The site might contain something useful for anyone who visits. The content means everything to the publisher, but it could mean nothing to the rest of the world.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In <a href="/zet/articles/write-about-health-personal/">this post from March</a> I declared that I would write more about my personal life and expanding the range of topics that I would publish on my blog / zettelkasten. And it has a great decision so far.</p>
<p>I thoroughly enjoy the sense of freedom it has given me. Rather than constraining myself to one subject area, I feel free to write about anything that currently interests me. Writing about these topics stimulates further research and more intentional content consumption.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m sharing more and more personal content, and this is the type of content one might expect to be seen on a social media platform. I don&rsquo;t use social media much, and decided to carve out my own space on the internet and write there instead. I will always be the owner of this content, and I can write about whatever I want and change the appearance and presentation.</p>
<p>I can&rsquo;t explain why, but there is something very satisfying about scrolling through my <a href="/archives/">archives</a> and seeing the things that caught my interest during those particular months, knowing that it is publically available and that others might be piqued by the keywords as well.</p>
<p>Discovering <a href="https://roytang.net/">Roy Tang&rsquo;s website</a> was also very inspirational. I picked up the idea of sharing my week notes and logging the content consumption from his blog. Reading Hacker News regularly has exposed me to several personal blogs which I&rsquo;ve added to my RSS feeds, and I enjoy reading about their interests and getting inspiration from what they decide to publish on their blogs.</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202305090805</p>
<p><a href="https://roytang.net/">https://roytang.net/</a></p>
<p><a href="http://sawv.org/en.html">http://sawv.org/en.html</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saw Sabaton Live Yesterday!</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/sabaton-concert-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/sabaton-concert-2023/</guid>
      <description>Had a great time at the Ziggo Dome in Amsterdam yesterday. Went to see Sabaton live. This was my second time seeing them live, and it was a great show.
I love Sabaton because all of their material revolves around history and warfare. They are one of my favourite bands. I was super happy they played some of my favourite songs: &amp;ldquo;Carolus Rex&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Stormtroopers&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;To Hell And Back&amp;rdquo;.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been a lover of metal music ever since childhood, but I had a break from metal music for about 5 years where I hardly listened to any music at all.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Had a great time at the Ziggo Dome in Amsterdam yesterday. Went to see Sabaton live. This was my second time seeing them live, and it was a great show.</p>
<p>I love Sabaton because all of their material revolves around history and warfare. They are one of my favourite bands. I was super happy they played some of my favourite songs: &ldquo;Carolus Rex&rdquo;, &ldquo;Stormtroopers&rdquo; and &ldquo;To Hell And Back&rdquo;.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve been a lover of metal music ever since childhood, but I had a break from metal music for about 5 years where I hardly listened to any music at all. But over the past 1,5 years I&rsquo;ve been really enjoying metal music again.</p>
<p>I believe the last live show I saw was Cannibal Corpse in 2014 in Oslo. Nearly 10 years without a metal concert?!</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202305041305</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Power of Writing</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/power-of-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/power-of-writing/</guid>
      <description>Ah, writing. It&amp;rsquo;s one of the skills that I&amp;rsquo;ve consistently been praised for throughout my life. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty good at it, and I think that&amp;rsquo;s because I enjoy it. It led me to getting an academic degree in English Literature and Culture, simply because I was following the things I was naturally good at.
However, just like any other skill, you can only become better at it through consistent practice. This morning I read a wonderful little blog post on writing regularly, and I was touched by his words:</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ah, writing. It&rsquo;s one of the skills that I&rsquo;ve consistently been praised for throughout my life. I&rsquo;m pretty good at it, and I think that&rsquo;s because I enjoy it. It led me to getting an academic degree in English Literature and Culture, simply because I was following the things I was naturally good at.</p>
<p>However, just like any other skill, you can only become better at it through consistent practice. This morning I read a wonderful little blog post <a href="https://herman.bearblog.dev/on-writing-regularly/">on writing regularly</a>, and I was touched by his words:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Similarly, some people believe that the art of writing is a skill that can be summoned on a whim, like a genie emerging from a lamp with a flourish of creative brilliance. In my experience, however, writing is more akin to the labour of a blacksmith, hamming words into shape through the heat and sweat of regular practise.</p>
</blockquote>
<h1 id="daily-practice">Daily Practice</h1>
<p>One way to gain more experience is to start keeping a daily journal. I&rsquo;ve always kept some notebook or other, jotting down thoughts and ideas as they came along sporadically. But it was only in July 2020 that I started <a href="https://www.artofmanliness.com/character/behavior/30-days-to-a-better-man-day-8-start-a-journal/">to keep a daily journal</a> and writing regularly. I started out writing by hand. I was in at an interesting place in life: I was spending two years in a Buddhist monastery, and after settling down for a couple of months, the intensive meditation practice was releasing all sorts of things in the mind and body, and I started to write them all down. I&rsquo;m still convinced that starting this habit has been one of the most important and beneficial decisions of my life.</p>
<p>It is so simple, but extremely effective. And you don&rsquo;t have to be doing anything special, or be in a special place. Just keeping a daily journal where you note down the things you did that day in a small pocket book is enough to get the habit going. Soon you will find that you will get the urge to write more. After several years of daily journaling, sometimes all I write is &ldquo;It&rsquo;s been a pretty good day&rdquo;. And that&rsquo;s it for that day. Sometimes I write several pages worth of thoughts, ideas and these longer writings often have powerful effects.</p>
<h1 id="the-power-of-writing">The Power Of Writing</h1>
<p>Sometimes I&rsquo;ll be struggling with something, and I&rsquo;ll be at a loss of what to do. The thoughts just keep whirling about aimlessly and no solution to the particular problem at hand seems to emerge from the chaos. Whenever I am in such a situation, I sit down, close my eyes, observe what is going on, and I start to write. I write it all down. The thoughts, the associations that these thoughts generate, and the effects they are having. I write down exactly how I feel. Attaching words to the feelings that I&rsquo;m experiencing mentally and physically. &ldquo;I feel a contraction in my lower abdomen&rdquo;. &ldquo;I&rsquo;m angry, and it manifests as a hot feeling on my forehead&rdquo;. And that&rsquo;s when the magic happens: something that I&rsquo;ve come to identify as &ldquo;The Power Of Writing&rdquo;.</p>
<p>Somehow the act of writing everything down will create structure in the chaos, and the solution to my problem wil emerge, often from very unexpected angles. Is it the fact that it is structured on paper? Or the fact that the visual representation of the contents of my mind enables me to apply structure to them? Is it the fact that I am moving my hands, adding bodily movement to my cognitive efforts?</p>
<p>I don&rsquo;t have the exact answer, but all I know is that it works for me. Almost every time. And often when I don&rsquo;t expect it at all. I&rsquo;ll just be sitting and writing in my journal, writing down a particular challenge that I&rsquo;m facing that day. And somehow some solution appears out of the blue. Whenever this happens, I always smile and write down: &ldquo;The Power of Writing&rdquo;.</p>
<h1 id="mindfulness">Mindfulness</h1>
<p>Even though I might not know the exact answer, I&rsquo;m certain that it is very closely related to mindfulness. Becoming more mindful through meditation and present moment awareness is the key to happiness in my opnion. I developed a mindfulness practice out of writing by creating this ritual where I sit down and identify what is going on and writing it down. In essence, I&rsquo;m forcing myself to be mindful, and to attach words to my mental and bodily experience. I&rsquo;m getting out of my own way and letting my mind solve the challenge all by itself.</p>
<p>You know what? It&rsquo;s happening right now! The Power of Writing. I hadn&rsquo;t been able to clearly capture in words what the mechanism behind the Power of Writing was, but as I was writing this article, it became obvious to me that it must be mindfulness underlying it all. So I&rsquo;m just going to leave it as it is. This is a perfect example of what you will find in my private zettelkasten. I wrote all of this in one sitting, with minimal editing. Just stream of conciousness, writing it down. And I finished with a wonderful realization.</p>
<p>I feel grateful, satsified and happy. There is also a pleasant tingling at the top of my neck, and an energy rising up through my feet. I hope that this might help someone else one day, and inspire someone to pick up the habit of writing.</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202305012005</p>
<p><a href="https://herman.bearblog.dev/on-writing-regularly/">https://herman.bearblog.dev/on-writing-regularly/</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video: How To Read The News From The Command Line</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/reading-news-from-command-line/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/reading-news-from-command-line/</guid>
      <description>I use RSS feeds to read the news, and I use Newsboat as a RSS reader.
To in stall on MacOS: brew install newsboat
Integrate in already existing terminal workflow Free from distraction Control how content is rendered Carefully curate which content you consume Build your own &amp;ldquo;Social Media feed&amp;rdquo; No advertisements or suggested articles Newsboat uses RSS feeds which are generated by websites Links: 202304271004
https://newsboat.org/</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/08SxwJ7ZVyo" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<p>I use RSS feeds to read the news, and I use Newsboat as a RSS reader.</p>
<p>To in stall on MacOS: <code>brew install newsboat</code></p>
<ul>
<li>Integrate in already existing terminal workflow</li>
<li>Free from distraction</li>
<li>Control how content is rendered</li>
<li>Carefully curate which content you consume</li>
<li>Build your own &ldquo;Social Media feed&rdquo;</li>
<li>No advertisements or suggested articles</li>
<li>Newsboat uses RSS feeds which are generated by websites</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202304271004</p>
<p><a href="https://newsboat.org/">https://newsboat.org/</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Importance Of Rest And Meditation When Making Changes To Routine</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/importance-rest-changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/importance-rest-changes/</guid>
      <description>Over the past two months I&amp;rsquo;ve increased the amount of exercise quite a lot. Over the past year or so I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing Brazilian Jiu Jitsu 1-2x a week and going for a 30-90 minute walk every day.
After I started running in February I have quit BJJ and changed to running 5-6 times a week, 30-60 minutes of Ashtangha Yoga almost every day and two calisthenics workouts a week. For my calisthenics I use rings and I do squats in the gym .</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Over the past two months I&rsquo;ve increased the amount of exercise quite a lot. Over the past year or so I&rsquo;ve been doing Brazilian Jiu Jitsu 1-2x a week and going for a 30-90 minute walk every day.</p>
<p>After I started running in February I have quit BJJ and changed to running 5-6 times a week, 30-60 minutes of Ashtangha Yoga almost every day and two calisthenics workouts a week. For my calisthenics I use rings and I do squats in the gym .</p>
<p>In addition, I reduced my calories to 1700 calories a day spread over two meals, doing 20 hours of fasting a day. I have also eliminated all sugar from my diet.</p>
<p>The reason I needed to do this is because my weight loss has plateaued for several months and I have at least 3kg more fat to lose until I reach my goal of 10% body fat.</p>
<p>Most people know me as someone who is very productive and frugal with his time, and that&rsquo;s true. I&rsquo;m always studying, writing, creating or learning in my free time. There is little to no time for girls and video games, I&rsquo;m on my purpose.</p>
<p>Yet I am also aware of the need of rest and relaxation. I haven&rsquo;t written much about it on my blog, and this will probably change in the time to come, but I am an established meditator and have a very solid mindfulness practice. I&rsquo;ll notice very quickly when I get out of balance and fortunately my practice has provided me with the wisdom to know what to do to bring things back into balance again.</p>
<p>Having introduced an increased amount of exercise and mental stress due to caloric restriction, I saw I needed to take a few steps back and allow my body and mind to adjust to these changes. I was already on caloric restriction and fasting 18 hours a day, but still I noticed I needed time to adjust.</p>
<p>To adjust I allowed myself to take a break from evening tech study and homelabbing and read some fiction instead, and I increased my meditation practice. Stilling the mind with breath meditation is helping me to deal with very intense food cravings. Quitting sugar is definitely no walk in the park.</p>
<p>I have made these kinds of changes many times before, and I know that after a while my body and mind are used to it and I can go back to my old routine again. Having a daily meditation practice gives me the tools to check in with myself. I am very grateful to myself that I put in the hard work over the past 6 years to get an established daily practice. I am also extremely grateful to my teacher and the Buddhist community who supported me while I spent time in a monastery in Norway.</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202304242004</p>
<p>[[buddhist-practice]]</p>
<p>[[meditation]]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing about Health and Personal Life</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/articles/write-about-health-personal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/articles/write-about-health-personal/</guid>
      <description>For weeks I&amp;rsquo;ve been debating with myself whether I should open up more on my blog. I spend my energy on two main pillars of my life: work and health, and up until now I&amp;rsquo;ve only been writing about work on my blog.
work I spend most of my waking hours sitting at my keyboard working on the command line: working, studying, coding, note taking. My life is focused around my career and I spend at at least 20 hours a week studying or learning new skills related to my career.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For weeks I&rsquo;ve been debating with myself whether I should open up more on my blog. I spend my energy on two main pillars of my life: work and health, and up until now I&rsquo;ve only been writing about work on my blog.</p>
<h1 id="work">work</h1>
<p>I spend most of my waking hours sitting at my keyboard working on the command line: working, studying, coding, note taking. My life is focused around my career and I spend at at least 20 hours a week studying or learning new skills related to my career. When I made my career change I started to write this blog to document the process and share my learning with anyone who might find it useful</p>
<h1 id="health">health</h1>
<p>The other main pillar of my life is health. In 2017 my father suffered two very serious hard attacks in close succession, and nearly losing him really woke me up and made me focus on my health.</p>
<p>I started eating a plant based diet and slowly reducing all the habits that were detrimental to my health, and increasing the activities that would promote my health. I quit drinking alcohol and I&rsquo;ve been sober for nearly 5 years now.</p>
<h2 id="mental-health">mental health</h2>
<p>I&rsquo;m also very interested in mental health. I&rsquo;ve done extensive studies of meditation and did several retreats. I&rsquo;ve had a daily meditation practice going for 6 years now. I have a teacher and enjoy conversing about this topic with friends that have similar interests. I also practice yoga several times a week.</p>
<h2 id="diet">diet</h2>
<p>I spend a lot of time reading and researching what the optimal diet is for me. I&rsquo;ve done a lot of experimentation. Not only what I eat, but also when I eat has been a subject of scrutiny for years now. I&rsquo;ve been on some form of intermittent fasting protocol since 2015, and I&rsquo;m currently eating only one meal a day.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MkuWE4QNuo0">Caloric restriction</a> has been shown to extend lifespan in many different organisms and I find it very intriguing. I&rsquo;ve been on a weight loss journey since late 2021 and I find that restricting my calories gives me all sorts of benefits.</p>
<h2 id="sleep">sleep</h2>
<p>My life changed when I read Matt Walker&rsquo;s book &ldquo;Why We Sleep&rdquo; and I&rsquo;ve focused on sleep hygiene ever since. My average sleep over the last year is 7 hours a night (logged by my iWatch).</p>
<h2 id="exercise">exercise</h2>
<p>I recently ran <a href="/zet/ran-5km">my first 5k</a> and I&rsquo;m about to embark on a whole new exercise journey where I&rsquo;ll be exploring my endurance limits.</p>
<h1 id="blog">blog</h1>
<p>All of the topics above are interests of mine and I spent a lot of time researching them. I listen to podcasts, read books, discuss them with friends. And most importantly: I keep notes about them.</p>
<p>So if I&rsquo;m happy to publish all of my work related notes with the world, why should I not share my other interests as well? I spend so much time gathering all this information and writing notes about them, and I feel that it might be useful to others who don&rsquo;t wish to plough through all of the material and would like to read summaries of the information.</p>
<h2 id="there-are-a-few-reasons-why-ive-been-hesitant-to-do-so">There are a few reasons why I&rsquo;ve been hesitant to do so.</h2>
<h3 id="seo">seo</h3>
<p>I used to have websites that marketed products, and from those years of optimizing for sales I&rsquo;ve gained some ingrained habits. These include keeping websites centered around one topic and repeating keywords throughout articles.</p>
<p>This blog was never intended for any sales or marketing, so I haven&rsquo;t been writing with any SEO in mind which has been liberating, frankly. But I find that these ingrained habits have stopped me from broadening my scope for the blog.</p>
<h3 id="centralization">centralization</h3>
<p>But keeping the website centered focused on one area has been a sticking point. I&rsquo;ve always had the reader in mind, but also for selfish reasons. Colleagues and managers have pointed out that my blog is an excellent supplement to my CV. When I switched jobs recently, one hiring manager even offered me a job with a good salary solely based on my CV, my blog and one phone conversation.</p>
<p>Readers of my blog might not necessarily be interested reading about my opinions and notes on health and exercise.</p>
<h2 id="its-my-blog">It&rsquo;s my blog!</h2>
<p>In the end I decided to start writing more about my personal life and health interests. The whole point of starting my own website was to have the <strong>freedom of writing about what I want without limitations</strong>. I could have just written all my stuff on LinkedIn on other social media, but then you don&rsquo;t own any of the content. What happens if you get banned for some reason? Or hacked? All your work is gone, which is why I chose my own website written in markdown files stored locally on my disk and hosted on GitHub.</p>
<p>From the beginning I made sure to use a system where readers can filter on tags if they are looking for specific content. And honestly, who reads my stuff anyway? I know of one person who regularly reads my stuff (Hi, F!), but my blog is mostly a relaxing creative activity. I like scrolling through it and seeing the thoughts I captured, and to see it grow over time. And it helps me tremendously with learning information, because writing about topics is a great way to test whether I really understand the matter.</p>
<p>Including my notes on other topics such as health and exercise will make my blog less focused and centralized around DevOps and tech, but it will reveal more about me as a person, and it will be fun to look back in the future and see my progress in these other areas as well. And I think that summaries of the research I do on these topics can actually be of use to others.</p>
<p>So I&rsquo;ve decided to remove all limitations on topics for my blog and to just write about everything that I feel like publishing and sharing with the world.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New job!</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/new-job-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/new-job-2023/</guid>
      <description>Last week I accepted a job offer! I&amp;rsquo;ve been hired as a DevOps Engineer by Fullstaq.
Fullstaq specialises in Kubernetes and Cloud Native, so I&amp;rsquo;m really happy I could join their team. I&amp;rsquo;ll be doing projects for a variety of clients, and I think it will be a great place to learn and gain more experience in the Kubernetes and CNCF space.
Fullstaq has been delightfully welcoming and great to work with so far.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last week I accepted a job offer! I&rsquo;ve been hired as a DevOps Engineer by <a href="https://fullstaq.com">Fullstaq</a>.</p>
<p>Fullstaq specialises in Kubernetes and Cloud Native, so I&rsquo;m really happy I could join their team. I&rsquo;ll be doing projects for a variety of clients, and I think it will be a great place to learn and gain more experience in the Kubernetes and CNCF space.</p>
<p>Fullstaq has been delightfully welcoming and great to work with so far. The future looks bright!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How This Blog is Created, Written and Hosted</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/articles/how-this-blog-is-created/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/articles/how-this-blog-is-created/</guid>
      <description>As I alluded to in my article about Obsidian, I am very fond of editing my text in neovim. Naturally, if you want to edit in neovim, you need to have your text as local files. I keep all of my personal notes in markdown.
Previously I was using WordPress, but the editing and writing experience became torture which I could not endure any longer. I looked for a different solution that would allow me to edit my files locally instead of in the browser.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As I alluded to in my <a href="/zet/articles/obsidian-introduction">article about Obsidian,</a> I am very fond of editing my text in neovim. Naturally, if you want to edit in neovim, you need to have your text as local files. I keep all of my personal notes in markdown.</p>
<p>Previously I was using WordPress, but the editing and writing experience became torture which I could not endure any longer. I looked for a different solution that would allow me to edit my files locally instead of in the browser.</p>
<p>I discovered <a href="https://gohugo.io/">Hugo</a> and I fell in love with it immediately.</p>
<p>Hugo is a static site generator based on markdown files. My entire blog is written in markdown files which are stored <a href="https://github.com/mischavandenburg/blog">in a GitHub repo.</a>. I write my blog posts in vim and when I&rsquo;m done I use Hugo to generate the updated website.</p>
<p>The result is what you see in the &ldquo;public&rdquo; directory in the GitHub repo. This public directory is pushed to a different repo which is hooked up to my hosting provider. My hosting provider uses Plesk, and with Plesk I have the option to connect the GitHub repo to the web server with a webhook. When I push to my hosting repo, the contents are gathered by the webserver and served as public web content.</p>
<p>My complete writing and publishing workflow looks like this:</p>
<ol>
<li>Create a new markdown file</li>
<li>Write the note or article</li>
<li>Save the file and run the &ldquo;hugo&rdquo; command to regenerate the website</li>
<li>Run the &ldquo;publish&rdquo; script. This is a custom script I wrote that takes the contents of the &ldquo;public&rdquo; directory to my hosting repo</li>
<li>Push the newly generated website to the hosting repo</li>
<li>And we&rsquo;re live! ðŸš€ ðŸŽ‰</li>
</ol>
<p>It is such a smooth and convenient process. I can literally have a new note published to the interet within a few minutes, and it is all done from the command line using my favorite tools.</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/mischavandenburg/blog">Blog GitHub repo</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting a Project</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/starting-a-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 21:00:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/starting-a-project/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m starting a project with a friend. Developing an application. We make a good team, he&amp;rsquo;s great at coding and knows the backend too.
He&amp;rsquo;ll do the development, I&amp;rsquo;m in charge of hosting. We&amp;rsquo;re setting everything up in Azure DevOps, so it is a great way to practice my Azure skills and apply the things I&amp;rsquo;ve learned in my recently obtained AZ-104 Azure Administrator certification.
Even though it is a small scale hobby project, I still plan to approach it as if it was an enterprise production application.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m starting a project with a friend. Developing an application. We make a good team, he&rsquo;s great at coding and knows the backend too.</p>
<p>He&rsquo;ll do the development, I&rsquo;m in charge of hosting. We&rsquo;re setting everything up in Azure DevOps, so it is a great way to practice my Azure skills and apply the things I&rsquo;ve learned in my recently obtained <a href="/zet/articles/az-104-study-guide/">AZ-104</a> Azure Administrator certification.</p>
<p>Even though it is a small scale hobby project, I still plan to approach it as if it was an enterprise production application. I&rsquo;ll set up a full CI/CD pipeline with testing in a secure manner. Credentials stored in an Azure key vault and images pushed to a private registry.</p>
<p>This is going to be fun!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going to Publish Smaller, and More Often</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/move-to-zet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 20:52:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/move-to-zet/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve transitioned my note taking system towards a Zettelkasten system. I still use directories for folders and make copious links, but more often than not I put them in the larger generic 00-zettelkasten directory in my Obsidian vault.
The concept of &amp;ldquo;atomic notes&amp;rdquo; is also very important in Zettelkasten methods. Notes should be small and concise.
Up until this point I&amp;rsquo;ve been publishing full articles on my blog. I came across Rob Muhlestein yesterday and I was very inspired by his setup and public zettelkasten.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve transitioned my note taking system towards a Zettelkasten system. I still use directories for folders and make copious links, but more often than not I put them in the larger generic 00-zettelkasten directory in my <a href="/zet/articles/obsidian-introduction/">Obsidian</a> vault.</p>
<p>The concept of &ldquo;atomic notes&rdquo; is also very important in Zettelkasten methods. Notes should be small and concise.</p>
<p>Up until this point I&rsquo;ve been publishing full articles on my blog. I came across <a href="https://github.com/rwxrob">Rob Muhlestein</a> yesterday and I was very inspired by his setup and public zettelkasten. I think I&rsquo;ll move to a similar approach. Still planning to write and publish full articles as well, but also including atomic notes and personal status updates.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Notes: Ikigai: The Japanese Secret to a Long and Happy Life</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/articles/ikigai-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/articles/ikigai-book/</guid>
      <description>I came across this little book while doing some research for my Jiro Dreams of Sushi article. While scanning the book&amp;rsquo;s description, I was intrigued by this sentence: &amp;ldquo;the happiness of always being busy.&amp;rdquo; Although I work hard every day, I also enjoy ticking off the last item on my to-do list and enjoying some rest. Is there more happiness in being in constant activity?
Ikigai &amp;ldquo;He who has a why to live for can bear with almost any how.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I came across this little book while doing some research for my <a href="/zet/articles/jiro-sushi">Jiro Dreams of Sushi article.</a> While scanning the book&rsquo;s description, I was intrigued by this sentence: &ldquo;the happiness of always being busy.&rdquo; Although I work hard every day, I also enjoy ticking off the last item on my to-do list and enjoying some rest. Is there more happiness in being in constant activity?</p>
<h2 id="ikigai">Ikigai</h2>
<blockquote>
<hr>
<p>&ldquo;He who has a why to live for can bear with almost any how.&rdquo;</p>
<ul>
<li>Friedrich Nietzsche</li>
</ul>
<hr>
</blockquote>
<p>According to Japanese culture, everybody has a purpose in life: the ikigai. &ldquo;Ikigai is the reason we get up in the morning.&rdquo; The book explores this concept through interesting stories and brings related notions from various areas to explain ikigai to the Western mind.</p>
<p>There are many different ikigai, and people can have several ikigai simultaneously. For example, some people have their vegetable garden as their ikigai, while others have drawing or calligraphy. <a href="/zet/articles/jiro-sushi">Jiro</a> has making sushi as his ikigai. Even though many people have their work as their ikigai, it does not necessarily have to be the case. Ikigai can also be of a social nature, such as a family or local community.</p>
<p>
  <img loading="lazy" src="https://external-content.duckduckgo.com/iu/?u=https%3A%2F%2F3nw94z2pgadc432nw33p8qg5-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com%2Fwp-content%2Fuploads%2F2018%2F01%2Fwhat-is-ikigai-darling.png&amp;f=1&amp;nofb=1&amp;ipt=f5fa9a17a2865d283af2bfdf8d978f1dcb0e9ff4e7fb646fb2c26c4963f95e77&amp;ipo=images" alt=""  /></p>
<h2 id="retirement">Retirement</h2>
<p>When I watched Jiro Dreams of Sushi for the first time, I was surprised that Jiro still worked at his restaurant every day at age 85. This book explores that further.</p>
<p>Apparently, many people never really retire in Japan. The concept of retirement, as we know it in the West, does not exist in the Japanese language: there is &ldquo;no word in Japanese that means retire in the sense of &ldquo;leaving the workforce for good&rdquo; as in English.&rdquo; People continue doing what they like doing as long as their health allows. They keep following their ikigai.</p>
<p>This concept was very refreshing to me and had a profound influence on how I imagine my own future. After becoming more intentional about my career, I became interested in <a href="https://www.investopedia.com/terms/f/financial-independence-retire-early-fire.asp">FIRE</a> and the possibility of retiring early. However, as I contemplated this strategy, I discovered that I didn&rsquo;t want to stop working because I really enjoy my work.</p>
<p>Why would I want to retire if I&rsquo;m doing what I love? That was the whole point of switching my career to IT, and this is where Western culture can learn a lot from Japanese culture. In Japanese culture, there is more emphasis on aligning your career with your interests and continuing that passion well into old age.</p>
<blockquote>
<hr>
<p>When to quit? The job you have worked so hard for? I never once hated my job. I fell in love with my work and gave my life to it. Even though I&rsquo;m 85 years old, I don&rsquo;t feel like retiring.</p>
<ul>
<li>Jiro</li>
</ul>
<hr>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="longevity">Longevity</h2>
<p>A large part of the book is about the residents of Okinawa: the island with the highest number of people 100 years old or older. The authors tell the story of their visit to the island to reveal the secret of the Okinawan&rsquo;s long lives. It is not uncommon to see people working in the fields who are well into their eighties. The Okinawans freely share their secrets with us, and the authors do a great job translating the Japanese principles into actionable advice.</p>
<p>Much of the advice is centered around dietary habits. Not only what to eat, but also how to eat it: &ldquo;Okinawans stop eating when they feel their stomachs reach 80 percent of their capacity, rather than overeating&rdquo;, a practice which is named &ldquo;hara haci bu.&rdquo; They consume a daily average of 1800 to 1900 calories, a significant difference from the 2200 to 3300 calories consumed by an average person in the US every day.</p>
<p>Another theme that keeps returning is the crucial function of social groups for finding meaning in life, especially in old age: &ldquo;It is customary in Okinawa to form close bonds within local communities. A moai is an informal group of people with common interests who look out for one another. For many, serving the community becomes part of their ikigai.&rdquo;</p>
<p>This book may be a good resource if you are interested in longevity. Even though I only expected to read about the ikigai concept, it contains a surprisingly large amount of valuable advice and practical tips to live a longer and happier life.</p>
<h2 id="chock-full">Chock-full</h2>
<p>&ldquo;Ikigai: The Japanese Secret to a Long and Happy Life&rdquo; is a small book that covers an astonishing amount of subjects. It covers topics such as meditation, flow states, and exercise methods such as Tai Chi and Qi Gong. The disadvantage is that it does not deeply cover any of these topics. But I think this book can be a very useful springboard for further research and a great introduction to many different subjects that can improve your life.</p>
<p>It is a short read, but it contains a lot of wisdom, and I learned much from this book. It has changed the way I think of retirement and the way I approach my work. I am also very interested in health and longevity. Through the conversations with the centenarians of Okinawa, I received a lot of helpful tips, which I&rsquo;m already applying to my daily life.</p>
<p>Have I discovered the art of being busy? I believe I took this definition too literally when I started reading this book. I found that Okinawans lead active lives full of meaning but also take plenty of rest. Always being busy does not mean that you have to work yourself to death. However, it does mean that the secret to reaching a healthy old age is to keep doing what you love. There is no need to become sedentary and only sit in front of the TV when you turn 67. I think Western culture has a lot to learn in this area.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m In Love with my Work: Lessons from a Japanese Sushi Master</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/articles/jiro-sushi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/articles/jiro-sushi/</guid>
      <description>Last week I watched &amp;ldquo;Jiro Dreams of Sushi&amp;rdquo; again. It must be the eighth time I revisited this piece of art. I have very little interest in sushi, but there is much more to this documentary. It was first recommended to me by my good friend Anders more than five years ago, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t grasp its underlying life lessons the first time around.
Even though I couldn&amp;rsquo;t fully understand the message, I was intrigued by it and kept returning to the documentary.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last week I watched &ldquo;Jiro Dreams of Sushi&rdquo; again. It must be the eighth time I revisited this piece of art. I have very little interest in sushi, but there is much more to this documentary. It was first recommended to me by my good friend Anders more than five years ago, but I couldn&rsquo;t grasp its underlying life lessons the first time around.</p>
<p>Even though I couldn&rsquo;t fully understand the message, I was intrigued by it and kept returning to the documentary. Over the years, I managed to grasp more of its deeper meaning. The documentary is about Jiro: one of the best sushi chefs in the world. His tiny restaurant, located in a subway station, even received a 3 Michelin star rating. So how does a man operating from a subway restaurant become the best in the world? And what can a DevOps Engineer learn from a sushi chef?</p>
<p>
  <img loading="lazy" src="https://culinaireambiance.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/1_J8Bw5e9O9AfmLNdDKRRv6A-1.jpeg" alt="Jiro, the Master"  /></p>
<p>Jiro is referred to as a shokunin, a Japanese cultural phenomenon that doesn&rsquo;t have a direct translation into English. A shokunin is an artisan or a craftsman who has devoted his entire life to becoming a master of his craft. For example, there are shokunin carpenters, weavers, and blacksmiths. The shokunin achieve mastery by doing the same action over and over again and trying to improve with every repetition.</p>
<blockquote>
<hr>
<p>&ldquo;Once you decide on your occupation, you must immerse yourself in your work. You have to fall in love with your work. Never complain about your job. You must dedicate your life to mastering your skill. That&rsquo;s the secret of success and is the key to being regarded honorably.&rdquo;</p>
<ul>
<li>Jiro</li>
</ul>
<hr>
</blockquote>
<p>We get to know Jiro as a man who is devoted to his occupation. He follows the same routine every day; he even gets on the train from the same position. He says he dislikes holidays and prefers to be at work. He used to get up at 5:00 and get home after 22:00. Even at age 85, he&rsquo;s still working at the restaurant every day, simply because he doesn&rsquo;t want to do anything else.</p>
<p>But it&rsquo;s not just about putting in long hours and working past the retirement age. It&rsquo;s also about the mindset and the attitude that Jiro has adopted towards his craft:</p>
<blockquote>
<hr>
<p>&ldquo;I&rsquo;ve seen many chefs who are self-critical, but I&rsquo;ve never seen another chef who is so hard on himself. He sets the standard for self-discipline. He&rsquo;s always looking ahead. He&rsquo;s never satisfied with his work. He&rsquo;s always trying to find ways to make the sushi better or to improve his skills. Even now, that&rsquo;s what he thinks about every day.&rdquo;</p>
<ul>
<li>Masuhiro Yamamoto, Food Critic.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="finding-my-craft">Finding my Craft</h2>
<p>It was hard to decide on my occupation. It took me 32 years and a lot of trial and error to find the answer. I have always envied people who knew they wanted to become a nurse since childhood.</p>
<p>What occupation should I choose? I answered this question by answering another question: what do I like to do in my free time? The answer was clear: I tinkered with computers. I had already coded several websites and loved experimenting with game automation. I ran &ldquo;bot farms&rdquo; on Linux servers which I configured myself from the command line.</p>
<p>I decided to make IT and tech my occupation. Fortunately for me, the job market was in my favor, and employers were much more willing to consider candidates without a formal background in IT. If you&rsquo;d like to read more, I wrote about my journey into DevOps in <a href="/my-journey-into-devops-so-far">this article</a>.</p>
<h2 id="the-ways-of-the-shokunin">The Ways of the Shokunin</h2>
<p>After making the career change, I adopted the shokunin mindset and dedicated my life to mastering my craft. In practical terms, I needed to commit to devoting my time to my profession and avoid straying from it. Making this commitment wasn&rsquo;t very difficult because I chose my career based on my free-time activities. It&rsquo;s more about adopting a mindset of striving to make everything relate to each other. For example, I try to select hobby projects that directly relate to what I&rsquo;m working with during the day. This way, my leisure activities will strengthen my professional skills, and my professional expertise will improve my hobby projects, creating a feedback loop that will eventually lead to results.</p>
<p>However, sticking to one thing does not necessarily come naturally to me. I have a tendency to pick up many different hobbies and get very excited about them. First, I will become extremely interested in a particular subject. Then, after approximately three months, I put it aside and become excited about something else. This isn&rsquo;t necessarily a case of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shiny_object_syndrome">Shiny Object Syndrome</a> because I tend to return to these hobbies in a cyclical pattern. As I apply myself to learning the skill with a feverish intensity, I&rsquo;m able to make a lot of progress during these bouts of obsession. But to the outside world, it might seem like I&rsquo;m constantly changing my mind about what I want.</p>
<p>I always considered this a negative character trait, but over the past few years, I&rsquo;ve learned to embrace it and guide this tendency in the right direction. Because I chose IT as my occupation and DevOps as an area of specialization, I gave myself a broad scope of interest with many sub-skills to learn. If you look at the <a href="https://roadmap.sh/devops">DevOps Roadmap</a>, you&rsquo;ll see that a good DevOps Engineer must master many different skills.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s like I&rsquo;ve given myself a large playground with a fence around it, full of exciting things to learn. I can go down a Python rabbit hole for a few months and improve my coding skills. Later, I find myself sucked into <a href="https://mischavandenburg.com/linux-creativity/">builing my own OS</a> and learning more about Linux in the process. The fence around the playground isn&rsquo;t locked, but I do my best to stay inside the fence. When, for example, I start getting the urge to get back into music production again, I consider that it will take up a few hours a day to get back on track. Investing these hours into something that brings me joy, but is also related to my occupation, would be a better option. Reflecting in this way keeps me focused on my goals.</p>
<p>My website is another example of this fusion between professional and free-time activities. I love to write. It&rsquo;s a relaxing activity, even though it is very challenging sometimes. After I learn about a new subject, I try to write about it. This is the best way I know to verify whether I&rsquo;ve really understood the topic. When I sit down to write about something, I force myself to think clearly about it and to make sure everything aligns properly in my mind. When I cannot explain the concepts in a few clear sentences, I know I don&rsquo;t fully understand it yet.</p>
<blockquote>
<hr>
<p>&ldquo;Clear thinking becomes clear writing; one can&rsquo;t exist without the other.&rdquo;</p>
<ul>
<li>William Zinsser, On Writing Well</li>
</ul>
<hr>
</blockquote>
<p>Another way my blog supports my professional development is because I prefer to write my blog posts in neovim in the markdown format. Writing and editing text often involves moving a lot of words and paragraphs around. Because I use vim to do my writing, I&rsquo;m also constantly practicing the keybinds I use for writing and editing code during my day job. I often learn a new motion for my blog writing, which I use the next day at work.</p>
<h2 id="never-finished">Never Finished</h2>
<blockquote>
<hr>
<p>&ldquo;All I want to do is make better sushi. I do the same thing over and over, improving bit by bit. There is always a yearning to achieve more. I&rsquo;ll continue to climb, trying to reach the top, but no one knows where the top is. Even at my age, after decades of work, I don&rsquo;t think I have achieved perfection. But I feel ecstatic all day. I love making sushi. That&rsquo;s the spirit of the shokunin.&rdquo;</p>
<ul>
<li>Jiro</li>
</ul>
<hr>
</blockquote>
<p>Jiro taught me never to be satisfied with my skills. If I desire to become a master of my craft, there will never be a point where I can lean back and think that I&rsquo;ve learned enough. There&rsquo;s always something to improve, which is why I chose an IT career. My thirst for learning cannot be quenched, and there&rsquo;s always something to learn in this field.</p>
<p>
  <img loading="lazy" src="https://external-content.duckduckgo.com/iu/?u=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2FR2L5IrkQTV0%2Fmaxresdefault.jpg&amp;f=1&amp;nofb=1&amp;ipt=447c7c4a93a10b64191d653525bfe6ab6ab5aba0f3e9a1c64bc3617420bbc109&amp;ipo=images" alt="Never Finished"  /></p>
<h2 id="devotion">Devotion</h2>
<p>Although it might seem like a simple food documentary, do not be deceived. Jiro Dreams of Sushi is full of valuable life lessons. It&rsquo;s one of the documentaries which I revisit regularly. It&rsquo;s relaxing to watch, and I get hugely inspired by Jiro&rsquo;s devotion to his craft and powerful teachings every time.</p>
<p>Jiro&rsquo;s guidance has changed my life. He made me realize that if I wished to become a master of my craft, I needed to devote my life to it. I changed my lifestyle, so the things I do in my free time strengthen my professional skills. I also became more mindful of the content I consume and the things I read, trying to keep it related to my occupation. He showed me the true meaning of the phrase &ldquo;my work is my hobby.&rdquo;</p>
<blockquote>
<hr>
<p>&ldquo;Always look beyond and above yourself. Always try to improve on yourself. Always strive to elevate your craft. That&rsquo;s what he taught me.&rdquo;</p>
<ul>
<li>Yoshikazu, Jiro&rsquo;s oldest son.</li>
</ul>
<hr>
</blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building my Own OS: Linux as a Creative Activity</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/articles/linux-creativity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 12:22:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/articles/linux-creativity/</guid>
      <description>NOTE: In this article, I use a rather broad definition of â€œOperating System.â€ I do not intend to appear as if I wrote and compiled my own Linux kernel, nor do I understand the inner workings of the kernel written in C. Instead, with â€œbuilding my OS from scratch,â€ I intend to convey that I used a minimal Linux distribution as a starting point and started building from there.
introduction I started using GNU/Linux as a daily driver about six months ago, and I have not regretted the decision ever since.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>NOTE: In this article, I use a rather broad definition of â€œOperating System.â€ I do not intend to appear as if I wrote and compiled my own Linux kernel, nor do I understand the inner workings of the kernel written in C. Instead, with â€œbuilding my OS from scratch,â€ I intend to convey that I used a minimal Linux distribution as a starting point and started building from there.</em></p>
<h2 id="introduction">introduction</h2>
<p>I started using GNU/Linux as a daily driver about six months ago, and I have not regretted the decision ever since. There has not been a single use case where I needed to use Windows for anything at all.</p>
<p>As I was getting more used to daily driving Linux, I noticed how much I enjoyed the ability to customize my operating system and workflow. Finally, after spending a weekend going down the customization rabbit hole, I had a good-looking terminal and customized neovim to perform as I needed it.</p>
<p>Not much later, I came across Arch Linux and the idea of building your own operating system from the ground up. I was instantly intrigued and knew I wanted to do the same. A few months have passed since I first came across Arch Linux, and now I am writing this blog post in neovim on my custom OS that I created from scratch. The font, the spacing, the colors, everything is exactly how I like it, and I love using it.</p>
<p>When you first install Arch Linux, all you get is a black screen with a blinking cursor. However, the experience of creating a fully functional graphical environment from â€œnothingâ€ has been extremely satisfying, and I learned so much about GNU/Linux in the process. I also realized that this could be seen as a creative activity, like a painter creating his masterpiece from a blank canvas or a sculptor carefully chipping away at a block of marble.</p>
<h2 id="not-just-graphics">not just graphics</h2>
<p>When I say customization, I am not just referring to the visual aspects of the operating system. The things going on â€œunder the hoodâ€ must also be carefully configured when you use a minimal distro such as Arch Linux.</p>
<p>Arch Linux comes with very few packages preinstalled, and every time you wish to add something to your system, you need to install it and enable the service in systemd. For example, after I did the installation and created my user account, I needed to run a command with root privileges. To my great surprise, even the â€œsudoâ€ command was unavailable and needed to be installed.</p>
<p>This is the aspect I learned most from. Whenever I desired a certain functionality from my operating system, I needed to install and enable it. This has given me a much better understanding of the processes and daemons running on my system. It has also given me a greater appreciation of all the elements needed to provide a working environment.</p>
<h2 id="graphic-violence">graphic violence</h2>
<p>When you create an Arch Linux installation USB and boot it up, you are greeted with a command line and nothing else.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/creative1.png" type="" alt=""  /></p>
<p>When you install something more beginner-friendly, such as Ubuntu or Manjaro KDE, your installation will include a graphical desktop environment. But on Arch Linux, you must install and configure this yourself. Furthermore, to be able to render a graphical environment, you will also need to install and configure a display server such as Xorg.</p>
<p>When I started on my journey, I intended to create something that used minimal resources with a minimal look. Having used GNOME on Manjaro for a few months, I was very satisfied, but I wanted to try a tiling window manager to shave down even more resource usage. After some research, I ended up with the Awesome Window Manager. Here are some screenshots of the final result:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/creative2.png" type="" alt=""  /></p>
<p>This is what my desktop looks like when I boot up.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/creative3.png" type="" alt=""  />
Here Iâ€™m editing my window manager configuration file, while I have a browser open and keep an eye on my system resources</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/creative4.png" type="" alt=""  /></p>
<p>my music listening setup, using mpd + ncmpcpp, cava and sptlrx. the lyrics are shown in real time as the music is played.</p>
<h2 id="creativity">creativity</h2>
<p><a href="https://dictionary.cambridge.org/dictionary/english">The Cambridge Dictionary</a> defines creativity as â€œthe ability to produce original and unusual ideas, or <strong>to make something new or imaginative</strong>.â€</p>
<p>When you embark on a journey, such as creating your operating system, you will probably start with a particular intention or a goal that you will work towards. With this goal in mind, you can start searching for the tools and color schemes you need to create the system that you have in mind. The result is a unique combination of tools, colors, fonts, and programs specifically tailored to your needs and wants and chosen by you.</p>
<p>Is this any different from a painter starting with a blank canvas or a musician starting with a fragment of a melody, ending up with a complete symphony? Entering commands into a computer terminal might not strike everybody as a creative activity. Still, I have found that it is a very effective and satisfying way of expressing myself and creating something I love to use daily. As an IT professional, I spend most of my time behind my computer. Doesnâ€™t it make sense to put effort into building something customized to your needs?</p>
<h4 id="resources">resources</h4>
<p>If you want to start building your own OS, I recommend these resources:</p>
<p><a href="https://archlinux.org/">Arch Linux</a></p>
<p><a href="https://wiki.archlinux.org/">Arch Wiki</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/unixporn/">r/unixporn â€“ a subreddit about customization</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Chose a Bear as a Logo</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/why-i-chose-a-bear-for-my-logo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 11:53:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/why-i-chose-a-bear-for-my-logo/</guid>
      <description>I always struggled with finding an online nickname for myself. I was never given one, and over the years I used a few here and there, ranging from Nordic gods to my favourite fantasy character: Gandalf the Grey.
I intended to create a tech blog to document my journey ever since I started my career change. But for months I was stopped by trying to decide on a name. (Thatâ€™s me in a nutshell), because it needed to be perfect.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I always struggled with finding an online nickname for myself. I was never given one, and over the years I used a few here and there, ranging from Nordic gods to my favourite fantasy character: Gandalf the Grey.</p>
<p>I intended to create a tech blog to document my journey ever since I started my career change. But for months I was stopped by trying to decide on a name. (Thatâ€™s me in a nutshell), because it needed to be perfect. Eventually I decided to just use my full name.</p>
<p>Although I have zero connections with Russia, neither genetically nor culturally, my parents decided to give me a name of Russian origin: Mischa.</p>
<p>According to <a href="https://babynames.com/name/mischa">this website</a>, Mischa has the following meaning:</p>
<p>â€œThe name Mischa is primarily a gender-neutral name of Russian origin that means <em>Who Is Like God</em>â€œ</p>
<p>Although I admire my parents for giving me such an ambitious name, I must confess that I turned out to be of a much more earthy and less godly nature.</p>
<p>When I was younger, an old gymnastics teacher once told me that Mischa meant â€œbearâ€ in Russian, and I always liked that connotation much more. I also turned out to be more bear-like than god-like, being 190cm tall and having thick and bristly curly hair.</p>
<p>Indeed, <a href="https://www.quora.com/What-does-Misha-mean-Its-Russian-by-the-way">this post on Quora</a> confirms that my name indeed has the meaning of bear:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><em>&ldquo;In Russia Mishka sometimes also used to denote a bear, particularly a bear cub.&rdquo;</em>
<a href="https://www.quora.com/profile/Misha-Sivan">Misha Sivan</a>, Born in USSR.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>
  <img loading="lazy" src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/a/a9/GrizzlyBearJeanBeaufort.jpg" alt=""  /></p>
<p>Although I am conveniently ignoring the â€œcubâ€ part of his explanation, I thought it was pretty cool that my actual name had connotations with our ursine friends.</p>
<p>Moreover, I lived 9 years in Norway where I roamed the mountains for weeks at a time, just me and my tent and a fishing rod. I developed a very close connection with nature during those years. Not only its beauty, but also its merciless forces and awe-inspiring ingenuity.</p>
<p>Although I never encountered a bear myself, they are most definitely present in the Norwegian nature. One time the newspapers told me that there was a bear sighted 4 kilometers from where I was camping one weekend.</p>
<p>But this is what the bear represents to me: the time I was allowed to spend in the North and the resulting connection with nature. The solitary character of the male, calmly roaming for many miles in search of sustenance. A force to be reckoned with when aggravated, but in general preferring to stay at a distance.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
