<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Podcast on Mischa van den Burg</title>
    <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/podcast/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Podcast on Mischa van den Burg</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/podcast/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Podcast Notes: Interview With Eliud Kipchoge, The Fastest Marathon Runner In The World</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/podcast-kipchoge-marathon-running/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/podcast-kipchoge-marathon-running/</guid>
      <description>What I Learned from Kipchoge, the Fastest Marathon Runner in the World Kipchoge is not only a world-class athlete, but also a source of inspiration and wisdom for anyone who wants to improve their life. I recently listened to an interview with him on YouTube, and I was amazed by his insights on running, success, pain, discipline and happiness. Here are some of the key takeaways and a summary of what he shared.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="what-i-learned-from-kipchoge-the-fastest-marathon-runner-in-the-world">What I Learned from Kipchoge, the Fastest Marathon Runner in the World</h1>
<p>Kipchoge is not only a world-class athlete, but also a source of inspiration and wisdom for anyone who wants to improve their life. I recently listened to an interview with him on YouTube, and I was amazed by his insights on running, success, pain, discipline and happiness. Here are some of the key takeaways and a summary of what he shared.</p>
<h2 id="preparation-and-planning-is-the-key">Preparation and Planning is the Key</h2>
<p>Kipchoge believes that success does not come by chance, but by pure and clean planning in preparation. He follows a strict program and sticks to it to the letter. He writes down everything in his journal every day, and documents his progress and challenges. He also avoids distractions and focuses on his priorities.</p>
<p>I really appreciate his emphasis on planning everything out meticulously. You should approach your training with a clear goal and intention and make a plan to reach that goal. I also identify with his habit of writing everything down, of course. This is what I&rsquo;ve been practicing myself for several years now, and it is nice to see yet another highly successful person who also shares this habit.</p>
<h2 id="morning-routine">Morning Routine</h2>
<p>Kipchoge has a morning routine which is very similar to my own. He wakes up at 5:45 and is out running by 6:10. When he comes back he has a shower and has breakfast. Only when that is finished will he look at his phone and check his messages and emails.</p>
<p>I also run first thing in the morning. I really enjoy to have it done for the day, and I prefer to exercise on an empty stomach. I think I will try Kipchoge&rsquo;s routine of not looking at the phone until the morning rituals are finished. I tend to check the news and read messages before I go out on my run, and then I use the run to prepare for the day. I&rsquo;ll try to get out with a &ldquo;clean mind&rdquo; and see what happens this week.</p>
<h2 id="movement-leads-to-a-long-and-happy-life">Movement Leads to a Long and Happy Life</h2>
<p>Kipchoge sees running as the best movement and the key to life. He says that life is about movement, and if you move, that&rsquo;s how you have a good life. He runs every day, even when he does not feel like it, because he knows that running is not only good for his body, but also for his mind. He runs in a group of people, and enjoys the social aspect of running. He says that running in a group helps him to talk, exchange ideas and learn from others. He also encourages running as a family lifestyle, and says that running should be fun and enjoyable.</p>
<h2 id="pain-is-part-of-success">Pain is Part of Success</h2>
<p>Kipchoge smiles when he runs, even when he is feeling pain. He says that when he smiles while running, he is actually enjoying the pain. He explains that pain is where success is, and those who know how to handle pain will be successful and move up to another level. Kipchoge also says that training is not the same as competing, and that training happens at a slower pace where you can follow the pace of the group. But when he competes, he pushes himself to the limit and embraces the pain.</p>
<h2 id="vitamin-n">Vitamin N</h2>
<p>Kipchoge shares a simple but powerful advice: inject yourself with vitamin N. What is vitamin N? It stands for NO! Kipchoge says that you need to learn to say no to things that are not aligned with your goals and values. You also need to set your priorities right and avoid complaining. These three things will help you develop self-discipline and achieve your dreams.</p>
<h2 id="listening-to-podcasts">Listening to Podcasts</h2>
<p>When I started running I listened to music, but after I could run for more than 20 minutes, I started to see my runs as a form of active meditation. I deliberately avoid listening to music and podcasts so I can focus completely on the running experience and use the breath, body and movement as meditation objects. However, Kipchoge says that it is all right to listen to music or podcasts during easy runs. They will make the time pass by very quickly.</p>
<p>I hope you enjoyed this blog post and learned something from Kipchoge&rsquo;s wisdom. If you want to listen to the full interview, you can find it here:</p>


    
    <div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
      <iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/X4la2sHwZB0?autoplay=0&controls=1&end=0&loop=0&mute=0&start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video"
      ></iframe>
    </div>

<p>Links:</p>
<p>202307221407</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=X4la2sHwZB0">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=X4la2sHwZB0</a></p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202307221907</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcast Notes: Marc Andreessen: Future of the Internet, Technology, and AI - Lex Fridman Podcast</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/podcast-fridman-andreessen-future-of-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/podcast-fridman-andreessen-future-of-ai/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I want to share some of the highlights and insights from a recent podcast episode that I listened to. It was Lex Fridman Podcast #234, where Lex interviewed Marc Andreessen, the co-creator of Mosaic, the first widely used web browser, the co-founder of Netscape, and the co-founder of the legendary Silicon Valley venture capital firm Andreessen Horowitz. Marc is one of the most outspoken and visionary voices on the future of technology, and he recently wrote an article titled &amp;ldquo;Why AI Will Save the World&amp;rdquo; which I highly recommend.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In this post, I want to share some of the highlights and insights from a recent podcast episode that I listened to. It was Lex Fridman Podcast #234, where Lex interviewed Marc Andreessen, the co-creator of Mosaic, the first widely used web browser, the co-founder of Netscape, and the co-founder of the legendary Silicon Valley venture capital firm Andreessen Horowitz. Marc is one of the most outspoken and visionary voices on the future of technology, and he recently wrote an article titled &ldquo;Why AI Will Save the World&rdquo; which I highly recommend.</p>
<h2 id="the-internet-as-a-medium">The Internet as a Medium</h2>
<p>One of the themes that Marc and Lex discussed was how the Internet is not just a network of computers, but a medium of communication and expression that incorporates and transcends all previous forms of media. Marc quoted Marshall McLuhan, who said that &ldquo;the content of each new medium is the old medium&rdquo;. For example, the content of movies was theater, the content of theater was written stories, and the content of written stories was spoken stories. Similarly, the content of the Internet is television, radio, books, essays, and every other form of prior media.</p>
<p>Interestingly, these patterns seem to have a tendency to return to text. Marc argued that this means that the Internet is not a static or fixed thing, but a dynamic and evolving one. He said that every new technology that comes along changes the nature of the Internet and opens up new possibilities for creativity and innovation. He gave examples such as search engines, social media, video streaming, podcasts, blogs, e-commerce, online education, online gaming, cryptocurrencies, NFTs, VR/AR/MR, and AI. He said that each of these technologies creates new ways for people to interact with information, with each other, and with themselves.</p>
<h2 id="ai-as-a-search-process">AI as a Search Process</h2>
<p>One of the first topics they talked about was how search engines like Google have dominated the way we interact with the Internet for the past 20 years, but how that might change in the next 5 or 10 years with the rise of AI assistants that can communicate with us in natural language and provide us with answers, not just links. Andreessen argued that search was always a hack, a temporary solution that was optimal for accessing the world&rsquo;s information on the web, but not necessarily the best way to interact with knowledge. He said that Google has been trying to move away from &ldquo;the 10 blue links model for a long time&rdquo;, and that AI assistants will be able to do that better by leveraging information from multiple sources and generating content on demand.</p>
<p>Fridman asked whether this would change the motivation and the format of creating content on the Internet, since search engines have driven how we optimize and structure web pages. Andreessen said that there might be less incentive to make web pages, but also more opportunity to create different kinds of content, such as conversations with AIs. He also pointed out that web pages are still a valuable source of training data for AIs, and that AIs might be able to generate synthetic training data as well. He called this a trillion dollar question: whether synthetic data can add signal or not to train better AIs.</p>
<p>Marc explained that AI is fundamentally about searching for patterns in data. This is what neural networks do when they learn from data. They search for patterns that allow them to make predictions about future data. Similarly, this is what humans do when they learn from experience. They search for patterns that allow them to make decisions about future actions. He said that this is also what evolution does when it selects for traits. It searches for patterns that allow organisms to survive and reproduce in changing environments.</p>
<p>I found this discussion very intriguing, because it made me think about how much search engines have shaped our online behavior and expectations, and how much that might change in the near future. I wonder how AI assistants will affect our ability to discover new information, to verify facts, to learn new skills, and to express ourselves online. Will we still have web pages as we know them? Will we still have blogs like this one? Will we still have podcasts like Fridman&rsquo;s? Or will we have something entirely different?</p>
<h2 id="creativity-and-hallucination-in-ai">Creativity and Hallucination in AI</h2>
<p>Another topic they discussed was how AIs can be creative or hallucinate, depending on how we view their output. Andreessen said that we call it hallucination when we don&rsquo;t like what the AI creates, or when it generates something that isn&rsquo;t based on reality. When we do like it, we call it creativity.</p>
<p>Fridman asked how we can know what is true or not when we interact with an AI, especially when it comes to contentious or complex topics. Andreessen said that this is a very difficult problem, and that there is no easy way to determine what is truth or who gets to decide what is truth. He said that we need a lot of humility and skepticism when we encounter claims of truth from any source, human or machine. He also said that we need to embrace the techniques of the Enlightenment, such as the scientific method, rationality, observation, experimentation, hypothesis testing, etc., even when they give us answers we don&rsquo;t like.</p>
<p>He also gave some examples of how AIs can be used for different purposes depending on how we steer them or constrain them. He said that he likes to use AIs for learning about contentious issues by asking them to debate different sides of an argument in good faith or bad faith. He said that he can also ask AIs to strip out the bias from news articles or other sources of information. AIs can be used for legal arguments as well, either in creative mode or in literal mode. He describes experiments he does himself where he gives very specific prompts to two AI models, such as &ldquo;you are a right wing politician defending point X&rdquo; and instructing the other model to be left wing, and then giving instructions such as &ldquo;the discussion should start friendly but end up very heated and none of the AIs should change their mind&rdquo;. I&rsquo;m very fascinated by this type of experiment and I&rsquo;m looking into setting this up for myself because I&rsquo;m very curious about the results.</p>
<h2 id="the-ethical-and-social-implications-of-ai-development-and-deployment">The ethical and social implications of AI development and deployment</h2>
<p>Another topic they talked about was how AI development and deployment will affect society and humanity in the near and long term. Andreessen said that he is optimistic about the positive impact of AI on various domains, such as health, education, entertainment, productivity, etc. He said that AI will save the world by solving many of the problems that we face today, such as climate change, poverty, disease, etc. He also said that AI will create new opportunities and possibilities for human creativity and expression.</p>
<p>Andreessen and Fridman also discussed that the people who are creating AI are not necessarily the best people to make judgements about the deployment of these AIs to the society at large. He draws the analogy with nuclear scientists. These people spend their entire lives in laboratories and they specialize on the technical application. The are not sociologists, and they are perhaps less connected to the society at large and with geo-political landscape. Yet, when nuclear bombs were developed, the were the ones who had a huge say in whether or not it was moral to actually use these weapons.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The competence, capability, intelligence, training, accomplishments of senior scientists and technologists working on a technology, and then being able to then make moral judgments in the use of the technology, that track record is terrible. That track record is catastrophically bad.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Therefore, it should not be the scientists who decide whether or not we start utilizing AI for automated airstrikes, it should be the politicians, philosophers, sociologists and policy makers of the world who are more connected with the morality and socio-political implications of these decisions.</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202307180607</p>
<p><a href="https://lexfridman.com/marc-andreessen/">https://lexfridman.com/marc-andreessen/</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcast Notes - Azure OpenAI with Dr. Linda Sharer</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/podcast-azure-openai/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/podcast-azure-openai/</guid>
      <description>Key points I&amp;rsquo;ve learned LLM models are not malleable. A generative AI model is a static thing which took an enormous amount of compute to get it to the state that it is For example ChatGPT 3.5, 4. They are as they are, they don&amp;rsquo;t change. The models won&amp;rsquo;t remember your previous data. The only way to have a continuous interaction with the model is to feed all of the data into it every time.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="key-points-ive-learned">Key points I&rsquo;ve learned</h1>
<ul>
<li>LLM models are not malleable. A generative AI model is a static thing which took an enormous amount of compute to get it to the state that it is</li>
<li>For example ChatGPT 3.5, 4. They are as they are, they don&rsquo;t change.</li>
<li>The models won&rsquo;t remember your previous data. The only way to have a continuous interaction with the model is to feed all of the data into it every time.</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="summary">Summary</h1>
<p>This podcast is about OpenAI with Dr. Linda Sharer, a senior cloud solution architect for data and AI at Microsoft. The main topic of the episode is Azure Open AI, a service that allows users to interact with powerful generative AI models using natural language. The guest explains the concepts and capabilities of Open AI, such as prompt engineering, one-shot and few-shot learning, fine-tuning, vectorization, and retrieval-augmented generation. She also discusses the design choices and challenges of building applications with Open AI, as well as the integration with other Azure services such as Cognitive Search and ML. The host and the co-host ask questions and share their experiences with using Open AI for various use cases, such as transcribing podcasts, generating code, and searching documents. The web page also provides links to the podcast website, Twitter account, and relevant resources on Open AI.</p>
<h1 id="some-more-bullet-points">Some more bullet points</h1>
<ul>
<li>Open AI models are static and do not change as users interact with them, but they can be influenced by providing examples, instructions, or additional context</li>
<li>One-shot and few-shot learning are techniques to provide examples in the prompt to guide the model&rsquo;s output</li>
<li>Fine-tuning is a technique to train additional layers on top of the model using a file of prompt-completion pairs for a specific use case</li>
<li>Vectorization is a technique to convert language into a numeric representation that captures meaning and allows for semantic search</li>
<li>Retrieval-augmented generation is a technique to combine Open AI with a knowledge store that can provide relevant search results as context for the model&rsquo;s output</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Open AI can be integrated with other Azure services such as Cognitive Search and ML to build applications that leverage different types of data and media</li>
</ul>
<p>If you are interested in learning more about Open AI, you can check out the following resources:</p>
<p>The Azure Podcast episode #466: <a href="https://azpodcast.azurewebsites.net/post/Episode-466-Open-AI">https://azpodcast.azurewebsites.net/post/Episode-466-Open-AI</a></p>
<p>The Azure Open AI service: <a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/services/openai/">https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/services/openai/</a></p>
<p>The Open AI Playground: <a href="https://playground.openai.com/">https://playground.openai.com/</a></p>
<p>The Open AI documentation: <a href="https://docs.openai.com/">https://docs.openai.com/</a></p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202307140707</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcast Notes - Optimal Water Intake</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/optimal-hydration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/optimal-hydration/</guid>
      <description>Hydration Notes from Huberman Podcast For the first 10 hours of the day, consume 236ml for every hour awake
During exercise, follow Galpin equation: 2ml per kg of bodyweight every 15-20 minutes on average.
This does not mean you need to stop exercising and drink this amount. You can also consume it in a larger amount afterwards. It is recommended to drink during exercise though.
Use the normal recommendation to hydrate before exercise, this establishes a good baseline for heading into exercise.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="hydration-notes-from-huberman-podcast">Hydration Notes from Huberman Podcast</h1>
<p>For the first 10 hours of the day, consume 236ml for every hour awake</p>
<p>During exercise, follow Galpin equation: 2ml per kg of bodyweight every 15-20 minutes on average.</p>
<p>This does not mean you need to stop exercising and drink this amount. You can also consume it in a larger amount afterwards. It is recommended to drink during exercise though.</p>
<p>Use the normal recommendation to hydrate before exercise, this establishes a good baseline for heading into exercise.</p>
<h2 id="is-this-amount-of-water-on-top-of-the-baseline-hydration">Is this amount of water on top of the baseline hydration?</h2>
<p>If you exercise about an hour you can replace the number with the number from the Galpin equation.</p>
<p>In my case, 1 hour of exercise = 77 * 2 = 154ml every 20 minutes</p>
<p>154 * 3 = 462ml for 1 hour of exercise</p>
<h2 id="caffeine">Caffeine</h2>
<p>Offset caffeine drinks with a 2:1 water ratio.</p>
<p>So 1 240ml cup of coffee should be followed by 480ml of water.</p>
<h2 id="reducing-nightly-urination">Reducing Nightly Urination</h2>
<p>Urine secretion / filtration in the kidneys is highly dependent on the circadian rhythm.</p>
<p>It is normal to wake up once or twice to urinate during the night.</p>
<p>To reduce nighttime waking for urination:</p>
<ul>
<li>Ensure sufficient hydration during the day so you are not thirsty in the evening</li>
<li>Reduce fluid intake at night (provided you hydrated sufficiently during the day)</li>
<li>Consume no more than 180-240ml between 10 hours after waking and bedtime</li>
</ul>
<p>This means, waking up at 6am, only drink 1 cup of tea after 4pm.</p>
<p>But I drink 500ml at dinner time, so I should probably never drink after dinner from here on out, or just one cup of tea.</p>
<p>How quickly you secrete fluid is also partially determined by how quickly you drink that fluid. Gulping down a lot of fluid wil lead to quicker secretion.</p>
<h1 id="my-typical-day">My Typical Day</h1>
<p>1 hour exercise = 500ml</p>
<p>2 cups of coffee 500ml</p>
<p>10 hours = 2,4l</p>
<p>So I should be drinking about 3,25L in total a day!</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202305301905</p>
<p><a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/gb/podcast/huberman-lab/id1545953110?i=1000602925839">https://podcasts.apple.com/gb/podcast/huberman-lab/id1545953110?i=1000602925839</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI Does Not Grow Exponentially, Thus, Less Scary</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/ai-does-not-grow-exponentially/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/ai-does-not-grow-exponentially/</guid>
      <description>I watch the whole AI craze from the sideline: I am interested in it but I do not spend a lot of time investigating it. But I do pick up a few things here and there.
In this Rich Roll podcast, Kevin Kelly argues that AI does not grow exponentially. It grows linearly, but not exponentially, because it is constrained by the infrastrucutre that we give it, and are able to give it.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[

    
    <div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
      <iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EKba_awaAkk?autoplay=0&controls=1&end=0&loop=0&mute=0&start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video"
      ></iframe>
    </div>

<p>I watch the whole AI craze from the sideline: I am interested in it but I do not spend a lot of time investigating it. But I do pick up a few things here and there.</p>
<p>In this Rich Roll podcast, Kevin Kelly argues that AI does not grow exponentially. It grows linearly, but not exponentially, because it is constrained by the infrastrucutre that we give it, and are able to give it. AI cannot grow by itself. We simply cannot provide enough computing power to enable exponential growth because the technology is not advanced enough yet, which means the growth is stunted.</p>
<p>This makes the doomsday image of an all-powerful single AI that takes over the world and exterminates all humans a lot less likely.</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202305152005</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EKba_awaAkk">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EKba_awaAkk</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
