<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Podcast on Mischa van den Burg</title>
    <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/podcast/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Podcast on Mischa van den Burg</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/podcast/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AI Does Not Grow Exponentially, Thus, Less Scary</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/ai-does-not-grow-exponentially/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/ai-does-not-grow-exponentially/</guid>
      <description>I watch the whole AI craze from the sideline: I am interested in it but I do not spend a lot of time investigating it. But I do pick up a few things here and there.
In this Rich Roll podcast, Kevin Kelly argues that AI does not grow exponentially. It grows linearly, but not exponentially, because it is constrained by the infrastrucutre that we give it, and are able to give it.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EKba_awaAkk" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<p>I watch the whole AI craze from the sideline: I am interested in it but I do not spend a lot of time investigating it. But I do pick up a few things here and there.</p>
<p>In this Rich Roll podcast, Kevin Kelly argues that AI does not grow exponentially. It grows linearly, but not exponentially, because it is constrained by the infrastrucutre that we give it, and are able to give it. AI cannot grow by itself. We simply cannot provide enough computing power to enable exponential growth because the technology is not advanced enough yet, which means the growth is stunted.</p>
<p>This makes the doomsday image of an all-powerful single AI that takes over the world and exterminates all humans a lot less likely.</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202305152005</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EKba_awaAkk">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EKba_awaAkk</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
