<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Podcast on Mischa van den Burg</title>
    <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/podcast/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Podcast on Mischa van den Burg</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/podcast/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Podcast Notes - Azure OpenAI with Dr. Linda Sharer</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/podcast-azure-openai/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/podcast-azure-openai/</guid>
      <description>Key points I&amp;rsquo;ve learned LLM models are not malleable. A generative AI model is a static thing which took an enormous amount of compute to get it to the state that it is For example ChatGPT 3.5, 4. They are as they are, they don&amp;rsquo;t change. The models won&amp;rsquo;t remember your previous data. The only way to have a continuous interaction with the model is to feed all of the data into it every time.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="key-points-ive-learned">Key points I&rsquo;ve learned</h1>
<ul>
<li>LLM models are not malleable. A generative AI model is a static thing which took an enormous amount of compute to get it to the state that it is</li>
<li>For example ChatGPT 3.5, 4. They are as they are, they don&rsquo;t change.</li>
<li>The models won&rsquo;t remember your previous data. The only way to have a continuous interaction with the model is to feed all of the data into it every time.</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="summary">Summary</h1>
<p>This podcast is about OpenAI with Dr. Linda Sharer, a senior cloud solution architect for data and AI at Microsoft. The main topic of the episode is Azure Open AI, a service that allows users to interact with powerful generative AI models using natural language. The guest explains the concepts and capabilities of Open AI, such as prompt engineering, one-shot and few-shot learning, fine-tuning, vectorization, and retrieval-augmented generation. She also discusses the design choices and challenges of building applications with Open AI, as well as the integration with other Azure services such as Cognitive Search and ML. The host and the co-host ask questions and share their experiences with using Open AI for various use cases, such as transcribing podcasts, generating code, and searching documents. The web page also provides links to the podcast website, Twitter account, and relevant resources on Open AI.</p>
<h1 id="some-more-bullet-points">Some more bullet points</h1>
<ul>
<li>Open AI models are static and do not change as users interact with them, but they can be influenced by providing examples, instructions, or additional context</li>
<li>One-shot and few-shot learning are techniques to provide examples in the prompt to guide the model&rsquo;s output</li>
<li>Fine-tuning is a technique to train additional layers on top of the model using a file of prompt-completion pairs for a specific use case</li>
<li>Vectorization is a technique to convert language into a numeric representation that captures meaning and allows for semantic search</li>
<li>Retrieval-augmented generation is a technique to combine Open AI with a knowledge store that can provide relevant search results as context for the model&rsquo;s output</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Open AI can be integrated with other Azure services such as Cognitive Search and ML to build applications that leverage different types of data and media</li>
</ul>
<p>If you are interested in learning more about Open AI, you can check out the following resources:</p>
<p>The Azure Podcast episode #466: <a href="https://azpodcast.azurewebsites.net/post/Episode-466-Open-AI">https://azpodcast.azurewebsites.net/post/Episode-466-Open-AI</a></p>
<p>The Azure Open AI service: <a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/services/openai/">https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/services/openai/</a></p>
<p>The Open AI Playground: <a href="https://playground.openai.com/">https://playground.openai.com/</a></p>
<p>The Open AI documentation: <a href="https://docs.openai.com/">https://docs.openai.com/</a></p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202307140707</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcast Notes - Optimal Water Intake</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/optimal-hydration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/optimal-hydration/</guid>
      <description>Hydration Notes from Huberman Podcast For the first 10 hours of the day, consume 236ml for every hour awake
During exercise, follow Galpin equation: 2ml per kg of bodyweight every 15-20 minutes on average.
This does not mean you need to stop exercising and drink this amount. You can also consume it in a larger amount afterwards. It is recommended to drink during exercise though.
Use the normal recommendation to hydrate before exercise, this establishes a good baseline for heading into exercise.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="hydration-notes-from-huberman-podcast">Hydration Notes from Huberman Podcast</h1>
<p>For the first 10 hours of the day, consume 236ml for every hour awake</p>
<p>During exercise, follow Galpin equation: 2ml per kg of bodyweight every 15-20 minutes on average.</p>
<p>This does not mean you need to stop exercising and drink this amount. You can also consume it in a larger amount afterwards. It is recommended to drink during exercise though.</p>
<p>Use the normal recommendation to hydrate before exercise, this establishes a good baseline for heading into exercise.</p>
<h2 id="is-this-amount-of-water-on-top-of-the-baseline-hydration">Is this amount of water on top of the baseline hydration?</h2>
<p>If you exercise about an hour you can replace the number with the number from the Galpin equation.</p>
<p>In my case, 1 hour of exercise = 77 * 2 = 154ml every 20 minutes</p>
<p>154 * 3 = 462ml for 1 hour of exercise</p>
<h2 id="caffeine">Caffeine</h2>
<p>Offset caffeine drinks with a 2:1 water ratio.</p>
<p>So 1 240ml cup of coffee should be followed by 480ml of water.</p>
<h2 id="reducing-nightly-urination">Reducing Nightly Urination</h2>
<p>Urine secretion / filtration in the kidneys is highly dependent on the circadian rhythm.</p>
<p>It is normal to wake up once or twice to urinate during the night.</p>
<p>To reduce nighttime waking for urination:</p>
<ul>
<li>Ensure sufficient hydration during the day so you are not thirsty in the evening</li>
<li>Reduce fluid intake at night (provided you hydrated sufficiently during the day)</li>
<li>Consume no more than 180-240ml between 10 hours after waking and bedtime</li>
</ul>
<p>This means, waking up at 6am, only drink 1 cup of tea after 4pm.</p>
<p>But I drink 500ml at dinner time, so I should probably never drink after dinner from here on out, or just one cup of tea.</p>
<p>How quickly you secrete fluid is also partially determined by how quickly you drink that fluid. Gulping down a lot of fluid wil lead to quicker secretion.</p>
<h1 id="my-typical-day">My Typical Day</h1>
<p>1 hour exercise = 500ml</p>
<p>2 cups of coffee 500ml</p>
<p>10 hours = 2,4l</p>
<p>So I should be drinking about 3,25L in total a day!</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202305301905</p>
<p><a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/gb/podcast/huberman-lab/id1545953110?i=1000602925839">https://podcasts.apple.com/gb/podcast/huberman-lab/id1545953110?i=1000602925839</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI Does Not Grow Exponentially, Thus, Less Scary</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/ai-does-not-grow-exponentially/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/ai-does-not-grow-exponentially/</guid>
      <description>I watch the whole AI craze from the sideline: I am interested in it but I do not spend a lot of time investigating it. But I do pick up a few things here and there.
In this Rich Roll podcast, Kevin Kelly argues that AI does not grow exponentially. It grows linearly, but not exponentially, because it is constrained by the infrastrucutre that we give it, and are able to give it.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EKba_awaAkk" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<p>I watch the whole AI craze from the sideline: I am interested in it but I do not spend a lot of time investigating it. But I do pick up a few things here and there.</p>
<p>In this Rich Roll podcast, Kevin Kelly argues that AI does not grow exponentially. It grows linearly, but not exponentially, because it is constrained by the infrastrucutre that we give it, and are able to give it. AI cannot grow by itself. We simply cannot provide enough computing power to enable exponential growth because the technology is not advanced enough yet, which means the growth is stunted.</p>
<p>This makes the doomsday image of an all-powerful single AI that takes over the world and exterminates all humans a lot less likely.</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202305152005</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EKba_awaAkk">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EKba_awaAkk</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
