<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Running on Mischa van den Burg</title>
    <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/running/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Running on Mischa van den Burg</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/running/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>New Running Record! Ran 12km today</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/running-record-12km/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/running-record-12km/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;New week, new record! For the first time in my life I ran 12 kilometers, and immediately another 10k PR!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning it was time for my long run, and while I was drinking my coffee I decided to watch a running technique video again to see what I could improve. Lately I have mainly focused on my heart rate and steps per minute, but today I focused more on maintaining a better posture by sticking out my chest a bit more and leaning forward a bit more. The result was that I suddenly ran much faster and more relaxed without this resulting in a higher HR, and my steps per minute were also fine afterwards with 171SPM. These days I usually run around 6:30 but I’m really surprised that I was able to set both a distance record and a higher average speed without having to make any effort except constantly maintaining a better posture. “Running Tall” was the mantra that I kept coming back to when I noticed that I started to sink back.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>New week, new record! For the first time in my life I ran 12 kilometers, and immediately another 10k PR!</p>
<p>This morning it was time for my long run, and while I was drinking my coffee I decided to watch a running technique video again to see what I could improve. Lately I have mainly focused on my heart rate and steps per minute, but today I focused more on maintaining a better posture by sticking out my chest a bit more and leaning forward a bit more. The result was that I suddenly ran much faster and more relaxed without this resulting in a higher HR, and my steps per minute were also fine afterwards with 171SPM. These days I usually run around 6:30 but I’m really surprised that I was able to set both a distance record and a higher average speed without having to make any effort except constantly maintaining a better posture. “Running Tall” was the mantra that I kept coming back to when I noticed that I started to sink back.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/12km1.png" type="" alt=""  /></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/12km2.png" type="" alt=""  /></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/12km3.png" type="" alt=""  /></p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202307221107</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcast Notes: Interview With Eliud Kipchoge, The Fastest Marathon Runner In The World</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/podcast-kipchoge-marathon-running/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/podcast-kipchoge-marathon-running/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-i-learned-from-kipchoge-the-fastest-marathon-runner-in-the-world&#34;&gt;What I Learned from Kipchoge, the Fastest Marathon Runner in the World&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kipchoge is not only a world-class athlete, but also a source of inspiration and wisdom for anyone who wants to improve their life. I recently listened to an interview with him on YouTube, and I was amazed by his insights on running, success, pain, discipline and happiness. Here are some of the key takeaways and a summary of what he shared.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="what-i-learned-from-kipchoge-the-fastest-marathon-runner-in-the-world">What I Learned from Kipchoge, the Fastest Marathon Runner in the World</h1>
<p>Kipchoge is not only a world-class athlete, but also a source of inspiration and wisdom for anyone who wants to improve their life. I recently listened to an interview with him on YouTube, and I was amazed by his insights on running, success, pain, discipline and happiness. Here are some of the key takeaways and a summary of what he shared.</p>
<h2 id="preparation-and-planning-is-the-key">Preparation and Planning is the Key</h2>
<p>Kipchoge believes that success does not come by chance, but by pure and clean planning in preparation. He follows a strict program and sticks to it to the letter. He writes down everything in his journal every day, and documents his progress and challenges. He also avoids distractions and focuses on his priorities.</p>
<p>I really appreciate his emphasis on planning everything out meticulously. You should approach your training with a clear goal and intention and make a plan to reach that goal. I also identify with his habit of writing everything down, of course. This is what I&rsquo;ve been practicing myself for several years now, and it is nice to see yet another highly successful person who also shares this habit.</p>
<h2 id="morning-routine">Morning Routine</h2>
<p>Kipchoge has a morning routine which is very similar to my own. He wakes up at 5:45 and is out running by 6:10. When he comes back he has a shower and has breakfast. Only when that is finished will he look at his phone and check his messages and emails.</p>
<p>I also run first thing in the morning. I really enjoy to have it done for the day, and I prefer to exercise on an empty stomach. I think I will try Kipchoge&rsquo;s routine of not looking at the phone until the morning rituals are finished. I tend to check the news and read messages before I go out on my run, and then I use the run to prepare for the day. I&rsquo;ll try to get out with a &ldquo;clean mind&rdquo; and see what happens this week.</p>
<h2 id="movement-leads-to-a-long-and-happy-life">Movement Leads to a Long and Happy Life</h2>
<p>Kipchoge sees running as the best movement and the key to life. He says that life is about movement, and if you move, that&rsquo;s how you have a good life. He runs every day, even when he does not feel like it, because he knows that running is not only good for his body, but also for his mind. He runs in a group of people, and enjoys the social aspect of running. He says that running in a group helps him to talk, exchange ideas and learn from others. He also encourages running as a family lifestyle, and says that running should be fun and enjoyable.</p>
<h2 id="pain-is-part-of-success">Pain is Part of Success</h2>
<p>Kipchoge smiles when he runs, even when he is feeling pain. He says that when he smiles while running, he is actually enjoying the pain. He explains that pain is where success is, and those who know how to handle pain will be successful and move up to another level. Kipchoge also says that training is not the same as competing, and that training happens at a slower pace where you can follow the pace of the group. But when he competes, he pushes himself to the limit and embraces the pain.</p>
<h2 id="vitamin-n">Vitamin N</h2>
<p>Kipchoge shares a simple but powerful advice: inject yourself with vitamin N. What is vitamin N? It stands for NO! Kipchoge says that you need to learn to say no to things that are not aligned with your goals and values. You also need to set your priorities right and avoid complaining. These three things will help you develop self-discipline and achieve your dreams.</p>
<h2 id="listening-to-podcasts">Listening to Podcasts</h2>
<p>When I started running I listened to music, but after I could run for more than 20 minutes, I started to see my runs as a form of active meditation. I deliberately avoid listening to music and podcasts so I can focus completely on the running experience and use the breath, body and movement as meditation objects. However, Kipchoge says that it is all right to listen to music or podcasts during easy runs. They will make the time pass by very quickly.</p>
<p>I hope you enjoyed this blog post and learned something from Kipchoge&rsquo;s wisdom. If you want to listen to the full interview, you can find it here:</p>


    
    <div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
      <iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/X4la2sHwZB0?autoplay=0&controls=1&end=0&loop=0&mute=0&start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video"
      ></iframe>
    </div>

<p>Links:</p>
<p>202307221407</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=X4la2sHwZB0">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=X4la2sHwZB0</a></p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202307221907</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovered MAF and Low Heart Rate Training</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/discovered-maf-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/discovered-maf-training/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Although I was already doing something very similar, yesterday I discovered MAF training through this video:&lt;/p&gt;


    
    &lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/P_VNQ6UIbS8?autoplay=0&amp;controls=1&amp;end=0&amp;loop=0&amp;mute=0&amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;
      &gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This video is super inspiring because he actually runs a 3 hour marathon while recording!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Although I was already doing something very similar, yesterday I discovered MAF training through this video:</p>


    
    <div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
      <iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/P_VNQ6UIbS8?autoplay=0&controls=1&end=0&loop=0&mute=0&start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video"
      ></iframe>
    </div>

<p>This video is super inspiring because he actually runs a 3 hour marathon while recording!</p>
<p>I was already doing <a href="/zet/base-training-running/">base training for my running</a> which I discovered through the r/running Reddit. Here you focus on time instead of distance and do many runs on low intensity throughout the week, and one long run where you go 5 minutes more every week.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m now in week 6 of my base training schedule and I&rsquo;m progressing nicely. My long run went from 50 minutes to 86 minutes, and my weekly total distance has increased from 20,6km to 32,8km!</p>
<h1 id="maf-training">MAF Training</h1>
<p>MAF stands for Maximum Aerobic Function and was developed by Dr. Phil Maffetone.</p>
<p>It uses <a href="https://philmaffetone.com/180-formula/">the 180 formula</a> to calculate the maximum heart rate you should hit during your run. What wasn&rsquo;t obvious from all the other videos I watched, was that this maximum heart rate actually establishes a zone you should be training in.</p>
<p>I discovered this in Dr. Maffetone&rsquo;s Book:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Once a maximum aerobic heart rate is found, a training range from this heart rate to 10 beats below could be used as a training range. For example, if an athlete’s maximum aerobic heart rate is determined to be 155, that person’s aerobic training zone would be 145 to 155 bpm. However, the more training at 155, the quicker an optimal aerobic base will be developed.</p>
</blockquote>
<h1 id="current-situation">Current Situation</h1>
<p>I hadn&rsquo;t been paying much attention to my heart rate up until this point. I just used the guideline of &ldquo;conversational pace&rdquo;, and that runs should feel easy and enjoyable. However, I knew I was going to need metrics one day, so I diligently tracked my workouts using my iWatch SE from day 1.</p>
<p>Here are my current heart rate stats and zones:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/zones.jpg" type="" alt=""  /></p>
<p>Going through my recent runs, my average heart rate has been around 100-115bpm. For example:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/heart.png" type="" alt=""  /></p>
<h1 id="time-to-start-nerding-on-some-numbers">Time To Start Nerding On Some Numbers</h1>
<p>Using the 180 formula, I calculated that I should use 180 - 33 - 5 = 142 as a maximum heart rate for my endurance training, which gives me a training zone of 132-142bpm. This is about 15 beats higher than I was used to! And if you look at the zones that Apple calculated for me, you&rsquo;ll see that this almost perfectly matches my calculated Zone 2.</p>
<p>After I calculated my new target, I tried it out immediately this morning. Here is the result:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/firstmaf.jpg" type="" alt=""  /></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/firstmaf2.jpg" type="" alt=""  /></p>


<div class="strava-embed-placeholder" data-embed-type="activity" data-embed-id="9143184934"></div><script src="https://strava-embeds.com/embed.js"></script>


<p>This definitely felt very different! After some experimentation and keeping an eye on my heart rate rising and falling, I managed to find a pattern that kept it around 135bpm. It felt much more like running instead of jogging. And I was surprised that even though I was running quite a bit faster than I was used to, I could still maintain a conversation if I wanted to, so I was still at a conversational pace. I had just estimated my conversational pace a lot lower than I was capable of. This shows you the power of using metrics for training! It definitely pushed me to go a little harder, a little faster, even though I&rsquo;m stil doing &ldquo;easy running&rdquo;.</p>
<p>Towards the end my legs started to hurt quite a bit more than usual, it felt much more like a workout, even though I was not totally exhausted in the end. The previous run I shared had a pace of 7.41/km and this one was on 6.42/km, which is a lot faster.</p>
<p>I have come to a point where all these numbers are starting to make sense to me now and I can start tracking them. Especially the heart rate has been a real eye opener. Now I have a perfect gauge to use while training: something that will let me know whether I should put in some more effort or slow down.</p>
<p>Already I&rsquo;m getting so much joy of seeing the progress I&rsquo;ve made from week 1 to 6, and seeing the numbers increase. I&rsquo;m really falling in love with this sport in so many ways, it&rsquo;s perfect for a nerd like me!</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202305261305</p>
<p><a href="https://philmaffetone.com/180-formula/">https://philmaffetone.com/180-formula/</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=e5wgoTuJuF8">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=e5wgoTuJuF8</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Ran 10k For The First Time Today</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/running-first-10k/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/running-first-10k/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I ran 10k for the first time in my life today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ran &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tumblr.com/mischavandenburg/717301155801235456/went-to-heemskerk-today-broke-my-running-record?source=share&#34;&gt;to the beach and back in Heemskerk&lt;/a&gt; on hardened forest roads, listening to the birds and feeling the spring sun on my face. I felt great and had a smile on my face most of the time. Lots of interesting thoughts popping up in the mind as I run and reflect. Hardly noticed that 77 minutes went by because I was having such a good time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I ran 10k for the first time in my life today.</p>
<p>I ran <a href="https://www.tumblr.com/mischavandenburg/717301155801235456/went-to-heemskerk-today-broke-my-running-record?source=share">to the beach and back in Heemskerk</a> on hardened forest roads, listening to the birds and feeling the spring sun on my face. I felt great and had a smile on my face most of the time. Lots of interesting thoughts popping up in the mind as I run and reflect. Hardly noticed that 77 minutes went by because I was having such a good time.</p>
<p>
  <img loading="lazy" src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/c2a5ec4a82684e3419ae336dbe388e6f/0c473022c40cc8ca-36/s1280x1920/8f0a174f159bd1445c7529cabed3a415d31f7147.jpg" alt=""  /></p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202305141605</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Having Fun While Running And Exploring</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/running-exploring-fun/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/running-exploring-fun/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you would have told me 5 years, 3 years, 1 year, or even 3 months ago, that one day I would be 50 minutes into a run with a big beaming smile on my face, I would have never believed you, but today it happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My base building schedule is giving me good results. I did this week&amp;rsquo;s long run this morning and it was 7 minutes longer than last week&amp;rsquo;s long run. I ran 8.5 kilometres in 67 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you would have told me 5 years, 3 years, 1 year, or even 3 months ago, that one day I would be 50 minutes into a run with a big beaming smile on my face, I would have never believed you, but today it happened.</p>
<p>My base building schedule is giving me good results. I did this week&rsquo;s long run this morning and it was 7 minutes longer than last week&rsquo;s long run. I ran 8.5 kilometres in 67 minutes.</p>
<p>And the best thing was: I was smiling. I was having fun. Running on an easy pace has been such a game changer for me. Sure, I&rsquo;m probably the slowest runner on earth. It&rsquo;s more like jogging, just a little bit faster than my speed when I do a brisk walk. But I&rsquo;m running. I&rsquo;m building a base, I&rsquo;m doing the first steps, and from here I can grow.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m also discovering another fun element to the sport: exploration. I moved to my current city less than a year ago and it is unexplored territory. I&rsquo;m now creating a network of nice runs and circuits for myself and I&rsquo;m discovering places I would never have discovered otherwise. Now that I&rsquo;m able to run longer distances, I can start exploring more. Just running on one direction for half and hour and seeing where I end up. Then I look for a nice way back, and this way I&rsquo;ve discoverd a few nice rounds already.</p>
<p>Today the sun was shining, it was 17 degrees, I did the longest run I&rsquo;ve ever done, and when I came back I felt good: energized, happy and satisfied. The endorphins where rushing through my body. Not exactly a &ldquo;runner&rsquo;s high&rdquo;, I think, but definitely a sense of calm and achievement.</p>
<p>Last week my knee started to hurt during my 60 minute run, but this week I had no pain at all. My body is adjusting.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m coming to a point where I&rsquo;m starting to fall in love with running. I just pray I won&rsquo;t run into injuries!</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202305071305</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I ran 5K for the first time in my life!</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/ran-5km/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/ran-5km/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I reached a significant milestone. I ran my first 5K!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always been on the heavy side. I did a lot of weightlifting from age 18 to around 27 and I was always rather bulky, but very strong. This meant I was very good at working in the woods or helping people move house, but I&amp;rsquo;ve never been able to do any running or endurance because my knees would start protesting very quickly. However, I always admired endurance athletes and I had the desire to be able to run more than a few minutes without feeling the urge to die on the spot.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday I reached a significant milestone. I ran my first 5K!</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve always been on the heavy side. I did a lot of weightlifting from age 18 to around 27 and I was always rather bulky, but very strong. This meant I was very good at working in the woods or helping people move house, but I&rsquo;ve never been able to do any running or endurance because my knees would start protesting very quickly. However, I always admired endurance athletes and I had the desire to be able to run more than a few minutes without feeling the urge to die on the spot.</p>
<p>Over the past 1,5 years I lost 20kg (~44 pounds) so I decided to give it yet another try.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve never been this lightweight so I decided to give running another try. I started small with only 10 minutes but over the course of two months I built it up gradually.</p>
<p>Last week I ran 4km and it felt pretty good, so I just decided to push a little bit more and try for my goal of 5k, and it went well! It feels like quite an accomplishment to me.</p>
<p>Now that I lost all this weight running actually feels good, and it is liberating to discover a whole new area of exercise that I haven&rsquo;t explored yet: endurance. Looking back to my progress over a couple of months, I&rsquo;m curious how far I&rsquo;ll come and what my limits are.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
