<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>MacOS on Mischa van den Burg</title>
    <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/macos/</link>
    <description>Recent content in MacOS on Mischa van den Burg</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/macos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>New Laptop: Moving to MacOS</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/move-to-macos/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/move-to-macos/</guid>
      <description>My new employer kindly sponsored me with a new 16-inch MacBook Pro M2. I chose 32GB Ram and the base model with 12 CPU and 19 GPU cores and 1TB of hard disk. These specifications will suit my needs well.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been daily driving Linux for a year now, and it has been such an incredible journey. Building my own Arch Linux system taught me much about Linux and what it means to maintain a system yourself.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>My new employer kindly sponsored me with a new 16-inch MacBook Pro M2. I chose 32GB Ram and the base model with 12 CPU and 19 GPU cores and 1TB of hard disk. These specifications will suit my needs well.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve been daily driving Linux for a year now, and it has been such an incredible journey. Building my own Arch Linux system taught me much about Linux and what it means to maintain a system yourself. I will undoubtedly miss my custom AwesomeWM configuration and the freedom that Arch provides.</p>
<p>Technically I could have chosen a Windows laptop and installed Linux on it. But I went for a Mac for the following reasons:</p>
<ul>
<li>Compatibility. I&rsquo;ll be doing contracts for various customers, so I&rsquo;ll likely run into environments where I&rsquo;ll need to use some software, such as a VPN that is not supported on Linux. MacOS will always be compatible everywhere.</li>
<li>Portability. I&rsquo;ll probably be going to the office multiple times a week, and using a MacBook as a daily driver will allow me to take my full setup with me everywhere. I also plan to spend some time abroad, and using a MacBook as a daily driver will allow me to work remotely for extended periods.</li>
<li>Stability. Even though my Linux systems never really broke on me, there is always a possibility. I don&rsquo;t have to worry about that with MacOS.</li>
</ul>
<p>Even though I&rsquo;ll be switching to my MacBook as my primary workstation, I will continue using Linux for my hobby projects and home lab. So there will be plenty of opportunity to keep growing in that area in the future.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
