<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Longevity on Mischa van den Burg</title>
    <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/longevity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Longevity on Mischa van den Burg</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/longevity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What My Ancestors Ate</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/what-my-ancestors-ate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/what-my-ancestors-ate/</guid>
      <description>Professor Longo recommends eating the same ingredients that your ancestors ate in his book The Longevity Diet.
Today I asked my 91 year old grandmother about her diet and her eating habits when she was younger. She was around 10 years old during the Second World War when food was very scarce and people were struggling to survive. I knew already that meat was a luxury product during her early life and that they consumed meat maybe once or twice a week in small quantities.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Professor Longo recommends eating the same ingredients that your ancestors ate in his book <a href="/zet/longevity-diet/">The Longevity Diet</a>.</p>
<p>Today I asked my 91 year old grandmother about her diet and her eating habits when she was younger. She was around 10 years old during the Second World War when food was very scarce and people were struggling to survive. I knew already that meat was a luxury product during her early life and that they consumed meat maybe once or twice a week in small quantities.</p>
<p>From our conversation I learned the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>they ate three meals a day: breakfast, a larger warm midday meal and a light evening meal</li>
<li>the staples were oatmeal, rice (which surprised me), potatoes, carrots, bread, milk, cheese and eggs</li>
<li>breakfast was usually oatmeal porridge</li>
<li>they ate dinner at noon and had a light meal in the evening, usually a couple of slices of bread</li>
<li>dinner was often rice porridge boiled in milk or potatoes with carrots, onions and a little meat (hutspot)</li>
<li>she had never eaten french fries until she was 60 years old</li>
<li>they didn&rsquo;t have any snacks</li>
<li>sometimes she was sent to bed with only a carrot</li>
</ul>
<p>I have always loved eating oatmeal, rice, bread and potatoes, and I never grow tired of these ingredients. Now I know why! It is exactly what my ancestors ate. I will keep eating these as main staples of my diet.</p>
<p>Especially the rice was surprising to me, I didn&rsquo;t know that rice was generally available during that time already but apparently it was.</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202309302009</p>
<p>[[health]]
[[diet]]
[[Longo-The Longevity Diet]]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
