<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Hardware on Mischa van den Burg</title>
    <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/hardware/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hardware on Mischa van den Burg</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/hardware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Starting My Homelab</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/starting-my-homelab/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/starting-my-homelab/</guid>
      <description>This week I started a project which I&amp;rsquo;ve been putting off for too long. I finally started my homelab. Over the past year I&amp;rsquo;ve been collecting hardware here and there, and I&amp;rsquo;ve had the intention to start up a proper Kubernetes cluster at home. I got inspired by Rob Muhlenstein&amp;rsquo;s Homelab Init playlist on YouTube which I&amp;rsquo;m working on.
There are a few reasons why I haven&amp;rsquo;t started up until now:</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This week I started a project which I&rsquo;ve been putting off for too long. I finally started my homelab. Over the past year I&rsquo;ve been collecting hardware here and there, and I&rsquo;ve had the intention to start up a proper Kubernetes cluster at home. I got inspired by Rob Muhlenstein&rsquo;s <a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLrK9UeDMcQLpjUGg5z9Z6Un-axVx06-2J">Homelab Init</a> playlist on YouTube which I&rsquo;m working on.</p>
<p>There are a few reasons why I haven&rsquo;t started up until now:</p>
<ul>
<li>Focused on switching jobs and certifications</li>
<li>Not knowing what to run on the cluster</li>
<li>High electricity costs</li>
</ul>
<p>Now that I found a new job with a great employer, I&rsquo;ve changed my focus towards doing more hands-on learning in my free time by learning Go and diving deeper into Cloud Native technology. Energy prices have come down in the meantime as well.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve reached a stage in my Go learning journey where I&rsquo;m actually able to start making small deployable applications, and I want an environment where I can do that without high costs or without fearing to break something. I want to learn more about databases on Kubernetes, and I want to start writing small microservices and API&rsquo;s that are able to query these databases.</p>
<p>My lab is going to be my playground, where I can deploy whatever I want and learn the technologies that interest me at that particular moment.</p>
<h1 id="hardware-parts">Hardware: Parts</h1>
<p>For some reason the Raspberry Pi has become synonymous with homelabs. I get that it&rsquo;s fun to run a cluster on something that is not much larger than a 1kg pack of sugar. But I never really caught on to that whole scene yet. Maybe it&rsquo;s because I&rsquo;m a bit late to the party and the Pi&rsquo;s have been scarce and very expensive lately?</p>
<p>In any case, I&rsquo;ve been thankfully accepting old computers that friends were going to get rid of, and I&rsquo;ve been keeping some of my own old hardware as well. I have enough motherboards and other parts to assemble around 3 nodes, which will probably have around 8GB RAM each, but possibilities to attach storage.</p>
<p>This is also what has been keeping me back for a while I think. There is quite a bit of work that I need to do to get these machines going, and probably I&rsquo;ll have to purchase a couple of other parts. However, I also have some functional hardware.</p>
<h2 id="gaming-desktop">Gaming Desktop</h2>
<p>I have an old gaming desktop with 16GB RAM, an Intel 6700K Skylake, 1070 video card and a couple of TB of storage.</p>
<p>This has been my Arch Linux desktop for the past year, but now that I switched to my new MacBook, I&rsquo;m not using it as much. I want to keep it as it is right now, but I could run a few Virtual Machines on there, and maybe consider turning it into a ProxMox server.</p>
<h2 id="old-laptops">Old Laptops</h2>
<p>I have two old laptops. One Asus with 4GB of RAM and a Thinkpad T430 with 8GB RAM. The Thinkpad is actually surprisingly powerful. As a weekend project I installed Arch on it and I fitted it with a refurbished keyboard, and it is a very pleasant machine to work with. However, now that I have a very powerful laptop that I use as a desktop and portable device, it has become redundant.</p>
<h1 id="old-laptops-as-raspberri-pis">Old Laptops as Raspberri Pi&rsquo;s</h1>
<p>Having these two old laptops lying around, it occurred to me that these machines were basically Raspberri Pi&rsquo;s with a large form factor and a higher power usage. Why would I need to spend hundreds of euros on these smaller computers if I could just use these laptops as a starting point for my lab?</p>
<p>Using laptops has the following advantages:</p>
<ul>
<li>No additional costs</li>
<li>No building needed</li>
<li>Easy to install Linux on them</li>
<li>Built-in screen and keyboard for quick access when SSH does not work out</li>
<li>Built-in batteries to handle short power disruptions (rare but possible)</li>
<li>Can get going very quickly</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="choices-and-goals">Choices and Goals</h1>
<h2 id="kubernetes">Kubernetes</h2>
<p>The first goal is to get a Kubernetes cluster running. I will do bare metal kubeadm installs, and later I want to learn more about Talos. Fortunately I feel very comfortable installing Kubernetes with kubeadm. I did plenty of practice for my CKA, and I recently installed it on free Oracle VM&rsquo;s. I&rsquo;ve experimented a bit with K9S earlier, but I want to learn how to maintain on-prem Kubernetes.</p>
<p>My goals is to learn to maintain production-grade clusters properly.</p>
<h2 id="linux">Linux</h2>
<p>Naturally I&rsquo;ll be using Linux as my base OS. After some consideration I chose to use Ubuntu Server 22. Some notes on that choice:</p>
<ul>
<li>I already have years of Ubuntu Server experience</li>
<li>Good to keep building on what I have</li>
<li>Working with managed Kubernetes on my day job requires me to keep Linux admin skills fresh</li>
<li>Still the <a href="https://www.enterpriseappstoday.com/stats/linux-statistics.html">most popular Linux distro</a></li>
<li>Google uses Ubuntu Server</li>
<li>Well documented and plenty of questions on StackOverflow</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="infrastructure-as-code--gitops">Infrastructure as Code &amp; GitOps</h2>
<p>Initially I&rsquo;ll configure the servers by hand, but I want to have the server configuration as code as Ansible playbooks eventually. However, I&rsquo;ll be using ArgoCD for all of my deployments on Kubernetes itself, so the server configuration is only a very small part of the setup. Just get Kubernetes running and do the rest with ArgoCD.</p>
<p>Perhaps I will expand with larger servers that run multiple VM&rsquo;s. Then it will be very relevant to start provisioning these with Ansible.</p>
<h2 id="networking">Networking</h2>
<p>I want to learn more about networking and use static IP addresses for my servers. I need to figure out how my home network works exactly. Surprisingly, I&rsquo;ve never taken the effort to actually know how the devices on my network get their IP addresses and how they communicate, even though I&rsquo;ve learned plenty about it for my day job and do networking in an enterprise environment daily.</p>
<p>For Kubernetes I&rsquo;ll use Flannel to start out with, but I want to learn more about Cilium, Istio and other service mesh implementations.</p>
<p>Another goal is to host my own DNS server for internal name resolution, probably CoreDNS.</p>
<h2 id="deployment">Deployment</h2>
<p>I want to host my own container registry (Harbor) and use Tekton pipelines to for CI/CD, and I&rsquo;m playing with the thought to host my own GitLab instance as well.</p>
<h1 id="lets-go">Let&rsquo;s Go!</h1>
<p>Another realization was that I don&rsquo;t need to have everything figured out before I begin. The beauty of cluster computing is that you can add to it as you go. I can start with a small cluster of two nodes and build it out as my needs grow. I don&rsquo;t expect to need more than a few GB of RAM in the foreseeable future, so these two laptops will be plenty to get going.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/cluster-laptops.png" type="" alt=""  /></p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>2023041213</p>
<p>[[homelab]]</p>
<p>[[homelab-network]]</p>
<p>[[Linux]]</p>
<p>[[homelab-ubuntu-server]]</p>
<p>[[Kubernetes]]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
