<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Explanations on Mischa&#39;s Blog &amp; Zettelkasten</title>
    <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/explanations/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Explanations on Mischa&#39;s Blog &amp; Zettelkasten</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 08:41:09 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/explanations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Application Insights: Telemetry Sampling</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/application-insights-sampling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 08:41:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/application-insights-sampling/</guid>
      <description>Telemetry is the collection of measurements or other data at remote points, and transmitting that data to a receiver for monitoring.
Sampling is used to reduce telemetry traffic and costs for storage and data in Application Insights.
For small and medium sized applications sampling is generally not necessary.
Advantages of sampling:
Throttling data when the application suddenly sends a high volume of telemetry in a short time This saves costs! Keeping a pricing tier quota Reduce network traffic from telemetry collection Three different kinds of sampling:</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Telemetry is the collection of measurements or other data at remote points, and transmitting that data to a receiver for monitoring.</p>
<p>Sampling is used to reduce telemetry traffic and costs for storage and data in Application Insights.</p>
<p>For small and medium sized applications sampling is generally not necessary.</p>
<p>Advantages of sampling:</p>
<ul>
<li>Throttling data when the application suddenly sends a high volume of telemetry in a short time
<ul>
<li>This saves costs!</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Keeping a pricing tier quota</li>
<li>Reduce network traffic from telemetry collection</li>
</ul>
<p>Three different kinds of sampling:</p>
<ul>
<li>adaptive sampling
<ul>
<li>automatically adjusts volume of telemetry</li>
<li>from ASP.NET or Azure Functions</li>
<li>only for these two</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>fixed-rate sampling
<ul>
<li>rate is set by the administrator</li>
<li>use when you have a clear idea of the appropriate sampling percentage</li>
<li>reduces volume from
<ul>
<li>ASP.NET or ASP.NET Core server</li>
<li>Java server</li>
<li>Python applications</li>
<li>User browsers</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>ingestion sampling
<ul>
<li>used when monthly quota is often met</li>
<li>reduces amount of processed and retained traffic by Application Insights
<ul>
<li>less processing = less cost</li>
<li>doesn&rsquo;t reduce telemetry traffic sent from the app</li>
<li>happens at Applications Insight service endpoint</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>disabled if SDK samples telemetry</li>
<li>can set sampling rate without redeploying the app</li>
<li>only applies when no other sampling is in effect
<ul>
<li>supports all Application Insights SDK&rsquo;s</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pipelines: Continuous Monitoring</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/pipelines-continuous-monitoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 08:30:03 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/pipelines-continuous-monitoring/</guid>
      <description>This term can be confusing. Initially I thought it meant monitoring of the pipelines themselves. However, in the context of Azure Release Pipelines, continuous monitoring refers to something else.
Continuous monitoring leverages metrics from other services such as Application Insights. You can set up release gates based on these metrics. For example, you can set up a release gate to roll back the deployment if an alert is being fired for high CPU usage in the application.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This term can be confusing. Initially I thought it meant monitoring of the pipelines themselves. However, in the context of Azure Release Pipelines, continuous monitoring refers to something else.</p>
<p>Continuous monitoring leverages metrics from other services such as Application Insights. You can set up release gates based on these metrics. For example, you can set up a release gate to roll back the deployment if an alert is being fired for high CPU usage in the application.</p>
<p>You can set up several of these checks. If all these checks pass, the pipeline can proceed.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distributed Tracing</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/distributed-tracing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 07:58:44 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/distributed-tracing/</guid>
      <description>Debugging is done using call stacks in monolithic applications. Nowadays it is more common to deploy an application using a microservices architecture. Microservices make it easier to update certain parts of the application, and allow for more frequent deployments.
Using microservices does have a disadvantage: you cannot use the local call stack for debugging, because calls are sent to different microservices.
Distributed tracing is an implementation of the call stack in the cloud.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Debugging is done using <a href="/zet/call-stacks/">call stacks</a> in monolithic applications. Nowadays it is more common to deploy an application using a microservices architecture. Microservices make it easier to update certain parts of the application, and allow for more frequent deployments.</p>
<p>Using microservices does have a disadvantage: you cannot use the local call stack for debugging, because calls are sent to different microservices.</p>
<p>Distributed tracing is an implementation of the call stack in the cloud. It is usually implemented by adding an agent, <a href="/zet/sdk/">SDK</a>, or library to the service. In Azure you can enable distributed tracing via Application Insights through auto-instrumentation or SDKs.</p>
<p><a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/azure-monitor/app/transaction-diagnostics">Unified cross-component transaction diagnostics</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a SDK?</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/sdk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 07:50:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/sdk/</guid>
      <description>A software development kit (SDK) is a set of tools provided by the manufacturer of (usually) a hardware platform, operating system (OS), or programming language.
SDKs contain all the tools you need to get started. They typically contain a compiler, a debugger and an API. But they can also contain documentation and testing tools.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A software development kit (SDK) is a set of tools provided by the manufacturer of (usually) a hardware platform, operating system (OS), or programming language.</p>
<p>SDKs contain all the tools you need to get started. They typically contain a compiler, a debugger and an API. But they can also contain documentation and testing tools.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How This Blog is Created, Written and Hosted</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/articles/how-this-blog-is-created/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/articles/how-this-blog-is-created/</guid>
      <description>As I alluded to in my article about Obsidian, I am very fond of editing my text in neovim. Naturally, if you want to edit in neovim, you need to have your text as local files. I keep all of my personal notes in markdown.
Previously I was using WordPress, but the editing and writing experience became torture which I could not endure any longer. I looked for a different solution that would allow me to edit my files locally instead of in the browser.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As I alluded to in my <a href="/articles/obsidian-introduction">article about Obsidian,</a> I am very fond of editing my text in neovim. Naturally, if you want to edit in neovim, you need to have your text as local files. I keep all of my personal notes in markdown.</p>
<p>Previously I was using WordPress, but the editing and writing experience became torture which I could not endure any longer. I looked for a different solution that would allow me to edit my files locally instead of in the browser.</p>
<p>I discovered <a href="https://gohugo.io/">Hugo</a> and I fell in love with it immediately.</p>
<p>Hugo is a static site generator based on markdown files. My entire blog is written in markdown files which are stored <a href="https://github.com/mischavandenburg/blog">in a GitHub repo.</a>. I write my blog posts in vim and when I&rsquo;m done I use Hugo to generate the updated website.</p>
<p>The result is what you see in the &ldquo;public&rdquo; directory in the GitHub repo. This public directory is pushed to a different repo which is hooked up to my hosting provider. My hosting provider uses Plesk, and with Plesk I have the option to connect the GitHub repo to the web server with a webhook. When I push to my hosting repo, the contents are gathered by the webserver and served as public web content.</p>
<p>My complete writing and publishing workflow looks like this:</p>
<ol>
<li>Create a new markdown file</li>
<li>Write the note or article</li>
<li>Save the file and run the &ldquo;hugo&rdquo; command to regenerate the website</li>
<li>Run the &ldquo;publish&rdquo; script. This is a custom script I wrote that takes the contents of the &ldquo;public&rdquo; directory to my hosting repo</li>
<li>Push the newly generated website to the hosting repo</li>
<li>And we&rsquo;re live! 🚀 🎉</li>
</ol>
<p>It is such a smooth and convenient process. I can literally have a new note published to the interet within a few minutes, and it is all done from the command line using my favorite tools.</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/mischavandenburg/blog">Blog GitHub repo</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Are Containers?</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/articles/what-are-containers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 16:17:58 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/articles/what-are-containers/</guid>
      <description>When you learn about DevOps, you will come across the concept of a container early on. This is a &amp;ldquo;Mischa Explains&amp;rdquo; article where I attempt to explain a concept in my own words as simply as possible. I use the Feynman technique and pretend to explain it to a 12-year-old.
Virtualization To understand containers, we need to understand virtualization. Virtualization is the process of creating &amp;ldquo;fake computers&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;virtual computers&amp;rdquo; on a physical computer.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When you learn about DevOps, you will come across the concept of a container early on. This is a &ldquo;Mischa Explains&rdquo; article where I attempt to explain a concept in my own words as simply as possible. I use the Feynman technique and pretend to explain it to a 12-year-old.</p>
<h1 id="virtualization">Virtualization</h1>
<p>To understand containers, we need to understand virtualization. Virtualization is the process of creating &ldquo;fake computers&rdquo; or &ldquo;virtual computers&rdquo; on a physical computer.</p>
<p>On your desk, you have a laptop or a desktop PC. This machine has hardware such as a motherboard, a hard disk, and a video card. To run programs on your computer, it needs an Operating System. Usually, Windows, macOS, or Linux are used.</p>
<p>Let&rsquo;s say you have a computer running Windows, but you want to run a program that can only run on Linux. One solution is to buy another laptop and put it beside your Windows laptop on your desk. So now you have two computers with two different operating systems.</p>
<p>Fortunately, there are other solutions. We can use virtualization to make a Virtual Machine. A virtual machine is created by software to imitate a fully functional running computer inside your current operating system. You can create a virtual machine that runs Linux on your Windows computer. Your Windows computer running the Linux virtual machine is known as the **host.</p>
<p>Now you don&rsquo;t need to buy another computer to run your Linux program. Instead, you can boot up your Linux virtual machine and run your program when needed. If you have a powerful computer, you could run ten or more virtual machines, each of which has its own operating system and custom environment.</p>
<h1 id="containers">Containers</h1>
<p>Every time you create a virtual machine, the virtual machine needs a complete operating system to work. So, first, the software creates a virtual processor, virtual video card, and a virtual network interface. Then, it runs a fully functional operating system on that virtual hardware. This takes up a lot of resources.</p>
<p>Containers are lightweight packages of software. They are designed to do a very specific task, and therefore they only contain the resources they need to do that task. Nothing more.</p>
<p>Containers use the operating system of the physical computer to run. They have a very minimal, lightweight operating system inside them, but it only contains the elements they need to do their specific task. Therefore, containers are very easy to distribute, and you can run them very quickly.</p>
<h1 id="containers-are-like-newspapers">Containers are like newspapers</h1>
<p>Containers are like newspapers. Newspapers have a particular task: providing you with the day&rsquo;s news. You cannot use newspapers to study for your mathematics exam. You use your math book to study for your math exam. If you want to be informed of the day&rsquo;s news, you use a newspaper. This is what I mean by containers having a specific task.</p>
<p>Next, newspapers are printed on a specific kind of paper. When you buy an expensive book, it will have a sturdy and durable cover, and the pages are made of nice thick paper that will last a long time. The pages don&rsquo;t tear very quickly, and when the book gets wet, it can withstand it. This thick cover and high-quality papers are like the operating system of a virtual machine.</p>
<p>Newspapers, on the other hand, are printed on very thin paper. Because they are designed to distribute the news to you effectively, newspapers do not need to be stored forever or do any other tasks. If you used thick, expensive paper for newspapers, they would become costly, and no one would buy them anymore. The paper is optimized to bring the news to you.</p>
<p>In the same way, the container only comes with the components it needs to do its specific task. Therefore, the container is optimized for its purpose. As a result, they can be distributed more quickly and do not take up a lot of resources when running.</p>
<p>There are other benefits to containers, such as improving the ability to autoscale your application, but I will expand on those in a future blog post.</p>
<h1 id="further-study">Further study</h1>
<p>To learn more about containers, you can use the following resources:</p>
<p><a href="https://youtu.be/r6YIlPEC4y4">Containers &amp; Friends from John Savill&rsquo;s DevOps Masterclass</a></p>
<p><a href="https://docs.docker.com/get-started/overview/">Docker Documentation</a></p>
<p><a href="https://youtu.be/3c-iBn73dDE">Docker Tutorial for Beginners</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tokens and Identity on the Internet</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/articles/identity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2022 00:55:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/articles/identity/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Have you ever thought about your identity on the internet? How does LinkedIn know it is you when you log in to LinkedIn? And when you allow LinkedIn to post to your Twitter, how does LinkedIn access your account and not your kindergarten teacher&amp;rsquo;s account?
This is a &amp;ldquo;Mischa Explains&amp;rdquo; article where I attempt to explain a concept in my own words as simply as possible. I use the Feynman technique and pretend to explain it to a 12-year-old.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="introduction">Introduction</h1>
<p>Have you ever thought about your identity on the internet? How does LinkedIn know it is you when you log in to LinkedIn? And when you allow LinkedIn to post to your Twitter, how does LinkedIn access your account and not your kindergarten teacher&rsquo;s account?</p>
<p>This is a &ldquo;Mischa Explains&rdquo; article where I attempt to explain a concept in my own words as simply as possible. I use the Feynman technique and pretend to explain it to a 12-year-old.</p>
<h1 id="identity">Identity</h1>
<p>The first step in this process is identity. You need a starting point; for many of us, this can be our Google account. You signed up for this account and probably verified this with your phone number.</p>
<p>This relates to <strong>authentication</strong>. Authentication is the process of verifying identity. You&rsquo;ll need to provide the correct password when you log in to your Google account. You must give a valid password to log in to your account and access the resources. Google uses your password to <strong>authenticate</strong> that it is you.</p>
<h1 id="authorization">Authorization</h1>
<p>Then we have <strong>authorization</strong>. Authorization means granting access to particular resources. For example, let&rsquo;s say you are working in the science classroom at school. In the classroom is a bookcase that everybody can use: it is not dangerous, and every student can take the books they need without asking for permission. In the back of the science classroom is a cabinet that contains chemicals. It would be very dangerous if everybody could go into the cabinet and take out the sulphuric acid. Not everybody might know how dangerous sulphuric acid is. That&rsquo;s why the cabinet is locked.</p>
<p>If you need something from the chemicals cabinet, you need to ask permission from the teacher. You need to be <strong>authorized</strong> by the teacher to take out the sulphuric acid. When you make your request, the teacher may ask you questions to ensure you know what you are doing. He might even ask you for your school ID card because he has not seen you before. The teacher <strong>authenticates</strong> you by asking for your school ID, and then he <strong>authorizes</strong> you to take out the sulphuric acid.</p>
<h1 id="tokens">Tokens</h1>
<p>How do we accomplish this on the internet?</p>
<p>To verify identities on the internet, we have identity providers. Google is an identity provider. Azure AD is also an identity provider. An open-source identity provider is Keycloak.</p>
<p>Identity providers use <em>tokens</em> to verify identity and authorize access to resources. There are two types of tokens: ID tokens and access tokens. And for each token, there is an associated protocol.</p>
<h2 id="id-tokens">ID tokens</h2>
<p>OpenID Connect, also known as OIDC, is an open standard for authentication. Identity providers have agreed with each other that they will use this standard. When you go through an OpenID workflow, the result is an ID token, proving that the user has been authenticated.</p>
<p>Your school ID card is the ID token in our science class example. When you started at your school, you went through a registration process. Your parents probably handled this. Your name was written down, and the school verified that it was you by looking at your passport and talking to your parents. The result of this process was your school ID card, which you use to borrow books from the library. The school ID card proves that you are a student of that school and that you can use the facilities at the school.</p>
<h2 id="access-tokens">Access tokens</h2>
<p>These are specifically designed to allow access to a resource. For example, this resource could be a file on a server or a database.</p>
<p>Access tokens are strictly for authorization and use the OAuth 2.0 standard.</p>
<p>In our science class example, the token would be the key to the chemicals cabinet. The teacher authorizes you to access the cabinet and gives you the key to the cabinet.</p>
<h2 id="putting-it-together">Putting it Together</h2>
<p>Now let&rsquo;s put it together with an example.</p>
<p>You just created a new Facebook account and want to add all your friends. However, you have a Google account, and Facebook can use the contacts in your Google account to automatically add all of your friends.</p>
<p>Your Google account can only be accessed by you, and your contacts are locked away behind a password. But it is possible to grant Facebook access to this.</p>
<p>On Facebook, you select the &ldquo;import contacts from Google&rdquo; function. Facebook sends you to Google, and Google will ask you to log in. Google is the teacher in our science class example. Google needs you to <strong>authenticate</strong> to prove that it is you. When this is done, Google generates an ID token using OIDC for Facebook: Google gives Facebook a school ID that it can use.</p>
<p>Next, Facebook needs access to the contacts in your Google account. In our example, Facebook asks to take the sulphuric acid from the chemicals cabinet. You will see a menu that specifies what Facebook wants to do, and you need to give your permission. When you give your permission, Google generates an OAuth 2.0 token for Facebook. In other words, Google gives the key to the chemicals cabinet to Facebook, and Facebook is now authorized to take the sulphuric acid.</p>
<p>When both of these tokens are generated, Facebook contacts Google and asks if it can take the sulphuric acid from the chemicals cabinet.</p>
<p>Google, the teacher, asks Facebook for the school ID, and Facebook shows the ID card it received earlier. When Google is satisfied with the ID and successfully authenticates Facebook, it gives Facebook the key to the chemicals cabinet. Facebook is now authorized to take out the sulphuric acid. Facebook is now authorized to access the contacts in your Google account.</p>
<h1 id="links">Links</h1>
<p>You can use these resources to learn more about this topic:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=t18YB3xDfXI">An Illustrated Guide to OAuth and OpenID connect</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=M4JIvUIE17c">ID Tokens vs Access Tokens - Do you know the difference?</a></p>
<p><a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/active-directory/develop/id-tokens">Microsoft Learn: ID Tokens</a></p>
<p><a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/active-directory/develop/security-tokens">Microsoft Learn: Security Tokens</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
