<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Azure on Mischa&#39;s Blog &amp; Zettelkasten</title>
    <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/azure/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Azure on Mischa&#39;s Blog &amp; Zettelkasten</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 08:41:09 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/azure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Application Insights: Telemetry Sampling</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/application-insights-sampling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 08:41:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/application-insights-sampling/</guid>
      <description>Telemetry is the collection of measurements or other data at remote points, and transmitting that data to a receiver for monitoring.
Sampling is used to reduce telemetry traffic and costs for storage and data in Application Insights.
For small and medium sized applications sampling is generally not necessary.
Advantages of sampling:
Throttling data when the application suddenly sends a high volume of telemetry in a short time This saves costs! Keeping a pricing tier quota Reduce network traffic from telemetry collection Three different kinds of sampling:</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Telemetry is the collection of measurements or other data at remote points, and transmitting that data to a receiver for monitoring.</p>
<p>Sampling is used to reduce telemetry traffic and costs for storage and data in Application Insights.</p>
<p>For small and medium sized applications sampling is generally not necessary.</p>
<p>Advantages of sampling:</p>
<ul>
<li>Throttling data when the application suddenly sends a high volume of telemetry in a short time
<ul>
<li>This saves costs!</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Keeping a pricing tier quota</li>
<li>Reduce network traffic from telemetry collection</li>
</ul>
<p>Three different kinds of sampling:</p>
<ul>
<li>adaptive sampling
<ul>
<li>automatically adjusts volume of telemetry</li>
<li>from ASP.NET or Azure Functions</li>
<li>only for these two</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>fixed-rate sampling
<ul>
<li>rate is set by the administrator</li>
<li>use when you have a clear idea of the appropriate sampling percentage</li>
<li>reduces volume from
<ul>
<li>ASP.NET or ASP.NET Core server</li>
<li>Java server</li>
<li>Python applications</li>
<li>User browsers</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>ingestion sampling
<ul>
<li>used when monthly quota is often met</li>
<li>reduces amount of processed and retained traffic by Application Insights
<ul>
<li>less processing = less cost</li>
<li>doesn&rsquo;t reduce telemetry traffic sent from the app</li>
<li>happens at Applications Insight service endpoint</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>disabled if SDK samples telemetry</li>
<li>can set sampling rate without redeploying the app</li>
<li>only applies when no other sampling is in effect
<ul>
<li>supports all Application Insights SDK&rsquo;s</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pipelines: Continuous Monitoring</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/pipelines-continuous-monitoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 08:30:03 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/pipelines-continuous-monitoring/</guid>
      <description>This term can be confusing. Initially I thought it meant monitoring of the pipelines themselves. However, in the context of Azure Release Pipelines, continuous monitoring refers to something else.
Continuous monitoring leverages metrics from other services such as Application Insights. You can set up release gates based on these metrics. For example, you can set up a release gate to roll back the deployment if an alert is being fired for high CPU usage in the application.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This term can be confusing. Initially I thought it meant monitoring of the pipelines themselves. However, in the context of Azure Release Pipelines, continuous monitoring refers to something else.</p>
<p>Continuous monitoring leverages metrics from other services such as Application Insights. You can set up release gates based on these metrics. For example, you can set up a release gate to roll back the deployment if an alert is being fired for high CPU usage in the application.</p>
<p>You can set up several of these checks. If all these checks pass, the pipeline can proceed.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distributed Tracing</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/distributed-tracing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 07:58:44 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/distributed-tracing/</guid>
      <description>Debugging is done using call stacks in monolithic applications. Nowadays it is more common to deploy an application using a microservices architecture. Microservices make it easier to update certain parts of the application, and allow for more frequent deployments.
Using microservices does have a disadvantage: you cannot use the local call stack for debugging, because calls are sent to different microservices.
Distributed tracing is an implementation of the call stack in the cloud.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Debugging is done using <a href="/zet/call-stacks/">call stacks</a> in monolithic applications. Nowadays it is more common to deploy an application using a microservices architecture. Microservices make it easier to update certain parts of the application, and allow for more frequent deployments.</p>
<p>Using microservices does have a disadvantage: you cannot use the local call stack for debugging, because calls are sent to different microservices.</p>
<p>Distributed tracing is an implementation of the call stack in the cloud. It is usually implemented by adding an agent, <a href="/zet/sdk/">SDK</a>, or library to the service. In Azure you can enable distributed tracing via Application Insights through auto-instrumentation or SDKs.</p>
<p><a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/azure-monitor/app/transaction-diagnostics">Unified cross-component transaction diagnostics</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Study Guide: AZ-104 Azure Administrator Associate</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/articles/az-104-study-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/articles/az-104-study-guide/</guid>
      <description>TLDR It took me 80 hours of studying to gain this certification. Here are my notes and Anki deck: GitHub repo
Introduction When I did my English degree at University, exams were usually handwritten essays that needed to be done within a 3-hour timeframe. Sometimes we had multiple-choice tests, and I would always consider them a guaranteed pass because multiple-choice was much easier in my experience.
That opinion has changed since I&amp;rsquo;ve obtained a few IT certifications.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="tldr">TLDR</h1>
<p>It took me 80 hours of studying to gain this certification. Here are my notes and Anki deck:
<a href="https://github.com/mischavandenburg/az-104-azure-administrator">GitHub repo</a></p>
<h1 id="introduction">Introduction</h1>
<p>When I did my English degree at University, exams were usually handwritten essays that needed to be done within a 3-hour timeframe. Sometimes we had multiple-choice tests, and I would always consider them a guaranteed pass because multiple-choice was much easier in my experience.</p>
<p>That opinion has changed since I&rsquo;ve obtained a few IT certifications. These tests are hard! I&rsquo;m typing this while sitting on the bus on my way home from my AZ-104 exam. I passed with an 860 score of 1000, where 700 or higher is a pass. But it was an astonishingly tough exam. Usually, I finish quickly and spend at least half an hour reviewing my answers. I had only 5 minutes to review my questions this time because I had used up all of the available time. The questions required intense concentration and were time-consuming because I needed to compare many options which were very similar to each other. There were no easy questions.</p>
<h1 id="preparation">Preparation</h1>
<p>I studied 80 hours for this exam in a month. I work full-time as a DevOps Engineer, so I study in the evenings and on weekends. I have my Azure Fundamentals and CKA, but I only work with Azure occasionally in my current role.</p>
<p>Here is what I did to prepare for my exam:</p>
<ul>
<li>Go through all of the <a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/certifications/exams/az-104">Microsoft Learn modules for the AZ-104</a></li>
<li>Watch the entire <a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLlVtbbG169nGlGPWs9xaLKT1KfwqREHbs">AZ-104 study list by John Savill</a></li>
<li>Practice exams on <a href="https://tutorialsdojo.com/">TutorialsDojo</a> until I could pass them with 90%+ scores</li>
<li>Microsoft ESI practice exams</li>
<li><a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/shows/exam-readiness-zone/preparing-for-az-104-manage-azure-identities-and-governance-1-of-5">Microsoft AZ-104 Exam prep videos</a></li>
</ul>
<h2 id="microsoft-learn">Microsoft Learn</h2>
<p>You really need to master all of the subject matter. Only completing the Microsoft Learn modules is not enough preparation. They are more like summaries. At the end of each module, they provide links to the documentation for the subject for further study. Unfortunately, Microsoft does not go easy on you. It expects you to know obscure details of nearly every service this exam covers. Therefore, I advise going beyond the Microsoft Learn modules and studying the linked articles after each module.</p>
<h2 id="youtube-az-104-study-playlist-by-john-savill">YouTube AZ-104 Study Playlist by John Savill</h2>
<p>I&rsquo;m not sure if it&rsquo;s better to watch this playlist first and then do the Microsoft modules or the other way around. I did the Microsoft modules first, but for my next exam (AZ-400 DevOps Expert), I&rsquo;ll start with the videos and then do the Microsoft Learn modules.</p>
<h2 id="tutorialsdojo">Tutorialsdojo</h2>
<p>These practice exams are excellent. I used them in preparation for my fundamentals exam.</p>
<p>The best thing about them is that they provide extensive documentation and explanation of the questions. So after you finish the exam, you can study a lot with these examples.</p>
<h2 id="esi-practice-exams">ESI Practice Exams</h2>
<p>You&rsquo;re lucky if your organization participates in Microsoft&rsquo;s <a href="esi.microsoft.com/">Enterprise Skills Initiative</a>. The practice exams provided in the ESI environment give you a good indication of what you can expect at the exam. I first did the Tutorialsdojo exams and then moved on to the ESI exams, and I was humiliated. The ESI questions are very complex and hard to solve, and I learned a lot from these exams.</p>
<p>There are 210 questions total, and I worked through all of them, and whenever I failed a question, I did a deeper dive into the question&rsquo;s theme.</p>
<h1 id="studying">studying</h1>
<p>I take notes in Obsidian, and I use Anki for spaced repetition. I highly recommend keeping a deck of Anki cards and continuously testing yourself. You will need to memorize a lot of details. For example, you are expected to remember that storage accounts of the FileStorage type do not support Geo Redundant Storage. You can find my Anki deck in the <a href="https://github.com/mischavandenburg/az-104-azure-administrator">GitHub repo.</a></p>
<h1 id="links">links</h1>
<p><a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/certifications/exams/az-104">AZ-104 Exam page with learning modules</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLlVtbbG169nGlGPWs9xaLKT1KfwqREHbs">John Savill&rsquo;s AZ-104 Study playlist</a></p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/mischavandenburg/az-104-azure-administrator">GitHub repo containing my notes and Anki deck</a></p>
<p><a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/shows/exam-readiness-zone/preparing-for-az-104-manage-azure-identities-and-governance-1-of-5">Microsoft AZ-104 Exam prep videos</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
