<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Book-Notes on Mischa van den Burg</title>
    <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/book-notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book-Notes on Mischa van den Burg</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/book-notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A List Of All The Books I Have Read In My Life</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/books-i-have-read/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/books-i-have-read/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m an avid reader, and this list is far from complete. But I wanted to start writing down the ones I&amp;rsquo;m reading now, and the ones I&amp;rsquo;ve read in the past. I&amp;rsquo;m mostly writing down titles but I&amp;rsquo;ll include the author when I remember the name.
2024 How To Take Smart Notes
Getting Things Done
2023 The Lords of the North
The Pale Horseman
The Last Kingdom
Born to Run 2</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m an avid reader, and this list is far from complete. But I wanted to start writing down the ones I&rsquo;m reading now, and the ones I&rsquo;ve read in the past. I&rsquo;m mostly writing down titles but I&rsquo;ll include the author when I remember the name.</p>
<h1 id="2024">2024</h1>
<p>How To Take Smart Notes</p>
<p>Getting Things Done</p>
<h1 id="2023">2023</h1>
<p>The Lords of the North</p>
<p>The Pale Horseman</p>
<p>The Last Kingdom</p>
<p>Born to Run 2</p>
<p>Born to Run</p>
<p>Four Thousand Weeks</p>
<p>The Plantpower Way - Rich Roll</p>
<p><a href="/zet/book-notes-eat-and-run/">Eat and Run - Scott Jurek</a></p>
<p><a href="/zet/book-notes-finding-ultra-rich-roll/">Finding Ultra - Rich Roll</a></p>
<p><a href="/zet/book-notes-simple-path-to-wealth/">A Simple Path to Wealth</a></p>
<p>The Richest Man in Babylon</p>
<p>Can&rsquo;t Hurt Me</p>
<p>How to Win Friends and Influence People</p>
<p>The Subtle Art of Not Giving A F*ck</p>
<p>Never Split the Difference</p>
<p><a href="/zet/articles/ikigai-book/">Ikigai</a></p>
<p>Building A Second Brain</p>
<p>On Writing Well</p>
<p>Fat Loss Forever - Layne Norton</p>
<p><a href="/zet/articles/unicorn-project/">The Unicorn Project</a></p>
<p>The Clean Coder</p>
<p>Get A Financial Life</p>
<p>Your Money or Your Life</p>
<h1 id="earlier">Earlier</h1>
<p>Moby Dick</p>
<p>The Lord of the Rings</p>
<p>The Wim Hof Method</p>
<p>The Way of Qigong</p>
<p>The Oxygen Advantage</p>
<p>Remember It</p>
<p>Pride and Prejudice</p>
<p>White Noise</p>
<p>The Road</p>
<p>The Reluctant Fundamentalist</p>
<p>The Last Kingdom series</p>
<p>War and Peace</p>
<p>Anna Karenina</p>
<p>Dictator</p>
<p>Imperium</p>
<p>Lustrum</p>
<p>4 Hour Workweek</p>
<p>Uncommon Wisdom</p>
<p>Stillness Flowing</p>
<p>Seeking Buddho</p>
<p>What Doesn&rsquo;t Kill Us</p>
<p>The Art Of Happiness</p>
<p>Into the Wild</p>
<p>Alone in the Wilderness</p>
<p>Call of the Wild</p>
<p>White Fang</p>
<p>Name of the Wind</p>
<p>Wise Man&rsquo;s Fear</p>
<p>Slow Regard of Silent Things</p>
<p>Bigger Leaner Stronger series</p>
<p>As I Lay Dying</p>
<p>The Canterbury Tales</p>
<p>Beowulf</p>
<p>Swedish Carving Techniques</p>
<p>Drawing Nature for the Absolute Beginner</p>
<p>Old Souls</p>
<p>Thus Spake Zarathustra</p>
<p>Opening the Door of Your Heart</p>
<p>The Kreutzer Sonata</p>
<p>The Hunger Fix</p>
<p>Fire First Law Trilogy</p>
<p>The Starch Solution</p>
<p>Ultimate Guide to Chinese Tea</p>
<p>The Way to Love</p>
<p>Moonwalking with Einstein</p>
<p>The Prose Edda</p>
<p>How to Draw what you See</p>
<p>Untethered Soul</p>
<p>How to Practice</p>
<p>Intuitive Awareness - Ajahn Sumedho</p>
<p>Awareness - Tony DeMello</p>
<p>Way of Power - Master Lam</p>
<p>The Way of Energy - Master Lam</p>
<p>The Noble Eightfold Path - Bikkhu Bodhi</p>
<p>Wisdom Develops Samadhi</p>
<p>The Collected Teachings of Ajahn Chah 1, 2, 3</p>
<p>Forest Desanas</p>
<p>Forest Dhamma</p>
<p>Mae Chee Kaew</p>
<p>Samana</p>
<p>The Way it Is</p>
<p>Art of Memory</p>
<p>Xu Yun</p>
<p>Bartleby: The Scrivener</p>
<p>Walden</p>
<p>How to Take Smart Notes</p>
<p>Steal Like an Artist</p>
<p>Can&rsquo;t Hurt Me</p>
<p>Hitchhiker&rsquo;s Guide to the Galaxy</p>
<p>Arthurian Literature</p>
<p>Mallory</p>
<p>Don Quichote</p>
<p>Starting Strength</p>
<p>Practical Programming</p>
<p>The Hidden Life of Trees</p>
<p>The Bullet Journal Method</p>
<p>Thinking Fast and Slow</p>
<p>Angela&rsquo;s Ashes</p>
<p>Great Expectations - Dickens</p>
<p>Hard Times - Dickens</p>
<p>Othello</p>
<p>King Lear</p>
<p>Broodje Gezond</p>
<p>Paradise - Toni Morrison</p>
<p>Watchmen</p>
<p>Heart of Darkness</p>
<p>Christianity - Chidester</p>
<p>In het Huis van de Islam</p>
<p>A Short History of Nearly Everything</p>
<p>The Surprising Purpose of Anger</p>
<p>Nonviolent Communication</p>
<p>The Hobbit</p>
<p>Mythology</p>
<p>The Iliad</p>
<p>In the Buddha&rsquo;s Words - Bhikkhu Bodhi</p>
<p>The Word of the Buddha - Nyanatiloka</p>
<p>The Dhammapada</p>
<p>Dependent Origination</p>
<p>Xu Yun: Dharma Words</p>
<p><a href="/zet/articles/phoenix-project/">The Phoenix Project</a></p>
<p>Why We Sleep</p>
<p>How to remember your Dreams</p>
<p>Solomon&rsquo;s Memory Palace</p>
<p>The Complete Guide to Fasting</p>
<p>Direct Realization - Ajahn Sumedho</p>
<p>Peace is a Simple Step - Ajahn Sumedho</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202307062007</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Notes: Ikigai: The Japanese Secret to a Long and Happy Life</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/articles/ikigai-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/articles/ikigai-book/</guid>
      <description>I came across this little book while doing some research for my Jiro Dreams of Sushi article. While scanning the book&amp;rsquo;s description, I was intrigued by this sentence: &amp;ldquo;the happiness of always being busy.&amp;rdquo; Although I work hard every day, I also enjoy ticking off the last item on my to-do list and enjoying some rest. Is there more happiness in being in constant activity?
Ikigai &amp;ldquo;He who has a why to live for can bear with almost any how.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I came across this little book while doing some research for my <a href="/zet/articles/jiro-sushi">Jiro Dreams of Sushi article.</a> While scanning the book&rsquo;s description, I was intrigued by this sentence: &ldquo;the happiness of always being busy.&rdquo; Although I work hard every day, I also enjoy ticking off the last item on my to-do list and enjoying some rest. Is there more happiness in being in constant activity?</p>
<h2 id="ikigai">Ikigai</h2>
<blockquote>
<hr>
<p>&ldquo;He who has a why to live for can bear with almost any how.&rdquo;</p>
<ul>
<li>Friedrich Nietzsche</li>
</ul>
<hr>
</blockquote>
<p>According to Japanese culture, everybody has a purpose in life: the ikigai. &ldquo;Ikigai is the reason we get up in the morning.&rdquo; The book explores this concept through interesting stories and brings related notions from various areas to explain ikigai to the Western mind.</p>
<p>There are many different ikigai, and people can have several ikigai simultaneously. For example, some people have their vegetable garden as their ikigai, while others have drawing or calligraphy. <a href="/zet/articles/jiro-sushi">Jiro</a> has making sushi as his ikigai. Even though many people have their work as their ikigai, it does not necessarily have to be the case. Ikigai can also be of a social nature, such as a family or local community.</p>
<p>
  <img loading="lazy" src="https://external-content.duckduckgo.com/iu/?u=https%3A%2F%2F3nw94z2pgadc432nw33p8qg5-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com%2Fwp-content%2Fuploads%2F2018%2F01%2Fwhat-is-ikigai-darling.png&amp;f=1&amp;nofb=1&amp;ipt=f5fa9a17a2865d283af2bfdf8d978f1dcb0e9ff4e7fb646fb2c26c4963f95e77&amp;ipo=images" alt=""  /></p>
<h2 id="retirement">Retirement</h2>
<p>When I watched Jiro Dreams of Sushi for the first time, I was surprised that Jiro still worked at his restaurant every day at age 85. This book explores that further.</p>
<p>Apparently, many people never really retire in Japan. The concept of retirement, as we know it in the West, does not exist in the Japanese language: there is &ldquo;no word in Japanese that means retire in the sense of &ldquo;leaving the workforce for good&rdquo; as in English.&rdquo; People continue doing what they like doing as long as their health allows. They keep following their ikigai.</p>
<p>This concept was very refreshing to me and had a profound influence on how I imagine my own future. After becoming more intentional about my career, I became interested in <a href="https://www.investopedia.com/terms/f/financial-independence-retire-early-fire.asp">FIRE</a> and the possibility of retiring early. However, as I contemplated this strategy, I discovered that I didn&rsquo;t want to stop working because I really enjoy my work.</p>
<p>Why would I want to retire if I&rsquo;m doing what I love? That was the whole point of switching my career to IT, and this is where Western culture can learn a lot from Japanese culture. In Japanese culture, there is more emphasis on aligning your career with your interests and continuing that passion well into old age.</p>
<blockquote>
<hr>
<p>When to quit? The job you have worked so hard for? I never once hated my job. I fell in love with my work and gave my life to it. Even though I&rsquo;m 85 years old, I don&rsquo;t feel like retiring.</p>
<ul>
<li>Jiro</li>
</ul>
<hr>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="longevity">Longevity</h2>
<p>A large part of the book is about the residents of Okinawa: the island with the highest number of people 100 years old or older. The authors tell the story of their visit to the island to reveal the secret of the Okinawan&rsquo;s long lives. It is not uncommon to see people working in the fields who are well into their eighties. The Okinawans freely share their secrets with us, and the authors do a great job translating the Japanese principles into actionable advice.</p>
<p>Much of the advice is centered around dietary habits. Not only what to eat, but also how to eat it: &ldquo;Okinawans stop eating when they feel their stomachs reach 80 percent of their capacity, rather than overeating&rdquo;, a practice which is named &ldquo;hara haci bu.&rdquo; They consume a daily average of 1800 to 1900 calories, a significant difference from the 2200 to 3300 calories consumed by an average person in the US every day.</p>
<p>Another theme that keeps returning is the crucial function of social groups for finding meaning in life, especially in old age: &ldquo;It is customary in Okinawa to form close bonds within local communities. A moai is an informal group of people with common interests who look out for one another. For many, serving the community becomes part of their ikigai.&rdquo;</p>
<p>This book may be a good resource if you are interested in longevity. Even though I only expected to read about the ikigai concept, it contains a surprisingly large amount of valuable advice and practical tips to live a longer and happier life.</p>
<h2 id="chock-full">Chock-full</h2>
<p>&ldquo;Ikigai: The Japanese Secret to a Long and Happy Life&rdquo; is a small book that covers an astonishing amount of subjects. It covers topics such as meditation, flow states, and exercise methods such as Tai Chi and Qi Gong. The disadvantage is that it does not deeply cover any of these topics. But I think this book can be a very useful springboard for further research and a great introduction to many different subjects that can improve your life.</p>
<p>It is a short read, but it contains a lot of wisdom, and I learned much from this book. It has changed the way I think of retirement and the way I approach my work. I am also very interested in health and longevity. Through the conversations with the centenarians of Okinawa, I received a lot of helpful tips, which I&rsquo;m already applying to my daily life.</p>
<p>Have I discovered the art of being busy? I believe I took this definition too literally when I started reading this book. I found that Okinawans lead active lives full of meaning but also take plenty of rest. Always being busy does not mean that you have to work yourself to death. However, it does mean that the secret to reaching a healthy old age is to keep doing what you love. There is no need to become sedentary and only sit in front of the TV when you turn 67. I think Western culture has a lot to learn in this area.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Notes: The Unicorn Project</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/articles/unicorn-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/articles/unicorn-project/</guid>
      <description>This book is the sequel to the Phoenix project. Both books are set at Parts Unlimited, a fictitious company that supplies car parts to DIY mechanics and repair shops. Phoenix is a new system that Parts Unlimited has worked on for multiple years. It is supposed to handle order processing and communication between manufacturing, stores, and clients. Phoenix will also play a role in sales and marketing. The company has been gathering customer data for years, but it cannot use any of this data yet.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>
  <img loading="lazy" src="https://m.media-amazon.com/images/W/IMAGERENDERING_521856-T1/images/I/91UM5i4nirL.jpg" alt="Unicorn Project"  /></p>
<p>This book is the sequel to <a href="/zet/articles/phoenix-project">the Phoenix project</a>. Both books are set at Parts Unlimited, a fictitious company that supplies car parts to DIY mechanics and repair shops. Phoenix is a new system that Parts Unlimited has worked on for multiple years. It is supposed to handle order processing and communication between manufacturing, stores, and clients. Phoenix will also play a role in sales and marketing. The company has been gathering customer data for years, but it cannot use any of this data yet. Phoenix will enable it to generate targeted marketing campaigns from the data when it&rsquo;s finished.</p>
<p>But as we saw in the previous book, it is far from finished, and things go wrong all the time. The company is not doing well, the stock prices are falling, and they need an edge over the competition. Phoenix will be their edge, but they&rsquo;ve been working on it for years. Eventually, management decided that Phoenix needed to be deployed in two weeks. But it is far from ready.</p>
<p>The main character in the Unicorn project is Maxine, a senior developer who temporarily transferred to a different department. She had to work on the Phoenix project against her will because of an unfortunate situation that needed a scapegoat. However, Maxine decides to make the best out of it, and she&rsquo;d like to begin with one thing: to get a Phoenix build going on her laptop.</p>
<p>Very quickly, she finds it impossible to run a full build of the Phoenix project due to missing files and other elements. She is appalled and makes it her mission to get the build going, but she meets another hurdle every step of the way. Missing credentials. Missing binaries and libraries. And for each of these hurdles, she must submit a ticket with a different department. Very soon, she has over 20 tickets running with long waiting times. Just to get a build going on her machine so she can work! Dozens of developers were hired to work on the Phoenix project. But when she asks them if they&rsquo;ve managed to get a build going yet, Maxine is horrified to discover that they&rsquo;ve tried for several months but haven&rsquo;t made any progress. Maxine has made more progress in a week.</p>
<blockquote>
<hr>
<p>&ldquo;Everyone around here thinks features are important because they can see them in their app, on the web page, or in the API. But no one seems to realize how important the build process is. Developers cannot be productive without a great build, integration, and test process.&rdquo;</p>
<ul>
<li>Unicorn Project</li>
</ul>
<hr>
</blockquote>
<p>After a few weeks, Maxine receives an invitation to have a drink with a group of people who are very interested in her. When she arrives at the bar, she meets the Rebellion: a group of developers, managers, and people from Operations, who are tired of the old organizational structure and want to make real changes. They think out of the box and experiment with new technologies, even though they are not authorized to do so.</p>
<p>With the Rebellion, Maxine significantly improves the build and deployment process. They recognized that Phoenix actually never was being built in its entirety. Developers were always working on parts of the application. However, after a lot of struggle, they create a build process that enables each developer to become operational on his first day.</p>
<p>This is the first step of a long series of exciting events that lead to Phoenix becoming a success. By the end of the book, they have a completely new development and testing process, and they can deploy changes to production without needing to take the entire application down. This allows them to create targeted marketing campaigns and respond to changes in the market. The first campaign was a huge success and generated the highest sales ever.</p>
<p>Maxine&rsquo;s struggle with the build process was an eye-opening experience for me. It gave me a very practical example of the need for DevOps principles to enable delivering value to customers. It is also something I recognize in my current organization. For example, projects can get stuck on a firewall change that needs to be approved by an external party. By implementing DevOps principles and arranging teams according to the &ldquo;you build it, you run it&rdquo; principle, teams can be responsible for the entire process from idea to production and therefore have a very short release cycle for their application.</p>
<p>I thoroughly enjoyed the first part of the book. However, the second part was less engaging to me. It became long-winded and felt like butter spread over too much bread. The author demonstrates a high level of technical experience and knowledge through his descriptions of processes, deployments, and fictional applications. Although I understand the intention of making Parts Unlimited a believable company, I think it could have been accomplished with much less detail and words.</p>
<p>The second part has more corporate drama, such as temporarily suspended managers without any clear reason. The focus shifts from a development and operations perspective to a managerial perspective. Maybe I will reread the book in a few years and this part will make a lot more sense to me then. The same happened when I reread the Phoenix project. I could not understand some aspects of the book, which became much clearer to me when I revisited it after gaining experience in the field.</p>
<p>I highly recommend this book to anyone working as a developer, DevOps Engineer, or in operations, especially if you are starting your career. The book gave me a lot of insights into &ldquo;the old way of working&rdquo; and a better understanding of the need for DevOps principles in the modern IT landscape. However, make sure to read the Phoenix project first.</p>
<h2 id="the-unicorn-project-a-novel-about-developers-digital-disruption-and-thriving-in-the-age-of-data-by-gene-kim">The Unicorn Project: A Novel about Developers, Digital Disruption, and Thriving in the Age of Data by Gene Kim</h2>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Notes: The Phoenix Project</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/articles/phoenix-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/articles/phoenix-project/</guid>
      <description>When I started my DevOps traineeship, I borrowed this book from my boss and read it from cover to cover. I loved the story and the characters; it helped me understand &amp;ldquo;the old way&amp;rdquo; of doing things and the merits of implementing DevOps principles.
I reread the book ten months later. In the meantime, I&amp;rsquo;ve learned many new skills and technologies and started working full-time as a DevOps engineer.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>
  <img loading="lazy" src="https://m.media-amazon.com/images/W/IMAGERENDERING_521856-T1/images/I/914-sUgELZL.jpg" alt="Phoenix Project"  /></p>
<p>When I started my DevOps traineeship, I borrowed this book from my boss and read it from cover to cover. I loved the story and the characters; it helped me understand &ldquo;the old way&rdquo; of doing things and the merits of implementing DevOps principles.</p>
<p>I reread the book ten months later. In the meantime, I&rsquo;ve learned many new skills and technologies and started working full-time as a DevOps engineer.</p>
<p>Not surprisingly, it made a lot more sense to me this time, and I&rsquo;m sure it will be even better when I reread it a few years later. In this article, I&rsquo;ll share my thoughts and notes on the book.</p>
<h2 id="the-story">The Story</h2>
<p>The main character is Bill Palmer, a mid-level IT manager in a manufacturing company called Parts Unlimited. Within a few pages, he is called into the CEO&rsquo;s office, and he is promoted to the VP of Operations, putting him in charge of IT, much against his own will or desire.</p>
<p>The situation Bill enters is a humorously chaotic one. We are thrown straight into a Sev 1 incident where managers point fingers and shout at each other. We quickly get the impression that this is a dysfunctional department that only performs tasks for the manager who shouts the loudest while fighting off crippling outages.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>It’s like the Wild West out here. We’re mostly shooting from the hip.”<br>
<em>The Phoenix Project</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>The bulk of the story revolves around how Bill, together with his team of managers, Wes, Patty, and John, manage to turn this chaos into a department that does work according to a streamlined plan in a much more predictable manner.</p>
<p>To achieve this goal, Bill is introduced to Erik, a prospective board member of the company. Erik becomes Bill&rsquo;s mentor and guides Bill through the process of creating order in the chaos. Their interaction reminds me of Zen masters training their disciples by asking deep questions which don&rsquo;t have an immediately apparent answer.</p>
<h2 id="master--disciple">Master &amp; Disciple</h2>
<p>Erik takes Bill to the manufacturing plant of Parts Unlimited and tries to impress upon Bill that manufacturing planning principles from Lean can be applied to IT work. Erik argues that an IT department could be structured like a factory production line, but Bill is not ready to accept this.</p>
<p>A fundamental notion from manufacturing principles is that work should always be moving forwards along the production line, never backward. But unfortunately, this is very often the case in the &ldquo;old&rdquo; way of working: the development team works on an application for several months, and when they are finished with it, they throw it over the fence to the Operations people, whose job it is to deploy the application.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>One of the developers had actually walked in a couple of minutes ago and said, “Look, it’s running on my laptop. How hard can it be?”<br>
<em>The Phoenix Project</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>However, as we see happening time after time in the book, usually the application is incompatible with the infrastructure it is deployed to. As a result, the application needs to go back to development. According to manufacturing theory, this is a situation where work goes backward through the production line, which we must avoid at all costs.</p>
<h2 id="implementation">Implementation</h2>
<p>Erik challenges Bill to start doing ten deployments a day instead of one deployment every nine months. Understandably, this is a ridiculous notion to Bill. The last few deployments were disastrous events that required his entire department to pull all-nighters through the weekend, and still, the stores were not managing to process all orders and payments.</p>
<p>However, Bill takes his mentor&rsquo;s advice and figures out a way to do it together with his team. One of the main problems they uncovered was the inconsistent deployment and production environments.</p>
<p>The solution to this problem was to involve the operations people in the development stage right from the beginning, so the development environment matched the production environment exactly. The environments were standardized and put in code with version control, and things started progressing quickly.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>As Wes talks, I think about Erik challenging me to think like a plant manager as opposed to a work center supervisor. I suddenly realize that he probably meant that I needed to span the departmental boundaries of Development and IT Operations.
<em>The Phoenix Project</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is just one of the problems addressed by melting away the fence between Development and Operations. By the end of the book, the two camps started to work together much better. They come closer to the target of 10 deployments a day, and the DevOps way of working was born.</p>
<h2 id="closing-thoughts">Closing Thoughts</h2>
<p>I think this book is a must-read for anyone considering entering the DevOps field or anyone already working with DevOps.</p>
<p>As a nerd who loves structure and organization, the theme of the story is incredibly entertaining and satisfying to me. The authors excellently capture the transition from an utterly disorganized situation to a predictable environment with happy co-workers. Actually, I&rsquo;m a little embarrassed by how much joy this transition brings me.</p>
<p>Especially the second time around, it helped me better understand the underlying principles that enable the DevOps way of working in an organization. Moreover, it paints a great picture of how an organization can change for the better by embracing DevOps principles and how these changes express themselves in the improved quality and speed of software development and deployment. All of these advantages lead to delivering better value to the customer, which is the core focus of any productive and creative endeavor involving customers and end users.</p>
<h2 id="the-phoenix-project-written-by-gene-kim-kevin-behr-george-spafford">The Phoenix Project, written by Gene Kim, Kevin Behr, George Spafford</h2>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
