<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Book-notes on Mischa van den Burg</title>
    <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/book-notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book-notes on Mischa van den Burg</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/book-notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Longevity Diet - Prof. Valter Longo</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/longevity-diet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/longevity-diet/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading The Longevity Diet by professor Valter Longo after encountering him in several podcasts.
I&amp;rsquo;m always experimenting with diet protols and this one seems interesting because its plant based but has an eating pattern that is very different from what I&amp;rsquo;m used to. I&amp;rsquo;ve been intermittent fasting for over 8 years and my eating windows have varied from 1 to 10 hours, usually skipping breakfast. However, based on his research, professor Longo recommends not skipping breakfast and skipping lunch instead.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve been reading The Longevity Diet by professor Valter Longo after encountering him in several podcasts.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m always experimenting with diet protols and this one seems interesting because its plant based but has an eating pattern that is very different from what I&rsquo;m used to. I&rsquo;ve been intermittent fasting for over 8 years and my eating windows have varied from 1 to 10 hours, usually skipping breakfast. However, based on his research, professor Longo recommends not skipping breakfast and skipping lunch instead.</p>
<p>Based on his research on centenarians he recommends eating a pescetarian diet with two small servings of high quality fish a week. I don&rsquo;t like seafood however, the thought of eating something that has been swimming around in our polluted seas absorbing heavy metals repulses me. I will have to see if I can find high quality fish. Soon I will be doing a blood test with Inside Tracker to see how my levels of nutrients are. If everything looks good I will probably wait with including fish into my diet. However, if it extends my lifespan and improves my health and well being I am willing to start eating a pescetarian diet.</p>
<p>Additionally, professor Longo recommends doing a 5 day fast at leat twice a year where you consume about 800 calories a day, which he calls a Fasting Mimicking Diet.</p>
<p>My main takeaways which I&rsquo;m implementing now:</p>
<ul>
<li>Start eating two meals a day, breakfast and dinner plus a 100 calorie snack</li>
<li>12 hour eating window</li>
<li>Do a 5 day fast 4 times a year</li>
<li>Consider eating fish twice a week, start looking for high quality sources</li>
<li>Research what my ancestors ate and select main ingredients accordingly</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="the-longevity-diet-for-adults">The Longevity Diet for Adults</h1>
<ol>
<li>Eat mostly vegan, plus a little fish, limiting meals with fish to a maximum of two or three per week. Choose fish, crustaceans, and mollusks with a high omega-3, omega-6, and vitamin B12 content (salmon, anchovies, sardines, cod, sea bream, trout, clams, shrimp.  Pay attention to the quality of the fish, choosing those with low levels of mercury.</li>
<li>If you are below the age of 65, keep protein intake low (0.31 to 0.36 grams per pound of body weight). That comes to 40 to 47 grams of proteins per day for a person weighing 130 pounds, and 60 to 70 grams of protein per day for someone weighing 200 to 220 pounds. (100kg) Over age 65, you should slightly increase protein intake but also increase consumption of fish, eggs, white meat, and products derived from goats and sheep to preserve muscle mass. Consume beans, chickpeas, green peas, and other legumes as your main source of protein.</li>
<li>Minimize saturated fats from animal and vegetable sources (meat, cheese) and sugar, and maximize good fats and complex carbs. Eat whole grains and high quantities of vegetables (tomatoes, broccoli, carrots, legumes, etc.) with generous amounts of olive oil (3 tablespoons per day) and nuts (1 ounce per day). (30g)</li>
<li>Follow a diet with high vitamin and mineral content, supplemented with a multivitamin buffer every three days.</li>
<li>Select ingredients among those discussed in this book that your ancestors would have eaten.</li>
<li>Based on your weight, age, and abdominal circumference, decide whether to have two or three meals per day. If you are overweight or tend to gain weight easily, consume two meals a day: breakfast and either lunch or dinner, plus two low-sugar (less than 5 grams) snacks with fewer than 100 calories each. If you are already at a normal weight, or if you tend to lose weight easily or are over 65 and of normal weight, eat three meals a day and one low-sugar (less than 3 to 5 grams) snack with fewer than 100 calories.</li>
<li>Confine all eating to within a twelve-hour period; for example, start after 8 a.m. and end before 8 p.m. Don’t eat anything within three to four hours of bedtime.</li>
</ol>
<p><a href="https://www.valterlongo.com/daily-longevity-diet-for-adults/">https://www.valterlongo.com/daily-longevity-diet-for-adults/</a></p>
<h2 id="do-not-skip-breakfast">Do not skip breakfast</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>For people trying to lose weight or those who tend to be heavy, the best nutritional advice is to eat breakfast daily; have lunch or dinner, but not both; and substitute for the missed meal one snack containing fewer than 100 calories and no more than 3 to 5 grams of sugar. (Do not skip breakfast, as this has been associated with increased risk for age-related diseases in multiple studies.)</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="the-recipe-for-a-long-life">The Recipe for a long life</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Areas of the world known to have the highest prevalence of centenarians—Okinawa, Japan; Loma Linda, California; small towns in Calabria and Sardinia, Italy; and in Costa Rica and Greece—all share diets that are (1) mostly plant-based with lots of nuts and some fish; (2) low in proteins, sugars, and saturated/trans fats; and (3) high in complex carbohydrates coming from beans and other plant-based foods. Most of these centenarians ate only two or three times a day, ate light meals in the evening, and were in many cases done eating before dark.</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="eat-low-protein-until-70-then-increase-with-20">Eat low protein until 70, then increase with 20%</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>In other words, maintaining a high-vegetable, low-protein diet for the first seventy or eighty years of life, and later switching to a diet richer in proteins but also animal-based foods like eggs, chicken, milk, and certain cheeses, may have slowed down aging and optimized the health of the Molochio centenarians. This explanation fits with our discovery that low-protein intake is associated with extended longevity and a major reduction in cancer in people age sixty-five and younger, but not in those above sixty-six.</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="prolonged-caloric-restriction-is-not-beneficial-for-health">Prolonged caloric restriction is not beneficial for health</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>So, on the one hand we know that chronic caloric restriction can have profoundly beneficial effects on risk factors for many diseases. On the other hand, we know that chronic and extreme diets—diets that reduce calories by 20 percent or more and are maintained for long periods or permanently—can negatively affect necessary processes, including wound healing, immune response, and cold-temperature tolerance. Put simply, besides making a person extremely thin, the detrimental effects of chronic calorie restriction appear to minimize its benefits by causing a major increase in other types of diseases and conditions that are less well understood. The focus of the rest of this book is on how to obtain the remarkable beneficial effects of calorie restriction without the negative ones.</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="epidemiology-low-protein-high-carb-plant-based-diets-are-healthiest">Epidemiology: low protein high carb plant based diets are healthiest</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Most large-population studies show an association between longevity and disease prevention, and a diet that is low in protein; largely plant- and fish-based; and rich in complex carbohydrates, olive oil, and nuts. For example, our epidemiological study of six thousand Americans suggested that consuming a high-protein diet is associated with increased levels of the pro-aging growth factor IGF-1 (see fig. 4.3), a 75 percent increased risk of overall mortality, and a three- to fourfold increased risk in cancer mortality compared with consuming the low-protein and plant-based diet recommended here (see fig. 4.4).12 Contrary to the findings of T. Colin Campbell in The China Study, which advocates consuming low levels of plant-based proteins throughout life, the beneficial effect of a low-protein diet seems to apply only before age sixty-five (fig. 4.3). A Harvard study of nearly 130,000 doctors and nurses also indicates that a low-carb diet high in animal fat and protein is associated with increases in overall cancer and cardiovascular disease mortality, a finding that is in agreement with our research.13 In line with our previous protein study, a follow-up study of the same group followed by Harvard University, in which I acted as a co-author, showed that consumption of high levels of animal but not plant-based proteins was associated with increased mortality from cardiovascular disease.14 A similar study of forty thousand men suggests that a low-carb, high-animal-protein diet is associated with a twofold increase in diabetes, a finding also consistent with our discovery in the six-thousand-person protein study.15 A number of other epidemiological studies consistently associate high IGF-1 levels in the bloodstream with an increase of twofold or more in the incidence of breast, prostate, and other cancer types.16 Because we know that protein consumption is the key regulator of IGF-1 levels and that animal-protein intake is usually associated with intake of saturated animal fats, these studies bolster the case for a link between cancer, diabetes, and high protein and saturated fat intake.Epidemiological studies also support the key role of nourishment in disease prevention, since populations with deficiencies in certain vitamins have been shown to have an increased incidence for a variety of diseases. For example, vitamin D deficiency has been associated with an increased risk for diabetes and autoimmune and cardiovascular diseases.17</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202309300809</p>
<p><a href="https://www.menshealth.com/nutrition/a19513749/rich-roll-vegan-diet/">https://www.menshealth.com/nutrition/a19513749/rich-roll-vegan-diet/</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.valterlongo.com/daily-longevity-diet-for-adults/">https://www.valterlongo.com/daily-longevity-diet-for-adults/</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Notes - Eat and Run by Scott Jurek</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/book-notes-eat-and-run/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/book-notes-eat-and-run/</guid>
      <description>We had trails and the fresh air and a little water and food and our fit bodies to move through and with the land. That was all we needed. Seeing Kyle and Tony so happy reminded me that that was all I ever needed, all any of us needed. How had I drifted away from those simple joys? I wanted to regain the purity and gratitude that Kyle and Tony seemed to hold so effortlessly, so lightly.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>We had trails and the fresh air and a little water and food and our fit bodies to move through and with the land. That was all we needed. Seeing Kyle and Tony so happy reminded me that that was all I ever needed, all any of us needed. How had I drifted away from those simple joys? I wanted to regain the purity and gratitude that Kyle and Tony seemed to hold so effortlessly, so lightly.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>I ran, and kept running, because I had learned that once you started something you didn’t quit, because in life, much like in an ultramarathon, you have to keep pressing forward. Eventually I ran because I turned into a runner, and my sport brought me physical pleasure and spirited me away from debt and disease, from the niggling worries of everyday existence. I ran because I grew to love other runners. I ran because I loved challenges and because there is no better feeling than arriving at the finish line or completing a difficult training run. And because, as an accomplished runner, I could tell others how rewarding it was to live healthily, to move my body every day, to get through difficulties, to eat with consciousness, that what mattered wasn’t how much money you made or where you lived, it was how you lived. I ran because overcoming the difficulties of an ultramarathon reminded me that I could overcome the difficulties of life, that overcoming difficulties was life. Could I quit and not be a quitter? “You’ve done it before,” Rick said. “You can do it again.” I appreciated the optimism. I also appreciated its idiocy.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Rarely do you come across a book that is grippingly entertainin, highly informative and potentially lifechanging at the same time.</p>
<p>I picked it up because of my increased interest in running. I&rsquo;ve also started to become a bit fascinated with marathon and ultra running, hoping to seek my own limits in these sports one day.</p>
<h1 id="the-body">The Body</h1>
<p>Eat and Run tells the story of Scott Jurek, one of the most famous and succesful ultrarunners in history. It starts with his childhood and documents his process and explains why he started running, and how he eventually ended up eating a vegan diet.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve been plant based for 7 years already, but if I were in need of more convincing, this book would definitely convince me to become vegan. Instead of pages of quotations of studies, Scott provides his subjective account of becoming vegan and how it affected his performance:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>I learned that I could eat more, enjoy it more, and still get leaner than I had ever been in my life. When I went vegan, I started eating more whole grains and legumes, fruits and vegetables. My cheekbones seemed more pronounced, my face more chiseled. Muscles I didn’t even know I had popped out. I was eating more, losing weight, and gaining muscle—all on a vegan diet. My recovery times between workouts and races got even shorter. I wasn’t even sore the day after 50-mile races. I woke up with more energy every day. Fruit tasted sweeter, vegetables crunchier and more flavorful. I was doing short runs in the morning, working 8- to 10-hour days, then running 10 to 20 miles in the evening. I felt as if my concentration was improving every day.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Anyone who pays attention to what they eat and how it affects them will naturally move toward plants—and toward health.</p>
</blockquote>
<h1 id="the-mind">The Mind</h1>
<p>The other aspect of ultrarunning, which draws me the most, is the psychological side of it. It takes massive mental strength to power yourself through a 24 or 48 hour race of constant running without any sleep. How long can you fight the urge to give up?</p>
<p>Scott tells gripping stories of his races and how he had to work with his own psyche to get through the worst parts. I find the accounts fascinating where he describes being ready to give up, but somehow finding a new source of energy out of nothing and finishing the race in great shape.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>When I got to the 50-mile mark I couldn’t think that I had 100 miles to go. I had to remember and forget. We move forward, but we must stay in the present. I tried to do so by breaking races into small, digestible parts. Sometimes I focused on the next aid station, three miles ahead. Sometimes I pictured the next shady spot down the road, or the next step.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>That’s one of the many great pleasures of an ultramarathon. You can hurt more than you ever thought possible, then continue until you discover that hurting isn’t that big a deal. Forget a second wind. In an ultra you can get a third, a fourth, a fifth even. I still had more than 40 miles to go, but that’s a second wonderful thing about 100- (and plus) milers. You can trail, and despair, and screw up, and despair more, and there’s almost always another chance. Salvation is always within reach. You can’t reach it by thinking or by figuring it out. Sometimes you just do things.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Even if you are not into running or plant based nutrition, this book can be an interesting read. I think there is something fascinating about powering yourself through 100 miles, fighting the pain and suffering and finding energy from nowhere that anybody can appreciate.</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202309270609</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Notes: Finding Ultra By Rich Roll</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/book-notes-finding-ultra-rich-roll/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/book-notes-finding-ultra-rich-roll/</guid>
      <description>Rich Roll has been a familiar face to me for many years. I first came across him about 7 years ago when I made my first explorations into plant based nutrition. I believe the documentary &amp;ldquo;Forks over Knives&amp;rdquo; was the first time I saw him. I recently read &amp;ldquo;Finding Ultra&amp;rdquo; by Rich Roll, which documents the journey from being an overweight and unhappy lawyer to becoming one of the world&amp;rsquo;s fittest men and a vegan ultra-endurance athlete.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Rich Roll has been a familiar face to me for many years. I first came across him about 7 years ago when I made my first explorations into plant based nutrition. I believe the documentary &ldquo;Forks over Knives&rdquo; was the first time I saw him. I recently read &ldquo;Finding Ultra&rdquo; by Rich Roll, which documents the journey from being an overweight and unhappy lawyer to becoming one of the world&rsquo;s fittest men and a vegan ultra-endurance athlete. I&rsquo;ve always appreciated his podcasts and his way of presenting himself, so it was great to learn about his journey.</p>
<p>In this book, Rich shares his story of how he overcame alcoholism, depression, and poor health by adopting a plant-based diet and a rigorous training regimen. He also describes his amazing feats of endurance, such as completing five Ironman-distance triathlons on five Hawaiian islands in under a week.</p>
<p>As someone who is already eating a plant-based diet, I still found this book very inspiring. It affirmed to me that you can be a high-performance athlete as a vegan. I have started running early this year and I have made a lot of progress. I recently ran 12 kilometres for the first time. This book has inspired me to clean up my diet even more and train harder and to search out my limits.</p>
<p>Here are some of the quotes from the book that I highlighted, which resonated with me:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;The solution is spiritual.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Safety isn’t just an illusion, it’s a cop-out.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;When you believe you’ve reached your absolute limit, you’ve only tapped into about 40 percent of what you’re truly capable of.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Bliss in depletion. I finally got it. It’s that beautiful place of ascetic purity that is permitted to bloom only when the mind is stopped dead in its tracks and everything else is stripped away, leaving your soul—or who you really are—to forge a connection with the truth.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;It’s not an exaggeration to say that my EPIC5 experience had been fueled in large part by avocados, grapeseed oil–based Vegenaise, and coconut water.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Some of the key takeaways that I learned from this book are:</p>
<ul>
<li>Change is possible at any age, but it requires commitment, discipline, and faith.</li>
<li>Plant-based nutrition can enhance health, performance, and recovery.</li>
<li>Endurance sports are not only physical, but also mental and spiritual challenges.</li>
<li>Finding your purpose and passion can give you the motivation and courage to overcome any obstacle.</li>
<li>Living authentically and gratefully is the ultimate reward.</li>
</ul>
<p>I highly recommend this book to anyone who is interested in personal growth, veganism, or endurance sports. It is a captivating and uplifting story that will make you rethink what you are capable of.</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202307240707</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A List Of All The Books I Have Read In My Life</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/books-i-have-read/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/books-i-have-read/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m an avid reader, and this list is far from complete. But I wanted to start writing down the ones I&amp;rsquo;m reading now, and the ones I&amp;rsquo;ve read in the past. I&amp;rsquo;m mostly writing down titles but I&amp;rsquo;ll include the author when I remember the name.
2023 Born to Run
Four Thousand Weeks
The Plantpower Way - Rich Roll
Eat and Run - Scott Jurek
Finding Ultra - Rich Roll</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m an avid reader, and this list is far from complete. But I wanted to start writing down the ones I&rsquo;m reading now, and the ones I&rsquo;ve read in the past. I&rsquo;m mostly writing down titles but I&rsquo;ll include the author when I remember the name.</p>
<h1 id="2023">2023</h1>
<p>Born to Run</p>
<p>Four Thousand Weeks</p>
<p>The Plantpower Way - Rich Roll</p>
<p><a href="/zet/book-notes-eat-and-run/">Eat and Run - Scott Jurek</a></p>
<p><a href="/zet/book-notes-finding-ultra-rich-roll/">Finding Ultra - Rich Roll</a></p>
<p><a href="/zet/book-notes-simple-path-to-wealth/">A Simple Path to Wealth</a></p>
<p>The Richest Man in Babylon</p>
<p>Can&rsquo;t Hurt Me</p>
<p>How to Win Friends and Influence People</p>
<p>The Subtle Art of Not Giving A F*ck</p>
<p>Never Split the Difference</p>
<p><a href="/zet/articles/ikigai-book/">Ikigai</a></p>
<p>Building A Second Brain</p>
<p>On Writing Well</p>
<p>Fat Loss Forever - Layne Norton</p>
<p><a href="/zet/articles/unicorn-project/">The Unicorn Project</a></p>
<p>The Clean Coder</p>
<p>Get A Financial Life</p>
<p>Your Money or Your Life</p>
<h1 id="earlier">Earlier</h1>
<p>Moby Dick</p>
<p>The Lord of the Rings</p>
<p>The Wim Hof Method</p>
<p>The Way of Qigong</p>
<p>The Oxygen Advantage</p>
<p>Remember It</p>
<p>Pride and Prejudice</p>
<p>White Noise</p>
<p>The Road</p>
<p>The Reluctant Fundamentalist</p>
<p>The Last Kingdom series</p>
<p>War and Peace</p>
<p>Anna Karenina</p>
<p>Dictator</p>
<p>Imperium</p>
<p>Lustrum</p>
<p>4 Hour Workweek</p>
<p>Uncommon Wisdom</p>
<p>Stillness Flowing</p>
<p>Seeking Buddho</p>
<p>What Doesn&rsquo;t Kill Us</p>
<p>The Art Of Happiness</p>
<p>Into the Wild</p>
<p>Alone in the Wilderness</p>
<p>Call of the Wild</p>
<p>White Fang</p>
<p>Name of the Wind</p>
<p>Wise Man&rsquo;s Fear</p>
<p>Slow Regard of Silent Things</p>
<p>Bigger Leaner Stronger series</p>
<p>As I Lay Dying</p>
<p>The Canterbury Tales</p>
<p>Beowulf</p>
<p>Swedish Carving Techniques</p>
<p>Drawing Nature for the Absolute Beginner</p>
<p>Old Souls</p>
<p>Thus Spake Zarathustra</p>
<p>Opening the Door of Your Heart</p>
<p>The Kreutzer Sonata</p>
<p>The Hunger Fix</p>
<p>Fire First Law Trilogy</p>
<p>The Starch Solution</p>
<p>Ultimate Guide to Chinese Tea</p>
<p>The Way to Love</p>
<p>Moonwalking with Einstein</p>
<p>The Prose Edda</p>
<p>How to Draw what you See</p>
<p>Untethered Soul</p>
<p>How to Practice</p>
<p>Intuitive Awareness - Ajahn Sumedho</p>
<p>Awareness - Tony DeMello</p>
<p>Way of Power - Master Lam</p>
<p>The Way of Energy - Master Lam</p>
<p>The Noble Eightfold Path - Bikkhu Bodhi</p>
<p>Wisdom Develops Samadhi</p>
<p>The Collected Teachings of Ajahn Chah 1, 2, 3</p>
<p>Forest Desanas</p>
<p>Forest Dhamma</p>
<p>Mae Chee Kaew</p>
<p>Samana</p>
<p>The Way it Is</p>
<p>Art of Memory</p>
<p>Xu Yun</p>
<p>Bartleby: The Scrivener</p>
<p>Walden</p>
<p>How to Take Smart Notes</p>
<p>Steal Like an Artist</p>
<p>Can&rsquo;t Hurt Me</p>
<p>Hitchhiker&rsquo;s Guide to the Galaxy</p>
<p>Arthurian Literature</p>
<p>Mallory</p>
<p>Don Quichote</p>
<p>Starting Strength</p>
<p>Practical Programming</p>
<p>The Hidden Life of Trees</p>
<p>The Bullet Journal Method</p>
<p>Thinking Fast and Slow</p>
<p>Angela&rsquo;s Ashes</p>
<p>Great Expectations - Dickens</p>
<p>Hard Times - Dickens</p>
<p>Othello</p>
<p>King Lear</p>
<p>Broodje Gezond</p>
<p>Paradise - Toni Morrison</p>
<p>Watchmen</p>
<p>Heart of Darkness</p>
<p>Christianity - Chidester</p>
<p>In het Huis van de Islam</p>
<p>A Short History of Nearly Everything</p>
<p>The Surprising Purpose of Anger</p>
<p>Nonviolent Communication</p>
<p>The Hobbit</p>
<p>Mythology</p>
<p>The Iliad</p>
<p>In the Buddha&rsquo;s Words - Bhikkhu Bodhi</p>
<p>The Word of the Buddha - Nyanatiloka</p>
<p>The Dhammapada</p>
<p>Dependent Origination</p>
<p>Xu Yun: Dharma Words</p>
<p><a href="/zet/articles/phoenix-project/">The Phoenix Project</a></p>
<p>Why We Sleep</p>
<p>How to remember your Dreams</p>
<p>Solomon&rsquo;s Memory Palace</p>
<p>The Complete Guide to Fasting</p>
<p>Direct Realization - Ajahn Sumedho</p>
<p>Peace is a Simple Step - Ajahn Sumedho</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202307062007</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book notes: The Simple Path to Wealth: Your road map to financial independence and  rich, free life</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/book-notes-simple-path-to-wealth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/book-notes-simple-path-to-wealth/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Sound investing is not complicated.&amp;rdquo; - location: 204 ^ref-4205
This book was recommended to me multiple times on the DutchFIRE Reddit. I finally got round to reading it.
Key takeaways Save half your income After building an emergency fund, invest your savings Invest everything in broadly spread index funds The market always goes up (in the long run) The market is going to crash, you need to prepare to ride it out It&amp;rsquo;s not about retiring early, it&amp;rsquo;s about F-you money Thoughts From my research I had already thought out a pretty similar investment strategy of maximizing savings and putting it all in index funds.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Sound investing is not complicated.&rdquo; - location: 204 ^ref-4205</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This book was recommended to me multiple times on the DutchFIRE Reddit. I finally got round to reading it.</p>
<h1 id="key-takeaways">Key takeaways</h1>
<ul>
<li>Save half your income</li>
<li>After building an emergency fund, invest your savings</li>
<li>Invest everything in broadly spread index funds</li>
<li>The market always goes up (in the long run)</li>
<li>The market is going to crash, you need to prepare to ride it out</li>
<li>It&rsquo;s not about retiring early, it&rsquo;s about F-you money</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="thoughts">Thoughts</h1>
<p>From my research I had already thought out a pretty similar investment strategy of maximizing savings and putting it all in index funds. I don&rsquo;t have a very entrepreneurial or business oriented mind. I don&rsquo;t have the interest to dive deep into financial reports and analyzing company earnings. So as an average guy I&rsquo;ll just invest it into index funds. Keep adding as much as I can to them for 20 years, let the market and compounding interest do the work, and then I should be financially independent.</p>
<p>What is financial independence? This book frames it as F-you money:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;For me, the pursuit of financial independence has never been about retirement. I like working and I’ve enjoyed my career. It’s been about having options. It’s been about being able to say “no.” It’s been about having F-You Money and the freedom it provides.&rdquo; - location: 228 ^ref-34594</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I love this idea, because I&rsquo;m not necessarily interested in retiring very early. I love my work and I&rsquo;m lucky to work in a field that is under continuous development. It&rsquo;s already hard to keep up, so the thought of working 30 years from now is actually rather exciting. I think it&rsquo;s good to have something to do, it&rsquo;s not healthy to just travel around when you&rsquo;re 35 and I think it will become a very empty and unfulfilling life pretty quickly.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;d much rather have the freedom to take a few months off here and there. Mini retirements. Go travelling for 6 months and start an exciting new position somewhere, or continue working on the things you left off.</p>
<h1 id="quotes">Quotes</h1>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Since money is the single most powerful tool we have for navigating this complex world we’ve created, understanding it is critical. If you choose to master it, money becomes a wonderful servant. If you don’t, it will surely master you.&rdquo; - location: 183 ^ref-59928</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;The beauty of a high savings rate is twofold: You learn to live on less even as you have more to invest.&rdquo; - location: 207 ^ref-14488</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;The other thing I quickly figured out is that financial independence is at least as much about being able to live modestly as it is about cash, as our opening parable describes.&rdquo; - location: 242 ^ref-10147</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;If you decide to pursue financial freedom you are going to have to choose to spend your money on investments. Somehow in our culture this has come to be seen by most people as deprivation. That has never made much sense to me. Personally, there is nothing I’d rather buy or own than F-You Money.&rdquo; - location: 2897 ^ref-10616</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;It’s not hard. Stop thinking about what your money can buy. Start thinking about what your money can earn. And then think about what the money it earns can earn. Once you begin to do this, you’ll start to see that when you spend money, not only is that money gone forever, the money it might have earned is gone as well. And so on.&rdquo; - location: 595 ^ref-24245</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;The market always goes up. Always. Bet no one’s told you that before. But it’s true. Understand this is not to say it is a smooth ride. It’s not. It is most often a wild and rocky road. But it always, and I mean always, goes up. Not every year. Not every month. Not every week and certainly not every day. But take a moment and look again at the chart of the stock market in the last chapter. The trend is relentlessly, through disaster after disaster, up.&rdquo; - location: 822 ^ref-50566</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;This is why you have to toughen up, learn to ignore the noise and ride out the storm; adding still more money to your investments as you go. 7. To be strong enough to stay the course you need to know these bad things are coming—not only intellectually but on an emotional level as well. You need to know this deep in your gut. They will happen. They will hurt. But like blizzards in winter they should never be a surprise. And, unless you panic, they won’t matter.&rdquo; - location: 830 ^ref-55872</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;We believe we can pick individual stocks. You can’t pick winning stocks. Don’t feel bad. I can’t either. Nor can the overwhelming majority of professionals in the business. The fact that this ability is so rare is the key reason why the very few who apparently can are so famous.&rdquo; - location: 935 ^ref-53690</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;To consider buying a house, if you are so inclined. But don’t be in a hurry. Houses are not investments, they are expensive indulgences. Buy one only when you can easily afford it and if it provides the lifestyle change you want.&rdquo; - location: 2836 ^ref-13073</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202307031907</p>
<p><a href="https://jlcollinsnh.com/">https://jlcollinsnh.com/</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Notes: Ikigai: The Japanese Secret to a Long and Happy Life</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/articles/ikigai-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/articles/ikigai-book/</guid>
      <description>I came across this little book while doing some research for my Jiro Dreams of Sushi article. While scanning the book&amp;rsquo;s description, I was intrigued by this sentence: &amp;ldquo;the happiness of always being busy.&amp;rdquo; Although I work hard every day, I also enjoy ticking off the last item on my to-do list and enjoying some rest. Is there more happiness in being in constant activity?
Ikigai &amp;ldquo;He who has a why to live for can bear with almost any how.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I came across this little book while doing some research for my <a href="/zet/articles/jiro-sushi">Jiro Dreams of Sushi article.</a> While scanning the book&rsquo;s description, I was intrigued by this sentence: &ldquo;the happiness of always being busy.&rdquo; Although I work hard every day, I also enjoy ticking off the last item on my to-do list and enjoying some rest. Is there more happiness in being in constant activity?</p>
<h2 id="ikigai">Ikigai</h2>
<blockquote>
<hr>
<p>&ldquo;He who has a why to live for can bear with almost any how.&rdquo;</p>
<ul>
<li>Friedrich Nietzsche</li>
</ul>
<hr>
</blockquote>
<p>According to Japanese culture, everybody has a purpose in life: the ikigai. &ldquo;Ikigai is the reason we get up in the morning.&rdquo; The book explores this concept through interesting stories and brings related notions from various areas to explain ikigai to the Western mind.</p>
<p>There are many different ikigai, and people can have several ikigai simultaneously. For example, some people have their vegetable garden as their ikigai, while others have drawing or calligraphy. <a href="/zet/articles/jiro-sushi">Jiro</a> has making sushi as his ikigai. Even though many people have their work as their ikigai, it does not necessarily have to be the case. Ikigai can also be of a social nature, such as a family or local community.</p>
<p>
  <img loading="lazy" src="https://external-content.duckduckgo.com/iu/?u=https%3A%2F%2F3nw94z2pgadc432nw33p8qg5-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com%2Fwp-content%2Fuploads%2F2018%2F01%2Fwhat-is-ikigai-darling.png&amp;f=1&amp;nofb=1&amp;ipt=f5fa9a17a2865d283af2bfdf8d978f1dcb0e9ff4e7fb646fb2c26c4963f95e77&amp;ipo=images" alt=""  /></p>
<h2 id="retirement">Retirement</h2>
<p>When I watched Jiro Dreams of Sushi for the first time, I was surprised that Jiro still worked at his restaurant every day at age 85. This book explores that further.</p>
<p>Apparently, many people never really retire in Japan. The concept of retirement, as we know it in the West, does not exist in the Japanese language: there is &ldquo;no word in Japanese that means retire in the sense of &ldquo;leaving the workforce for good&rdquo; as in English.&rdquo; People continue doing what they like doing as long as their health allows. They keep following their ikigai.</p>
<p>This concept was very refreshing to me and had a profound influence on how I imagine my own future. After becoming more intentional about my career, I became interested in <a href="https://www.investopedia.com/terms/f/financial-independence-retire-early-fire.asp">FIRE</a> and the possibility of retiring early. However, as I contemplated this strategy, I discovered that I didn&rsquo;t want to stop working because I really enjoy my work.</p>
<p>Why would I want to retire if I&rsquo;m doing what I love? That was the whole point of switching my career to IT, and this is where Western culture can learn a lot from Japanese culture. In Japanese culture, there is more emphasis on aligning your career with your interests and continuing that passion well into old age.</p>
<blockquote>
<hr>
<p>When to quit? The job you have worked so hard for? I never once hated my job. I fell in love with my work and gave my life to it. Even though I&rsquo;m 85 years old, I don&rsquo;t feel like retiring.</p>
<ul>
<li>Jiro</li>
</ul>
<hr>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="longevity">Longevity</h2>
<p>A large part of the book is about the residents of Okinawa: the island with the highest number of people 100 years old or older. The authors tell the story of their visit to the island to reveal the secret of the Okinawan&rsquo;s long lives. It is not uncommon to see people working in the fields who are well into their eighties. The Okinawans freely share their secrets with us, and the authors do a great job translating the Japanese principles into actionable advice.</p>
<p>Much of the advice is centered around dietary habits. Not only what to eat, but also how to eat it: &ldquo;Okinawans stop eating when they feel their stomachs reach 80 percent of their capacity, rather than overeating&rdquo;, a practice which is named &ldquo;hara haci bu.&rdquo; They consume a daily average of 1800 to 1900 calories, a significant difference from the 2200 to 3300 calories consumed by an average person in the US every day.</p>
<p>Another theme that keeps returning is the crucial function of social groups for finding meaning in life, especially in old age: &ldquo;It is customary in Okinawa to form close bonds within local communities. A moai is an informal group of people with common interests who look out for one another. For many, serving the community becomes part of their ikigai.&rdquo;</p>
<p>This book may be a good resource if you are interested in longevity. Even though I only expected to read about the ikigai concept, it contains a surprisingly large amount of valuable advice and practical tips to live a longer and happier life.</p>
<h2 id="chock-full">Chock-full</h2>
<p>&ldquo;Ikigai: The Japanese Secret to a Long and Happy Life&rdquo; is a small book that covers an astonishing amount of subjects. It covers topics such as meditation, flow states, and exercise methods such as Tai Chi and Qi Gong. The disadvantage is that it does not deeply cover any of these topics. But I think this book can be a very useful springboard for further research and a great introduction to many different subjects that can improve your life.</p>
<p>It is a short read, but it contains a lot of wisdom, and I learned much from this book. It has changed the way I think of retirement and the way I approach my work. I am also very interested in health and longevity. Through the conversations with the centenarians of Okinawa, I received a lot of helpful tips, which I&rsquo;m already applying to my daily life.</p>
<p>Have I discovered the art of being busy? I believe I took this definition too literally when I started reading this book. I found that Okinawans lead active lives full of meaning but also take plenty of rest. Always being busy does not mean that you have to work yourself to death. However, it does mean that the secret to reaching a healthy old age is to keep doing what you love. There is no need to become sedentary and only sit in front of the TV when you turn 67. I think Western culture has a lot to learn in this area.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Notes: The Unicorn Project</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/articles/unicorn-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/articles/unicorn-project/</guid>
      <description>This book is the sequel to the Phoenix project. Both books are set at Parts Unlimited, a fictitious company that supplies car parts to DIY mechanics and repair shops. Phoenix is a new system that Parts Unlimited has worked on for multiple years. It is supposed to handle order processing and communication between manufacturing, stores, and clients. Phoenix will also play a role in sales and marketing. The company has been gathering customer data for years, but it cannot use any of this data yet.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>
  <img loading="lazy" src="https://m.media-amazon.com/images/W/IMAGERENDERING_521856-T1/images/I/91UM5i4nirL.jpg" alt="Unicorn Project"  /></p>
<p>This book is the sequel to <a href="/zet/articles/phoenix-project">the Phoenix project</a>. Both books are set at Parts Unlimited, a fictitious company that supplies car parts to DIY mechanics and repair shops. Phoenix is a new system that Parts Unlimited has worked on for multiple years. It is supposed to handle order processing and communication between manufacturing, stores, and clients. Phoenix will also play a role in sales and marketing. The company has been gathering customer data for years, but it cannot use any of this data yet. Phoenix will enable it to generate targeted marketing campaigns from the data when it&rsquo;s finished.</p>
<p>But as we saw in the previous book, it is far from finished, and things go wrong all the time. The company is not doing well, the stock prices are falling, and they need an edge over the competition. Phoenix will be their edge, but they&rsquo;ve been working on it for years. Eventually, management decided that Phoenix needed to be deployed in two weeks. But it is far from ready.</p>
<p>The main character in the Unicorn project is Maxine, a senior developer who temporarily transferred to a different department. She had to work on the Phoenix project against her will because of an unfortunate situation that needed a scapegoat. However, Maxine decides to make the best out of it, and she&rsquo;d like to begin with one thing: to get a Phoenix build going on her laptop.</p>
<p>Very quickly, she finds it impossible to run a full build of the Phoenix project due to missing files and other elements. She is appalled and makes it her mission to get the build going, but she meets another hurdle every step of the way. Missing credentials. Missing binaries and libraries. And for each of these hurdles, she must submit a ticket with a different department. Very soon, she has over 20 tickets running with long waiting times. Just to get a build going on her machine so she can work! Dozens of developers were hired to work on the Phoenix project. But when she asks them if they&rsquo;ve managed to get a build going yet, Maxine is horrified to discover that they&rsquo;ve tried for several months but haven&rsquo;t made any progress. Maxine has made more progress in a week.</p>
<blockquote>
<hr>
<p>&ldquo;Everyone around here thinks features are important because they can see them in their app, on the web page, or in the API. But no one seems to realize how important the build process is. Developers cannot be productive without a great build, integration, and test process.&rdquo;</p>
<ul>
<li>Unicorn Project</li>
</ul>
<hr>
</blockquote>
<p>After a few weeks, Maxine receives an invitation to have a drink with a group of people who are very interested in her. When she arrives at the bar, she meets the Rebellion: a group of developers, managers, and people from Operations, who are tired of the old organizational structure and want to make real changes. They think out of the box and experiment with new technologies, even though they are not authorized to do so.</p>
<p>With the Rebellion, Maxine significantly improves the build and deployment process. They recognized that Phoenix actually never was being built in its entirety. Developers were always working on parts of the application. However, after a lot of struggle, they create a build process that enables each developer to become operational on his first day.</p>
<p>This is the first step of a long series of exciting events that lead to Phoenix becoming a success. By the end of the book, they have a completely new development and testing process, and they can deploy changes to production without needing to take the entire application down. This allows them to create targeted marketing campaigns and respond to changes in the market. The first campaign was a huge success and generated the highest sales ever.</p>
<p>Maxine&rsquo;s struggle with the build process was an eye-opening experience for me. It gave me a very practical example of the need for DevOps principles to enable delivering value to customers. It is also something I recognize in my current organization. For example, projects can get stuck on a firewall change that needs to be approved by an external party. By implementing DevOps principles and arranging teams according to the &ldquo;you build it, you run it&rdquo; principle, teams can be responsible for the entire process from idea to production and therefore have a very short release cycle for their application.</p>
<p>I thoroughly enjoyed the first part of the book. However, the second part was less engaging to me. It became long-winded and felt like butter spread over too much bread. The author demonstrates a high level of technical experience and knowledge through his descriptions of processes, deployments, and fictional applications. Although I understand the intention of making Parts Unlimited a believable company, I think it could have been accomplished with much less detail and words.</p>
<p>The second part has more corporate drama, such as temporarily suspended managers without any clear reason. The focus shifts from a development and operations perspective to a managerial perspective. Maybe I will reread the book in a few years and this part will make a lot more sense to me then. The same happened when I reread the Phoenix project. I could not understand some aspects of the book, which became much clearer to me when I revisited it after gaining experience in the field.</p>
<p>I highly recommend this book to anyone working as a developer, DevOps Engineer, or in operations, especially if you are starting your career. The book gave me a lot of insights into &ldquo;the old way of working&rdquo; and a better understanding of the need for DevOps principles in the modern IT landscape. However, make sure to read the Phoenix project first.</p>
<h2 id="the-unicorn-project-a-novel-about-developers-digital-disruption-and-thriving-in-the-age-of-data-by-gene-kim">The Unicorn Project: A Novel about Developers, Digital Disruption, and Thriving in the Age of Data by Gene Kim</h2>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Notes: The Phoenix Project</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/articles/phoenix-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/articles/phoenix-project/</guid>
      <description>When I started my DevOps traineeship, I borrowed this book from my boss and read it from cover to cover. I loved the story and the characters; it helped me understand &amp;ldquo;the old way&amp;rdquo; of doing things and the merits of implementing DevOps principles.
I reread the book ten months later. In the meantime, I&amp;rsquo;ve learned many new skills and technologies and started working full-time as a DevOps engineer.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>
  <img loading="lazy" src="https://m.media-amazon.com/images/W/IMAGERENDERING_521856-T1/images/I/914-sUgELZL.jpg" alt="Phoenix Project"  /></p>
<p>When I started my DevOps traineeship, I borrowed this book from my boss and read it from cover to cover. I loved the story and the characters; it helped me understand &ldquo;the old way&rdquo; of doing things and the merits of implementing DevOps principles.</p>
<p>I reread the book ten months later. In the meantime, I&rsquo;ve learned many new skills and technologies and started working full-time as a DevOps engineer.</p>
<p>Not surprisingly, it made a lot more sense to me this time, and I&rsquo;m sure it will be even better when I reread it a few years later. In this article, I&rsquo;ll share my thoughts and notes on the book.</p>
<h2 id="the-story">The Story</h2>
<p>The main character is Bill Palmer, a mid-level IT manager in a manufacturing company called Parts Unlimited. Within a few pages, he is called into the CEO&rsquo;s office, and he is promoted to the VP of Operations, putting him in charge of IT, much against his own will or desire.</p>
<p>The situation Bill enters is a humorously chaotic one. We are thrown straight into a Sev 1 incident where managers point fingers and shout at each other. We quickly get the impression that this is a dysfunctional department that only performs tasks for the manager who shouts the loudest while fighting off crippling outages.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>It’s like the Wild West out here. We’re mostly shooting from the hip.”<br>
<em>The Phoenix Project</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>The bulk of the story revolves around how Bill, together with his team of managers, Wes, Patty, and John, manage to turn this chaos into a department that does work according to a streamlined plan in a much more predictable manner.</p>
<p>To achieve this goal, Bill is introduced to Erik, a prospective board member of the company. Erik becomes Bill&rsquo;s mentor and guides Bill through the process of creating order in the chaos. Their interaction reminds me of Zen masters training their disciples by asking deep questions which don&rsquo;t have an immediately apparent answer.</p>
<h2 id="master--disciple">Master &amp; Disciple</h2>
<p>Erik takes Bill to the manufacturing plant of Parts Unlimited and tries to impress upon Bill that manufacturing planning principles from Lean can be applied to IT work. Erik argues that an IT department could be structured like a factory production line, but Bill is not ready to accept this.</p>
<p>A fundamental notion from manufacturing principles is that work should always be moving forwards along the production line, never backward. But unfortunately, this is very often the case in the &ldquo;old&rdquo; way of working: the development team works on an application for several months, and when they are finished with it, they throw it over the fence to the Operations people, whose job it is to deploy the application.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>One of the developers had actually walked in a couple of minutes ago and said, “Look, it’s running on my laptop. How hard can it be?”<br>
<em>The Phoenix Project</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>However, as we see happening time after time in the book, usually the application is incompatible with the infrastructure it is deployed to. As a result, the application needs to go back to development. According to manufacturing theory, this is a situation where work goes backward through the production line, which we must avoid at all costs.</p>
<h2 id="implementation">Implementation</h2>
<p>Erik challenges Bill to start doing ten deployments a day instead of one deployment every nine months. Understandably, this is a ridiculous notion to Bill. The last few deployments were disastrous events that required his entire department to pull all-nighters through the weekend, and still, the stores were not managing to process all orders and payments.</p>
<p>However, Bill takes his mentor&rsquo;s advice and figures out a way to do it together with his team. One of the main problems they uncovered was the inconsistent deployment and production environments.</p>
<p>The solution to this problem was to involve the operations people in the development stage right from the beginning, so the development environment matched the production environment exactly. The environments were standardized and put in code with version control, and things started progressing quickly.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>As Wes talks, I think about Erik challenging me to think like a plant manager as opposed to a work center supervisor. I suddenly realize that he probably meant that I needed to span the departmental boundaries of Development and IT Operations.
<em>The Phoenix Project</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is just one of the problems addressed by melting away the fence between Development and Operations. By the end of the book, the two camps started to work together much better. They come closer to the target of 10 deployments a day, and the DevOps way of working was born.</p>
<h2 id="closing-thoughts">Closing Thoughts</h2>
<p>I think this book is a must-read for anyone considering entering the DevOps field or anyone already working with DevOps.</p>
<p>As a nerd who loves structure and organization, the theme of the story is incredibly entertaining and satisfying to me. The authors excellently capture the transition from an utterly disorganized situation to a predictable environment with happy co-workers. Actually, I&rsquo;m a little embarrassed by how much joy this transition brings me.</p>
<p>Especially the second time around, it helped me better understand the underlying principles that enable the DevOps way of working in an organization. Moreover, it paints a great picture of how an organization can change for the better by embracing DevOps principles and how these changes express themselves in the improved quality and speed of software development and deployment. All of these advantages lead to delivering better value to the customer, which is the core focus of any productive and creative endeavor involving customers and end users.</p>
<h2 id="the-phoenix-project-written-by-gene-kim-kevin-behr-george-spafford">The Phoenix Project, written by Gene Kim, Kevin Behr, George Spafford</h2>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
