<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Health on Mischa van den Burg</title>
    <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/health/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Health on Mischa van den Burg</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>New Running Record! Ran 12km today</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/running-record-12km/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/running-record-12km/</guid>
      <description>New week, new record! For the first time in my life I ran 12 kilometers, and immediately another 10k PR!
This morning it was time for my long run, and while I was drinking my coffee I decided to watch a running technique video again to see what I could improve. Lately I have mainly focused on my heart rate and steps per minute, but today I focused more on maintaining a better posture by sticking out my chest a bit more and leaning forward a bit more.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>New week, new record! For the first time in my life I ran 12 kilometers, and immediately another 10k PR!</p>
<p>This morning it was time for my long run, and while I was drinking my coffee I decided to watch a running technique video again to see what I could improve. Lately I have mainly focused on my heart rate and steps per minute, but today I focused more on maintaining a better posture by sticking out my chest a bit more and leaning forward a bit more. The result was that I suddenly ran much faster and more relaxed without this resulting in a higher HR, and my steps per minute were also fine afterwards with 171SPM. These days I usually run around 6:30 but I’m really surprised that I was able to set both a distance record and a higher average speed without having to make any effort except constantly maintaining a better posture. “Running Tall” was the mantra that I kept coming back to when I noticed that I started to sink back.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/12km2.png" type="" alt=""  /></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/12km3.png" type="" alt=""  /></p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202307221107</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fastest Runners in the World: An Overview of the Current World Records</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/running-fastest-current-records/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/running-fastest-current-records/</guid>
      <description>The Fastest Runners in the World Today I set another record for myself, I ran 12kilometers in 70 minutes. Usually I run at a 6:30 / km pace, but today somehow I managed to run at 5:53. This had me wondering, what is the pace of the professionals? Who are the fastest runners in the world? How fast can they run different distances, such as 10km, 5km, or marathon? And how do their speeds compare to the average runner?</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="the-fastest-runners-in-the-world">The Fastest Runners in the World</h2>
<p>Today I set another record for myself, I ran 12kilometers in 70 minutes. Usually I run at a 6:30 / km pace, but today somehow I managed to run at 5:53. This had me wondering, what is the pace of the professionals? Who are the fastest runners in the world? How fast can they run different distances, such as 10km, 5km, or marathon? And how do their speeds compare to the average runner?</p>
<p>In this blog post, I will look at the current world records for these three distances. I will also convert them to minutes per km speed, which is a common way to measure running pace.</p>
<h3 id="10km">10km</h3>
<p>The current world records for the 10km are:</p>
<ul>
<li>Men: 26:24 minutes, set by Rhonex Kipruto of Kenya in 2020. This means he ran at an average pace of 2.64 minutes per km, or 15.3 km/h.</li>
<li>Women: 29:43 minutes, set by Joyciline Jepkosgei of Kenya in 2017. This means she ran at an average pace of 2.98 minutes per km, or 13.6 km/h.</li>
</ul>
<p>These records are incredible when you consider that the average 10km time for men of all ages is 56:35 minutes, and for women of all ages is 1:04:49 minutes, according to a study by RunRepeat. That means the record holders are more than twice as fast as the average runner!</p>
<h3 id="5km">5km</h3>
<p>The current world records for the 5km are:</p>
<ul>
<li>Men: 12:49 minutes, set by Berihu Aregawi of Ethiopia in 2021. This means he ran at an average pace of 2.56 minutes per km, or 15.8 km/h.</li>
<li>Women: 14:19 minutes, set by Ejgayehu Taye of Ethiopia in 2021. This means she ran at an average pace of 2.86 minutes per km, or 14.2 km/h.</li>
</ul>
<p>These records are also impressive when you compare them to the average 5km time for men of all ages, which is 28:46 minutes, and for women of all ages, which is 34:32 minutes, according to another study by RunRepeat. That means the record holders are almost twice as fast as the average runner!</p>
<h3 id="marathon">Marathon</h3>
<p>The marathon is the ultimate road race distance that requires stamina, strength, and mental toughness. The current world records for the marathon are:</p>
<ul>
<li>Men: 2:01:09 hours, set by Eliud Kipchoge of Kenya in 2022. This means he ran at an average pace of 2.87 minutes per km, or 14 km/h.</li>
<li>Women: 2:14:04 hours, set by Brigid Kosgei of Kenya in 2019. This means she ran at an average pace of 3.18 minutes per km, or 12.7 km/h.</li>
</ul>
<p>These records are astounding when you think that the average marathon time for men of all ages is 4:32:49 hours, and for women of all ages is 5:09:45 hours, according to yet another study by RunRepeat. That means the record holders are more than twice as fast as the average runner!</p>
<h3 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h3>
<p>As you can see, the fastest runners in the world are truly remarkable athletes who can run at speeds that most of us can only dream of. They have trained hard and dedicated themselves to their sport, and have achieved amazing feats of human performance.</p>
<p>If you want to learn more about these runners and their records, you can check out these links:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/10K_run">10K run - Wikipedia</a></li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/5K_run">5K run - Wikipedia</a></li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marathon_world_record_progression">Marathon world record progression - Wikipedia</a></li>
<li><a href="https://worldathletics.org/">World Athletics</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Happy running! 😊</p>
<p>202307221107</p>
<p>[[running]]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcast Notes - Optimal Water Intake</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/optimal-hydration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/optimal-hydration/</guid>
      <description>Hydration Notes from Huberman Podcast For the first 10 hours of the day, consume 236ml for every hour awake
During exercise, follow Galpin equation: 2ml per kg of bodyweight every 15-20 minutes on average.
This does not mean you need to stop exercising and drink this amount. You can also consume it in a larger amount afterwards. It is recommended to drink during exercise though.
Use the normal recommendation to hydrate before exercise, this establishes a good baseline for heading into exercise.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="hydration-notes-from-huberman-podcast">Hydration Notes from Huberman Podcast</h1>
<p>For the first 10 hours of the day, consume 236ml for every hour awake</p>
<p>During exercise, follow Galpin equation: 2ml per kg of bodyweight every 15-20 minutes on average.</p>
<p>This does not mean you need to stop exercising and drink this amount. You can also consume it in a larger amount afterwards. It is recommended to drink during exercise though.</p>
<p>Use the normal recommendation to hydrate before exercise, this establishes a good baseline for heading into exercise.</p>
<h2 id="is-this-amount-of-water-on-top-of-the-baseline-hydration">Is this amount of water on top of the baseline hydration?</h2>
<p>If you exercise about an hour you can replace the number with the number from the Galpin equation.</p>
<p>In my case, 1 hour of exercise = 77 * 2 = 154ml every 20 minutes</p>
<p>154 * 3 = 462ml for 1 hour of exercise</p>
<h2 id="caffeine">Caffeine</h2>
<p>Offset caffeine drinks with a 2:1 water ratio.</p>
<p>So 1 240ml cup of coffee should be followed by 480ml of water.</p>
<h2 id="reducing-nightly-urination">Reducing Nightly Urination</h2>
<p>Urine secretion / filtration in the kidneys is highly dependent on the circadian rhythm.</p>
<p>It is normal to wake up once or twice to urinate during the night.</p>
<p>To reduce nighttime waking for urination:</p>
<ul>
<li>Ensure sufficient hydration during the day so you are not thirsty in the evening</li>
<li>Reduce fluid intake at night (provided you hydrated sufficiently during the day)</li>
<li>Consume no more than 180-240ml between 10 hours after waking and bedtime</li>
</ul>
<p>This means, waking up at 6am, only drink 1 cup of tea after 4pm.</p>
<p>But I drink 500ml at dinner time, so I should probably never drink after dinner from here on out, or just one cup of tea.</p>
<p>How quickly you secrete fluid is also partially determined by how quickly you drink that fluid. Gulping down a lot of fluid wil lead to quicker secretion.</p>
<h1 id="my-typical-day">My Typical Day</h1>
<p>1 hour exercise = 500ml</p>
<p>2 cups of coffee 500ml</p>
<p>10 hours = 2,4l</p>
<p>So I should be drinking about 3,25L in total a day!</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202305301905</p>
<p><a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/gb/podcast/huberman-lab/id1545953110?i=1000602925839">https://podcasts.apple.com/gb/podcast/huberman-lab/id1545953110?i=1000602925839</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovered MAF and Low Heart Rate Training</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/discovered-maf-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/discovered-maf-training/</guid>
      <description>Although I was already doing something very similar, yesterday I discovered MAF training through this video:
This video is super inspiring because he actually runs a 3 hour marathon while recording!
I was already doing base training for my running which I discovered through the r/running Reddit. Here you focus on time instead of distance and do many runs on low intensity throughout the week, and one long run where you go 5 minutes more every week.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Although I was already doing something very similar, yesterday I discovered MAF training through this video:</p>

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/P_VNQ6UIbS8" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<p>This video is super inspiring because he actually runs a 3 hour marathon while recording!</p>
<p>I was already doing <a href="/zet/base-training-running/">base training for my running</a> which I discovered through the r/running Reddit. Here you focus on time instead of distance and do many runs on low intensity throughout the week, and one long run where you go 5 minutes more every week.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m now in week 6 of my base training schedule and I&rsquo;m progressing nicely. My long run went from 50 minutes to 86 minutes, and my weekly total distance has increased from 20,6km to 32,8km!</p>
<h1 id="maf-training">MAF Training</h1>
<p>MAF stands for Maximum Aerobic Function and was developed by Dr. Phil Maffetone.</p>
<p>It uses <a href="https://philmaffetone.com/180-formula/">the 180 formula</a> to calculate the maximum heart rate you should hit during your run. What wasn&rsquo;t obvious from all the other videos I watched, was that this maximum heart rate actually establishes a zone you should be training in.</p>
<p>I discovered this in Dr. Maffetone&rsquo;s Book:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Once a maximum aerobic heart rate is found, a training range from this heart rate to 10 beats below could be used as a training range. For example, if an athlete’s maximum aerobic heart rate is determined to be 155, that person’s aerobic training zone would be 145 to 155 bpm. However, the more training at 155, the quicker an optimal aerobic base will be developed.</p>
</blockquote>
<h1 id="current-situation">Current Situation</h1>
<p>I hadn&rsquo;t been paying much attention to my heart rate up until this point. I just used the guideline of &ldquo;conversational pace&rdquo;, and that runs should feel easy and enjoyable. However, I knew I was going to need metrics one day, so I diligently tracked my workouts using my iWatch SE from day 1.</p>
<p>Here are my current heart rate stats and zones:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/zones.jpg" type="" alt=""  /></p>
<p>Going through my recent runs, my average heart rate has been around 100-115bpm. For example:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/heart.png" type="" alt=""  /></p>
<h1 id="time-to-start-nerding-on-some-numbers">Time To Start Nerding On Some Numbers</h1>
<p>Using the 180 formula, I calculated that I should use 180 - 33 - 5 = 142 as a maximum heart rate for my endurance training, which gives me a training zone of 132-142bpm. This is about 15 beats higher than I was used to! And if you look at the zones that Apple calculated for me, you&rsquo;ll see that this almost perfectly matches my calculated Zone 2.</p>
<p>After I calculated my new target, I tried it out immediately this morning. Here is the result:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/firstmaf.jpg" type="" alt=""  /></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/firstmaf2.jpg" type="" alt=""  /></p>


<div class="strava-embed-placeholder" data-embed-type="activity" data-embed-id="9143184934"></div><script src="https://strava-embeds.com/embed.js"></script>


<p>This definitely felt very different! After some experimentation and keeping an eye on my heart rate rising and falling, I managed to find a pattern that kept it around 135bpm. It felt much more like running instead of jogging. And I was surprised that even though I was running quite a bit faster than I was used to, I could still maintain a conversation if I wanted to, so I was still at a conversational pace. I had just estimated my conversational pace a lot lower than I was capable of. This shows you the power of using metrics for training! It definitely pushed me to go a little harder, a little faster, even though I&rsquo;m stil doing &ldquo;easy running&rdquo;.</p>
<p>Towards the end my legs started to hurt quite a bit more than usual, it felt much more like a workout, even though I was not totally exhausted in the end. The previous run I shared had a pace of 7.41/km and this one was on 6.42/km, which is a lot faster.</p>
<p>I have come to a point where all these numbers are starting to make sense to me now and I can start tracking them. Especially the heart rate has been a real eye opener. Now I have a perfect gauge to use while training: something that will let me know whether I should put in some more effort or slow down.</p>
<p>Already I&rsquo;m getting so much joy of seeing the progress I&rsquo;ve made from week 1 to 6, and seeing the numbers increase. I&rsquo;m really falling in love with this sport in so many ways, it&rsquo;s perfect for a nerd like me!</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202305261305</p>
<p><a href="https://philmaffetone.com/180-formula/">https://philmaffetone.com/180-formula/</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=e5wgoTuJuF8">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=e5wgoTuJuF8</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Went on My First Camping Trip After Moving Back to NL From Norway</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/first-camping-trip-in-netherlands/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/first-camping-trip-in-netherlands/</guid>
      <description>It was a nice week. I had an extra day off on Asenscion day and I decided to go for a camping trip for the first time after I moved back to the Netherlands.
It was a great experience, and I wrote a couple of Tumblr posts with photos:
https://www.tumblr.com/mischavandenburg/718093517925367808/first-trip-in-the-netherlands-part-1?source=share
https://www.tumblr.com/mischavandenburg/718098930739593216/part-2?source=share
Links: 202305232005
[[outdoors]]</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It was a nice week. I had an extra day off on Asenscion day and I decided to go for a camping trip for the first time after I moved back to the Netherlands.</p>
<p>It was a great experience, and I wrote a couple of Tumblr posts with photos:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.tumblr.com/mischavandenburg/718093517925367808/first-trip-in-the-netherlands-part-1?source=share">https://www.tumblr.com/mischavandenburg/718093517925367808/first-trip-in-the-netherlands-part-1?source=share</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.tumblr.com/mischavandenburg/718098930739593216/part-2?source=share">https://www.tumblr.com/mischavandenburg/718098930739593216/part-2?source=share</a></p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202305232005</p>
<p>[[outdoors]]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8 Simple Japanese Habits</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/8-simple-japanese-habits/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/8-simple-japanese-habits/</guid>
      <description>Through YouTube I&amp;rsquo;ve been exposed to quite a bit of Japanese culture and I love many aspects of it. I love this list of habits, and I was surprised to see how many of them I already incorporate.
Clean the Toilet Many successful businessmen clean the toilet every day. It humbles you. Ajahn Chah also talks about this a lot. Check out &amp;ldquo;Toilets on the Path&amp;rdquo;. I&amp;rsquo;m also very focused on cleanliness and especially emphasize keeping my toilet clean.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/04wZNnjdURE" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<p>Through YouTube I&rsquo;ve been exposed to quite a bit of Japanese culture and I love many aspects of it. I love this list of habits, and I was surprised to see how many of them I already incorporate.</p>
<ol>
<li>Clean the Toilet</li>
</ol>
<p>Many successful businessmen clean the toilet every day. It humbles you. Ajahn Chah also talks about this a lot. Check out &ldquo;Toilets on the Path&rdquo;. I&rsquo;m also very focused on cleanliness and especially emphasize keeping my toilet clean. But I like the idea of cleaning it every day and I&rsquo;m going to give it a try.</p>
<ol start="2">
<li>Put your shoes away neatly</li>
</ol>
<p>Just look at how clean that looks in the video! Fortunately I also have a habit of putting them neatly on a rack I have.</p>
<ol start="3">
<li>Improve your posture</li>
</ol>
<p>Investing in my Herman Miller chair has been a huge improvement to my life, and combined with yoga my posture has improved a lot over the past few months. I walk more upright and find myself correcting posture more often than before.</p>
<ol start="4">
<li>Thanking for meals</li>
</ol>
<p>Being grateful for all people who were involved in making that meal. The farmers, the cooks, everybody.</p>
<p>Being grateful for life.</p>
<p>I can definitely improve on this and appreciate my food more.</p>
<ol start="5">
<li>Put the chair back after you use it</li>
</ol>
<p>Japanese people are very concerned with other people&rsquo;s feelings. Putting a chair back in a restaurant you will make the restaurant staff happy, for example. I&rsquo;m usually quite considerate about these things and generally want to make the world a better place. I have a habit of thinking, &ldquo;how can I make this person&rsquo;s day a little better?&rdquo;</p>
<ol start="6">
<li>Appreciate the things you already have</li>
</ol>
<p>Don&rsquo;t look at the things you don&rsquo;t have, but look at what you already have.</p>
<ol start="7">
<li>Okage Samade</li>
</ol>
<p>A phrase that means something to the effect of &ldquo;I am good because of all the people that suppport me&rdquo;. Used when someone asks &ldquo;How are you?&rdquo;</p>
<ol start="8">
<li>Going to bed early and waking up early.</li>
</ol>
<p>This is absolutely true. I get up at 6 every day. At 10pm I usually start winding down for bed and lights are off at 23:00. I&rsquo;ve also gone through long periods of getting up at 4 or 3am, and I felt great doing so. I&rsquo;m currenlty using 6am because I sometimes have social engagements that prevent me from going to bed very early.</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202305162205</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=04wZNnjdURE">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=04wZNnjdURE</a></p>
<p>[[my ikigai and flow]]</p>
<p>[[invest-in-experiences-for-happiness]]</p>
<p>[[buddhist-practice]]</p>
<p>[[happiness]]</p>
<p>[[miniamlism]]</p>
<p>[[stoicism]]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invest In Experiences For Happiness</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/invest-in-experiences-for-happiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/invest-in-experiences-for-happiness/</guid>
      <description>Happiness, Hedonic Adjustment, Experiences This was a very good video. I can honestly say that I am very happy and content, and I lead a very fulfilling life. I do not usually watch this kind of &amp;ldquo;happiness&amp;rdquo; content because I&amp;rsquo;m already happy. But this video did give me some very important insights which have influenced the way I approach money and happiness.
Memories as Dividends The main takeaway for me is to prioritize creating memories by investing in experiences.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/840iXuXwE4Y" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<h1 id="happiness-hedonic-adjustment-experiences">Happiness, Hedonic Adjustment, Experiences</h1>
<p>This was a very good video. I can honestly say that I am very happy and content, and I lead a very fulfilling life. I do not usually watch this kind of &ldquo;happiness&rdquo; content because I&rsquo;m already happy. But this video did give me some very important insights which have influenced the way I approach money and happiness.</p>
<h1 id="memories-as-dividends">Memories as Dividends</h1>
<p>The main takeaway for me is to prioritize creating memories by investing in experiences. The author phrases it very well here:</p>
<p>&ldquo;When you buy a shiny new car, every time you use it that shine wears of just a little bit. You hedonically adjust. With a memory, every time you think about it, you experience joy. Your brain cements the pathway to that memory, and you relive it in your brain, experiencing feelings of happines or nostalgia.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Hedonic adjustment happens when you become used to the things you like, and you need to have bigger and better things in order to get the same satisfaction. The Stoics, among others, counteracted this with forced deprivation: eating plain bread for a few days will make you appreciate your customary food.</p>
<p>Another very clever point which Damien makes is to see money spent on experiences as dividends:</p>
<p>&ldquo;Experiences and memories in this way are like investments in happiness, because we can call on them to release the happiness hormones in our brains that make us feel good.&rdquo;</p>
<p>They can be seen as happiness dividends. You get the initial experience and you get to re-live it again and again. And the best thing is that you don&rsquo;t hedonically adjust to these memories.</p>
<p>This definitely made me re-think my approach to fincancial happiness and independence. I am definitely going to prioritize experiences a lot more in the future.</p>
<h1 id="other-takeaways">Other Takeaways</h1>
<ul>
<li>Variety and anticipation of events or smaller purchases provides a large portion of the happiness, rather than the purchase itself</li>
<li>Make many smaller purchases rather than one big purchase</li>
<li>Take short weekend holidays rather than a big expensive 4 week holiday</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="norway">Norway</h1>
<p>A case in point is my upcoming trip to Norway. Ever since I decided on the date for the trip, I noticed my energy has increased because I&rsquo;m excited about the trip. I&rsquo;m getting a lot of joy out of the anticipation: I&rsquo;m reading up on areas to visit, going through all of my outdoor gear, and getting out into nature more because I want to connect to that Norwegian part of me. This is all rooted very deeply within me because I lived there for 9 years, and the anticipation of returning to Norway for a short time gives me so much joy.</p>
<p>By taking time off and purchasing the necesseties for my trip, I&rsquo;m investing in experiences that will create memories which in turn will provide me more happiness in the future as dividends.</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202305152005</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=840iXuXwE4Y">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=840iXuXwE4Y</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Ran 10k For The First Time Today</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/running-first-10k/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/running-first-10k/</guid>
      <description>I ran 10k for the first time in my life today.
I ran to the beach and back in Heemskerk on hardened forest roads, listening to the birds and feeling the spring sun on my face. I felt great and had a smile on my face most of the time. Lots of interesting thoughts popping up in the mind as I run and reflect. Hardly noticed that 77 minutes went by because I was having such a good time.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I ran 10k for the first time in my life today.</p>
<p>I ran <a href="https://www.tumblr.com/mischavandenburg/717301155801235456/went-to-heemskerk-today-broke-my-running-record?source=share">to the beach and back in Heemskerk</a> on hardened forest roads, listening to the birds and feeling the spring sun on my face. I felt great and had a smile on my face most of the time. Lots of interesting thoughts popping up in the mind as I run and reflect. Hardly noticed that 77 minutes went by because I was having such a good time.</p>
<p>
  <img loading="lazy" src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/c2a5ec4a82684e3419ae336dbe388e6f/0c473022c40cc8ca-36/s1280x1920/8f0a174f159bd1445c7529cabed3a415d31f7147.jpg" alt=""  /></p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202305141605</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Having Fun While Running And Exploring</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/running-exploring-fun/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/running-exploring-fun/</guid>
      <description>If you would have told me 5 years, 3 years, 1 year, or even 3 months ago, that one day I would be 50 minutes into a run with a big beaming smile on my face, I would have never believed you, but today it happened.
My base building schedule is giving me good results. I did this week&amp;rsquo;s long run this morning and it was 7 minutes longer than last week&amp;rsquo;s long run.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you would have told me 5 years, 3 years, 1 year, or even 3 months ago, that one day I would be 50 minutes into a run with a big beaming smile on my face, I would have never believed you, but today it happened.</p>
<p>My base building schedule is giving me good results. I did this week&rsquo;s long run this morning and it was 7 minutes longer than last week&rsquo;s long run. I ran 8.5 kilometres in 67 minutes.</p>
<p>And the best thing was: I was smiling. I was having fun. Running on an easy pace has been such a game changer for me. Sure, I&rsquo;m probably the slowest runner on earth. It&rsquo;s more like jogging, just a little bit faster than my speed when I do a brisk walk. But I&rsquo;m running. I&rsquo;m building a base, I&rsquo;m doing the first steps, and from here I can grow.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m also discovering another fun element to the sport: exploration. I moved to my current city less than a year ago and it is unexplored territory. I&rsquo;m now creating a network of nice runs and circuits for myself and I&rsquo;m discovering places I would never have discovered otherwise. Now that I&rsquo;m able to run longer distances, I can start exploring more. Just running on one direction for half and hour and seeing where I end up. Then I look for a nice way back, and this way I&rsquo;ve discoverd a few nice rounds already.</p>
<p>Today the sun was shining, it was 17 degrees, I did the longest run I&rsquo;ve ever done, and when I came back I felt good: energized, happy and satisfied. The endorphins where rushing through my body. Not exactly a &ldquo;runner&rsquo;s high&rdquo;, I think, but definitely a sense of calm and achievement.</p>
<p>Last week my knee started to hurt during my 60 minute run, but this week I had no pain at all. My body is adjusting.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m coming to a point where I&rsquo;m starting to fall in love with running. I just pray I won&rsquo;t run into injuries!</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202305071305</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcast Notes: Responding To Stress With Eating</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/stress-eating/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/stress-eating/</guid>
      <description>I always thought everybody responded to stress by eating more. I was surprised to learn that many people actually stop eating when they are stressed out. This seems totally foreign to me, and this might also be why I have always been overweight.
Huberman Podcast Notes: Stress &amp;amp; Stress Related Eating Dr. Elissa Epel: Control Stress for Healthy Eating, Metabolism &amp;amp; Aging
Stress takes enormous amoutns of resources in the body Especially ATP There is a well documented relationship between stress response and obesity.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I always thought everybody responded to stress by eating more. I was surprised to learn that many people actually stop eating when they are stressed out. This seems totally foreign to me, and this might also be why I have always been overweight.</p>
<h1 id="huberman-podcast-notes-stress--stress-related-eating">Huberman Podcast Notes: Stress &amp; Stress Related Eating</h1>
<p>Dr. Elissa Epel: Control Stress for Healthy Eating, Metabolism &amp; Aging</p>
<ul>
<li>Stress takes enormous amoutns of resources in the body</li>
<li>Especially ATP</li>
</ul>
<p>There is a well documented relationship between stress response and obesity. Many obese people have a higher stress response, and they have become accustomed to dealing with this stress response through eating.</p>
<p>Manifests as huge cravings for food which can be nearly impossible to manage, leading to binge eating.</p>
<p>There are two types of people: people who stop eating when stressed and people who start to crave when stressed.</p>
<p>(I am definitely in the second cateogry without a doubt.)</p>
<p>These people have problems with satiety, cannot feel satiated and have eating disorders. They benefit from mindful eating practices and getting in touch with the physiological response to food.</p>
<p>Elon Musk has been on a prescriptive drug recently and lost a lot of weight.</p>
<h2 id="interventions-for-binge-eating">Interventions For Binge Eating</h2>
<p>The compulsive drive to eat is one of the strongest there can be once that pathway has developed.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Separating emotions from hunger</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Labeling my hunger from 1 to 10</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Is it hunger or is it boredom? Check-in before you eat</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Ride the craving</strong></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Go for walk</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Do pushups</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Get away from food</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Creating safe environments where you don&rsquo;t have risky foods (already doing this)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Body scans are very effictive to reducing craving</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Post its and phone reminders to do check-ins</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Checking the body, slow breathing</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Slow movement. qigong, yoga, slow walking</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202305070705</p>
<p>Dr. Elissa Epel: Control Stress for Healthy Eating, Metabolism &amp; Aging:</p>
<p><a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/dr-elissa-epel-control-stress-for-healthy-eating-metabolism/id1545953110?i=1000607079878">https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/dr-elissa-epel-control-stress-for-healthy-eating-metabolism/id1545953110?i=1000607079878</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Power of Writing</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/power-of-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/power-of-writing/</guid>
      <description>Ah, writing. It&amp;rsquo;s one of the skills that I&amp;rsquo;ve consistently been praised for throughout my life. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty good at it, and I think that&amp;rsquo;s because I enjoy it. It led me to getting an academic degree in English Literature and Culture, simply because I was following the things I was naturally good at.
However, just like any other skill, you can only become better at it through consistent practice. This morning I read a wonderful little blog post on writing regularly, and I was touched by his words:</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ah, writing. It&rsquo;s one of the skills that I&rsquo;ve consistently been praised for throughout my life. I&rsquo;m pretty good at it, and I think that&rsquo;s because I enjoy it. It led me to getting an academic degree in English Literature and Culture, simply because I was following the things I was naturally good at.</p>
<p>However, just like any other skill, you can only become better at it through consistent practice. This morning I read a wonderful little blog post <a href="https://herman.bearblog.dev/on-writing-regularly/">on writing regularly</a>, and I was touched by his words:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Similarly, some people believe that the art of writing is a skill that can be summoned on a whim, like a genie emerging from a lamp with a flourish of creative brilliance. In my experience, however, writing is more akin to the labour of a blacksmith, hamming words into shape through the heat and sweat of regular practise.</p>
</blockquote>
<h1 id="daily-practice">Daily Practice</h1>
<p>One way to gain more experience is to start keeping a daily journal. I&rsquo;ve always kept some notebook or other, jotting down thoughts and ideas as they came along sporadically. But it was only in July 2020 that I started <a href="https://www.artofmanliness.com/character/behavior/30-days-to-a-better-man-day-8-start-a-journal/">to keep a daily journal</a> and writing regularly. I started out writing by hand. I was in at an interesting place in life: I was spending two years in a Buddhist monastery, and after settling down for a couple of months, the intensive meditation practice was releasing all sorts of things in the mind and body, and I started to write them all down. I&rsquo;m still convinced that starting this habit has been one of the most important and beneficial decisions of my life.</p>
<p>It is so simple, but extremely effective. And you don&rsquo;t have to be doing anything special, or be in a special place. Just keeping a daily journal where you note down the things you did that day in a small pocket book is enough to get the habit going. Soon you will find that you will get the urge to write more. After several years of daily journaling, sometimes all I write is &ldquo;It&rsquo;s been a pretty good day&rdquo;. And that&rsquo;s it for that day. Sometimes I write several pages worth of thoughts, ideas and these longer writings often have powerful effects.</p>
<h1 id="the-power-of-writing">The Power Of Writing</h1>
<p>Sometimes I&rsquo;ll be struggling with something, and I&rsquo;ll be at a loss of what to do. The thoughts just keep whirling about aimlessly and no solution to the particular problem at hand seems to emerge from the chaos. Whenever I am in such a situation, I sit down, close my eyes, observe what is going on, and I start to write. I write it all down. The thoughts, the associations that these thoughts generate, and the effects they are having. I write down exactly how I feel. Attaching words to the feelings that I&rsquo;m experiencing mentally and physically. &ldquo;I feel a contraction in my lower abdomen&rdquo;. &ldquo;I&rsquo;m angry, and it manifests as a hot feeling on my forehead&rdquo;. And that&rsquo;s when the magic happens: something that I&rsquo;ve come to identify as &ldquo;The Power Of Writing&rdquo;.</p>
<p>Somehow the act of writing everything down will create structure in the chaos, and the solution to my problem wil emerge, often from very unexpected angles. Is it the fact that it is structured on paper? Or the fact that the visual representation of the contents of my mind enables me to apply structure to them? Is it the fact that I am moving my hands, adding bodily movement to my cognitive efforts?</p>
<p>I don&rsquo;t have the exact answer, but all I know is that it works for me. Almost every time. And often when I don&rsquo;t expect it at all. I&rsquo;ll just be sitting and writing in my journal, writing down a particular challenge that I&rsquo;m facing that day. And somehow some solution appears out of the blue. Whenever this happens, I always smile and write down: &ldquo;The Power of Writing&rdquo;.</p>
<h1 id="mindfulness">Mindfulness</h1>
<p>Even though I might not know the exact answer, I&rsquo;m certain that it is very closely related to mindfulness. Becoming more mindful through meditation and present moment awareness is the key to happiness in my opnion. I developed a mindfulness practice out of writing by creating this ritual where I sit down and identify what is going on and writing it down. In essence, I&rsquo;m forcing myself to be mindful, and to attach words to my mental and bodily experience. I&rsquo;m getting out of my own way and letting my mind solve the challenge all by itself.</p>
<p>You know what? It&rsquo;s happening right now! The Power of Writing. I hadn&rsquo;t been able to clearly capture in words what the mechanism behind the Power of Writing was, but as I was writing this article, it became obvious to me that it must be mindfulness underlying it all. So I&rsquo;m just going to leave it as it is. This is a perfect example of what you will find in my private zettelkasten. I wrote all of this in one sitting, with minimal editing. Just stream of conciousness, writing it down. And I finished with a wonderful realization.</p>
<p>I feel grateful, satsified and happy. There is also a pleasant tingling at the top of my neck, and an energy rising up through my feet. I hope that this might help someone else one day, and inspire someone to pick up the habit of writing.</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202305012005</p>
<p><a href="https://herman.bearblog.dev/on-writing-regularly/">https://herman.bearblog.dev/on-writing-regularly/</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🍎 My Weight Loss Journey And Current Goal 📉</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/weight-loss-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/weight-loss-journey/</guid>
      <description>I started my weight loss journey in December 2021 on 97,7kg and steadily dropped weight over the following year.
I achieved this by intermittent fasting and cutting out junk food as the first main intervention. I was already used to eating only 8 hours a day, but I experimented with shortening this window and doing 36 hour or 48 hour fasts.
Eventually I plateaued, and there was no way around it: I needed to start tracking calories strictly.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I started my weight loss journey in December 2021 on 97,7kg and steadily dropped weight over the following year.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/weightloss1.png" type="" alt=""  /></p>
<p>I achieved this by intermittent fasting and cutting out junk food as the first main intervention. I was already used to eating only 8 hours a day, but I experimented with shortening this window and doing 36 hour or 48 hour fasts.</p>
<p>Eventually I plateaued, and there was no way around it: I needed to start tracking calories strictly. I made a habit of weighing all of my food and entering it to an app (YAZIO). Periods of weight loss strictly correlate with my adherence to this practice.</p>
<p>The weight loss plateaued in 2022/2023.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/weightloss2.png" type="" alt=""  /></p>
<p>Even though I kept bouncing back up when I reached 76kg, I&rsquo;m still really satisfied that I managed to keep the weight off so far.According to Layne Norton in his book &ldquo;Fat Loss Forever&rdquo;, only 5% of people who undertake weight loss journeys actually manage to keep the weight off.</p>
<p>The main intervention for me here is to weigh myself daily. I&rsquo;ve gone from periods where I was strictly counting calories to periods where I was eyeballing things and trying to eat intuitively, leading to weight gain. But as soon as I started creeping to the 80kg mark, I knew I had to reign myself in again.</p>
<h1 id="current-goal">Current Goal</h1>
<p>Although I&rsquo;m happy I&rsquo;m managing to keep the weight off, I&rsquo;m not satisfied with my current weight.  My goal is to reach 10% body fat. I realized that simply &ldquo;losing weight&rdquo; was not going to cut it anymore because I kept bouncing back up. I needed to become more intentional about my weight loss.</p>
<p>I did some insightful research on goal setting and realized that I needed to set a clear goal within a timeframe and track the progress towards that goal. <a href="https://hubermanlab.com/the-science-of-setting-and-achieving-goals/">Huberman&rsquo;s Podcast episode on goal setting</a> was very enlightening here.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/weightloss3.png" type="" alt=""  /></p>
<p>Again my weight creeped up from 76kg to 80kg and I decided I had enough.</p>
<p>Since my breakpoint always seems to be 76kg, I set my goal to 75kg within a time frame of 2 months.</p>
<p>My starting weight was 78.6kg and this morning I weighed in at 77.3kg. So far it&rsquo;s working, it&rsquo;s about 0,5kg a week which is a healthy amount to lose in a week&rsquo;s time.</p>
<p>I made this little sheet which hangs on my kitchen cupboard, and every day I mark whether I adhered to my calorie target of 1700kcal +/- 100kcal. The squares indicate a day where I do a 500kcal fasting day.</p>
<h2 id="current-weight-loss-interventions">Current Weight Loss Interventions</h2>
<ul>
<li>Calorie target: 1700kcal</li>
<li>Two meals a day in a 4 hour eating window</li>
<li>20 hours of fasting a day</li>
<li>Strictly tracking all calories, even when overeating</li>
<li>5:2 pattern: two days of fasting a week where I eat a small meal of 500 calories</li>
<li>Running 5+ times a week</li>
<li>Two <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zkY6MM_dLo4&amp;t=18s&amp;pp=ygUJdGFvIHJpbmdz">ring workouts</a> a week</li>
</ul>
<p>When I list them all out, it seems extreme that I need this many interventions to lose those last few kilograms of fat. But apparently it is all necessary. If/when I start losing more than 0.5kg a week I&rsquo;ll know I can reduce the intensity by increasing my calorie target.</p>
<h2 id="accountability">Accountability</h2>
<p>When I made this sheet I shared it with my brother and a few friends for external accountability. So far I&rsquo;ve just been doing my journey alone, but as I got stuck at around 77kg, I upped the ante and started to involve others. It really helps to stick with the program. It would be very embarassing to make this kind of commitment and not sticking with it.</p>
<p>Now that I&rsquo;m two weeks in, and the results are starting to show, I decided to make it completely public and post it on my blog. So we&rsquo;ll see in two months if I&rsquo;m making a fool out of myself or not 🥲</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202304300804</p>
<p><a href="https://hubermanlab.com/the-science-of-setting-and-achieving-goals/">https://hubermanlab.com/the-science-of-setting-and-achieving-goals/</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zkY6MM_dLo4&amp;t=18s&amp;pp=ygUJdGFvIHJpbmdz">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zkY6MM_dLo4&amp;t=18s&amp;pp=ygUJdGFvIHJpbmdz</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Fat-Loss-Forever-Lose-KEEP/dp/1794510109">https://www.amazon.com/Fat-Loss-Forever-Lose-KEEP/dp/1794510109</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Base Training For Running: Time Instead Of Distance</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/base-training-running/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/base-training-running/</guid>
      <description>I started running on the 13th of February 2023. I ran 1.2 kilometres in 9 minutes. Slowly I built it up to my first 5k which I ran on the 23th of March 2023.
After I discovered a new potential within me now that I lost so much weight, I felt I needed some more structure towards my running training. Reddit, as always, comes to the rescue. On the r/running subreddit I discovered base training.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I started running on the 13th of February 2023. I ran 1.2 kilometres in 9 minutes. Slowly I built it up to my first 5k which I ran on the 23th of March 2023.</p>
<p>After I discovered a new potential within me now that I lost so much weight, I felt I needed some more structure towards my running training. Reddit, as always, comes to the rescue. On the r/running subreddit I discovered <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/running/comments/3bckeh/base_training_a_guide_to_your_foundation_to/">base training.</a></p>
<p>I focused completely on the <em>distance ran</em> while slowly working my way up to 5 kilometres. Base training, however, made me focus on the <em>duration</em> of the runs. This was quite an eye opener and changed my perspective.</p>
<p>The idea is that the duration is much more important for beginners because they experience  more stress on the body while running. An experienced runner might finish 10 kilometres in 30 minutes, but a beginner will experience a lot more stress on the body doing 30 minutes of running on an easy pace because there are more foot strikes occurring and because the body is unadapted. The beginner first needs to build up strength in the legs and resistance in the joints and tissues.</p>
<p>So far it has been a good experience. I like the idea of running more often, but not pushing myself every single run. The schedule also allows for variation. Some days are easier than others, so it feels good to have the opportunity to go for only a short 30 minute run on the days where I&rsquo;m not feeling up to it.</p>
<p>Here are the results of my first week:</p>
<h2 id="week-16---1">Week 16 - 1</h2>
<ul>
<li>Easy Run 1 Mon 30min</li>
<li>Easy Run 2 Wed 43min</li>
<li>Easy Run 3 Thu 36,5min</li>
<li>Easy Run 4 Sun 43min</li>
<li>Long Run   Fri 50min</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Total distance: 20.59km</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="goal">Goal</h2>
<p>I currently don&rsquo;t have a particular goal in mind. I have a knee injury which started to flare up again when I started running. So far the body has adapted, and the knee stopped hurting. I&rsquo;m going to follow this program for 6 weeks, adding 5 minutes (or more if I feel good) per week to my long run, and see where this takes me.</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202304241704</p>
<p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/running/comments/3bckeh/base_training_a_guide_to_your_foundation_to/">https://www.reddit.com/r/running/comments/3bckeh/base_training_a_guide_to_your_foundation_to/</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Importance Of Rest And Meditation When Making Changes To Routine</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/importance-rest-changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/importance-rest-changes/</guid>
      <description>Over the past two months I&amp;rsquo;ve increased the amount of exercise quite a lot. Over the past year or so I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing Brazilian Jiu Jitsu 1-2x a week and going for a 30-90 minute walk every day.
After I started running in February I have quit BJJ and changed to running 5-6 times a week, 30-60 minutes of Ashtangha Yoga almost every day and two calisthenics workouts a week. For my calisthenics I use rings and I do squats in the gym .</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Over the past two months I&rsquo;ve increased the amount of exercise quite a lot. Over the past year or so I&rsquo;ve been doing Brazilian Jiu Jitsu 1-2x a week and going for a 30-90 minute walk every day.</p>
<p>After I started running in February I have quit BJJ and changed to running 5-6 times a week, 30-60 minutes of Ashtangha Yoga almost every day and two calisthenics workouts a week. For my calisthenics I use rings and I do squats in the gym .</p>
<p>In addition, I reduced my calories to 1700 calories a day spread over two meals, doing 20 hours of fasting a day. I have also eliminated all sugar from my diet.</p>
<p>The reason I needed to do this is because my weight loss has plateaued for several months and I have at least 3kg more fat to lose until I reach my goal of 10% body fat.</p>
<p>Most people know me as someone who is very productive and frugal with his time, and that&rsquo;s true. I&rsquo;m always studying, writing, creating or learning in my free time. There is little to no time for girls and video games, I&rsquo;m on my purpose.</p>
<p>Yet I am also aware of the need of rest and relaxation. I haven&rsquo;t written much about it on my blog, and this will probably change in the time to come, but I am an established meditator and have a very solid mindfulness practice. I&rsquo;ll notice very quickly when I get out of balance and fortunately my practice has provided me with the wisdom to know what to do to bring things back into balance again.</p>
<p>Having introduced an increased amount of exercise and mental stress due to caloric restriction, I saw I needed to take a few steps back and allow my body and mind to adjust to these changes. I was already on caloric restriction and fasting 18 hours a day, but still I noticed I needed time to adjust.</p>
<p>To adjust I allowed myself to take a break from evening tech study and homelabbing and read some fiction instead, and I increased my meditation practice. Stilling the mind with breath meditation is helping me to deal with very intense food cravings. Quitting sugar is definitely no walk in the park.</p>
<p>I have made these kinds of changes many times before, and I know that after a while my body and mind are used to it and I can go back to my old routine again. Having a daily meditation practice gives me the tools to check in with myself. I am very grateful to myself that I put in the hard work over the past 6 years to get an established daily practice. I am also extremely grateful to my teacher and the Buddhist community who supported me while I spent time in a monastery in Norway.</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202304242004</p>
<p>[[buddhist-practice]]</p>
<p>[[meditation]]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcast Notes: Dopamine and Motivation - Huberman</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/dopamine-and-motivation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/dopamine-and-motivation/</guid>
      <description>Dopamine Listened to an interesting podcast on Dopamine by Andrew Huberman. I always enjoy his content because he is completely driven by science, not by personal opinion. He is truly objective as far as I can tell.
Dopamine is often misunderstood. It is not necessarily associated with good feelings after you pursue an activity. It is more related to motivation to engage in certain behaviours.
Rewards Scientists did an experiment where they observed children of kindergarten age, and later reproduced this in adults.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="dopamine">Dopamine</h1>
<p>Listened to <a href="https://hubermanlab.com/leverage-dopamine-to-overcome-procrastination-and-optimize-effort/">an interesting podcast on Dopamine</a> by Andrew Huberman. I always enjoy his content because he is completely driven by science, not by personal opinion. He is truly objective as far as I can tell.</p>
<p>Dopamine is often misunderstood. It is not necessarily associated with good feelings after you pursue an activity. It is more related to motivation to engage in certain behaviours.</p>
<h1 id="rewards">Rewards</h1>
<p>Scientists did an experiment where they observed children of kindergarten age, and later reproduced this in adults. The children were monitored during school days, where they had blocks of structured time and free time. During structured time their activities were managed. They had to sing or write, for example. Then they had blocks of free time where they could do whatever activity they liked.</p>
<p>They observed what activity the children liked to do in their free time, and then started to reward these children for their work. For example, if the children liked to draw in their free time, the researches started giving them gold stars and other praise for their work.</p>
<p>Then the researches removed the reward for the activity, and interestingly, the children and adults started showing less interest and enjoyment in the activity because they were lacking the reward.Note that this is the activity that they liked to do in their free time prior to the experiment.</p>
<p>This all has to do with the nature of dopamine, dopamine baselines and peaks.</p>
<p>Huberman explains this with a metaphor of a pool. In the pool you have waves, and the waves have peaks and troughs. At the peaks, your dopamine is high, but they are inevitably followed by troughs: dips in dopamine, which lead to low energy and low motivation.</p>
<p>Then there is the baseline of dopamine: the amount of water in the pool. The baseline is the relative point to which the peaks and throughs are determined.</p>
<p>So it is important that you don&rsquo;t reward yourself for activities that you are doing. Don&rsquo;t reward yourself too much when you achieve a fitness or study goal. You will feel good after the event, but you will end up in a through. Being in the trough means feeling demotivated, leading to procrastination.</p>
<h1 id="getting-out-of-the-trough">Getting Out Of The Trough</h1>
<p>The good news is that the system will reset itself after experiencing highs or lows due to rewards.Getting out of the trough happens automatically, but you can influence the rate at which you climb out of it.</p>
<p>Let&rsquo;s say you are not motivated to study. You&rsquo;ll need to do something which is more painful. Something that&rsquo;s even harder to do. Whatever feels harder to do in the moment than the activity that you <em>should</em> be doing. Do something that makes you feel uncomfortable.</p>
<h2 id="tactics">Tactics</h2>
<ul>
<li>exercise for 1 minute</li>
<li>do something that really sucks
<ul>
<li>cold water</li>
<li>anything that makes you cringe</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>leverage something that&rsquo;s painful</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="the-holy-grail-of-motivation">The Holy Grail Of Motivation</h1>
<p>The holy grail of motivation: not needing any external reward, but enjoying the activity itself that is leading you towards your goal. For example, enjoying running training in pursuit of a marathon goal. Enjoying coding and doing coding exercises in pursuit of becoming a software engineer.</p>
<p>I feel very fortunate that I succeeded at turning my passion into my career. The journey itself is fun. I enjoy coding, and that activity is taking me closer towards the goal of becoming a good software engineer and the ability to contribute to open source.</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202303311903</p>
<p><a href="https://hubermanlab.com/leverage-dopamine-to-overcome-procrastination-and-optimize-effort/">https://hubermanlab.com/leverage-dopamine-to-overcome-procrastination-and-optimize-effort/</a></p>
<p>[[my ikigai and flow]]</p>
<p>[[coding]]</p>
<p>[[devops]]</p>
<p>[[career]]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exercise Stimulates Creativity And Motivation</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/exercise-stimulates-creativity-and-motivation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/exercise-stimulates-creativity-and-motivation/</guid>
      <description>I noticed multiple times now that during my workouts my mind is generating lots of new ideas for coding projects or blog posts. It is a well known fact that walking stimulates areas in the brain that which will in turn stimulate creativity. But I&amp;rsquo;m noticing that it starts to happen with strength workouts as well.
Although I don&amp;rsquo;t struggle with the motivation to get myself to the gym, I sometimes feel &amp;ldquo;guilty&amp;rdquo; for not spending that time on coding or studying.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I noticed multiple times now that during my workouts my mind is generating lots of new ideas for coding projects or blog posts. It is a well known fact that walking stimulates areas in the brain that which will in turn stimulate creativity. But I&rsquo;m noticing that it starts to happen with strength workouts as well.</p>
<p>Although I don&rsquo;t struggle with the motivation to get myself to the gym, I sometimes feel &ldquo;guilty&rdquo; for not spending that time on coding or studying. I&rsquo;m realizing now that this is a very irrational train of thought.</p>
<p>Exercise actually stimulates my creativity and will help generating new ideas or help me understand concepts better in the unconscious. It is also massively beneficial for health and general well being. When general well-being is enhanced I&rsquo;ll also be able to focus better and absorb information more quickly.</p>
<p>I should re-frame my thinking and actually put exercise as priority number 1. Exercise time is never wasted time. It indirectly contributes to my productivity and coding endeavours as well.</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202304011104</p>
<p>[[exercise]]</p>
<p>[[health]]</p>
<p>[[focus]]</p>
<p>[[productivity]]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I ran 5K for the first time in my life!</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/ran-5km/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/ran-5km/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I reached a significant milestone. I ran my first 5K!
I&amp;rsquo;ve always been on the heavy side. I did a lot of weightlifting from age 18 to around 27 and I was always rather bulky, but very strong. This meant I was very good at working in the woods or helping people move house, but I&amp;rsquo;ve never been able to do any running or endurance because my knees would start protesting very quickly.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday I reached a significant milestone. I ran my first 5K!</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve always been on the heavy side. I did a lot of weightlifting from age 18 to around 27 and I was always rather bulky, but very strong. This meant I was very good at working in the woods or helping people move house, but I&rsquo;ve never been able to do any running or endurance because my knees would start protesting very quickly. However, I always admired endurance athletes and I had the desire to be able to run more than a few minutes without feeling the urge to die on the spot.</p>
<p>Over the past 1,5 years I lost 20kg (~44 pounds) so I decided to give it yet another try.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve never been this lightweight so I decided to give running another try. I started small with only 10 minutes but over the course of two months I built it up gradually.</p>
<p>Last week I ran 4km and it felt pretty good, so I just decided to push a little bit more and try for my goal of 5k, and it went well! It feels like quite an accomplishment to me.</p>
<p>Now that I lost all this weight running actually feels good, and it is liberating to discover a whole new area of exercise that I haven&rsquo;t explored yet: endurance. Looking back to my progress over a couple of months, I&rsquo;m curious how far I&rsquo;ll come and what my limits are.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing about Health and Personal Life</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/articles/write-about-health-personal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/articles/write-about-health-personal/</guid>
      <description>For weeks I&amp;rsquo;ve been debating with myself whether I should open up more on my blog. I spend my energy on two main pillars of my life: work and health, and up until now I&amp;rsquo;ve only been writing about work on my blog.
work I spend most of my waking hours sitting at my keyboard working on the command line: working, studying, coding, note taking. My life is focused around my career and I spend at at least 20 hours a week studying or learning new skills related to my career.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For weeks I&rsquo;ve been debating with myself whether I should open up more on my blog. I spend my energy on two main pillars of my life: work and health, and up until now I&rsquo;ve only been writing about work on my blog.</p>
<h1 id="work">work</h1>
<p>I spend most of my waking hours sitting at my keyboard working on the command line: working, studying, coding, note taking. My life is focused around my career and I spend at at least 20 hours a week studying or learning new skills related to my career. When I made my career change I started to write this blog to document the process and share my learning with anyone who might find it useful</p>
<h1 id="health">health</h1>
<p>The other main pillar of my life is health. In 2017 my father suffered two very serious hard attacks in close succession, and nearly losing him really woke me up and made me focus on my health.</p>
<p>I started eating a plant based diet and slowly reducing all the habits that were detrimental to my health, and increasing the activities that would promote my health. I quit drinking alcohol and I&rsquo;ve been sober for nearly 5 years now.</p>
<h2 id="mental-health">mental health</h2>
<p>I&rsquo;m also very interested in mental health. I&rsquo;ve done extensive studies of meditation and did several retreats. I&rsquo;ve had a daily meditation practice going for 6 years now. I have a teacher and enjoy conversing about this topic with friends that have similar interests. I also practice yoga several times a week.</p>
<h2 id="diet">diet</h2>
<p>I spend a lot of time reading and researching what the optimal diet is for me. I&rsquo;ve done a lot of experimentation. Not only what I eat, but also when I eat has been a subject of scrutiny for years now. I&rsquo;ve been on some form of intermittent fasting protocol since 2015, and I&rsquo;m currently eating only one meal a day.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MkuWE4QNuo0">Caloric restriction</a> has been shown to extend lifespan in many different organisms and I find it very intriguing. I&rsquo;ve been on a weight loss journey since late 2021 and I find that restricting my calories gives me all sorts of benefits.</p>
<h2 id="sleep">sleep</h2>
<p>My life changed when I read Matt Walker&rsquo;s book &ldquo;Why We Sleep&rdquo; and I&rsquo;ve focused on sleep hygiene ever since. My average sleep over the last year is 7 hours a night (logged by my iWatch).</p>
<h2 id="exercise">exercise</h2>
<p>I recently ran <a href="/zet/ran-5km">my first 5k</a> and I&rsquo;m about to embark on a whole new exercise journey where I&rsquo;ll be exploring my endurance limits.</p>
<h1 id="blog">blog</h1>
<p>All of the topics above are interests of mine and I spent a lot of time researching them. I listen to podcasts, read books, discuss them with friends. And most importantly: I keep notes about them.</p>
<p>So if I&rsquo;m happy to publish all of my work related notes with the world, why should I not share my other interests as well? I spend so much time gathering all this information and writing notes about them, and I feel that it might be useful to others who don&rsquo;t wish to plough through all of the material and would like to read summaries of the information.</p>
<h2 id="there-are-a-few-reasons-why-ive-been-hesitant-to-do-so">There are a few reasons why I&rsquo;ve been hesitant to do so.</h2>
<h3 id="seo">seo</h3>
<p>I used to have websites that marketed products, and from those years of optimizing for sales I&rsquo;ve gained some ingrained habits. These include keeping websites centered around one topic and repeating keywords throughout articles.</p>
<p>This blog was never intended for any sales or marketing, so I haven&rsquo;t been writing with any SEO in mind which has been liberating, frankly. But I find that these ingrained habits have stopped me from broadening my scope for the blog.</p>
<h3 id="centralization">centralization</h3>
<p>But keeping the website centered focused on one area has been a sticking point. I&rsquo;ve always had the reader in mind, but also for selfish reasons. Colleagues and managers have pointed out that my blog is an excellent supplement to my CV. When I switched jobs recently, one hiring manager even offered me a job with a good salary solely based on my CV, my blog and one phone conversation.</p>
<p>Readers of my blog might not necessarily be interested reading about my opinions and notes on health and exercise.</p>
<h2 id="its-my-blog">It&rsquo;s my blog!</h2>
<p>In the end I decided to start writing more about my personal life and health interests. The whole point of starting my own website was to have the <strong>freedom of writing about what I want without limitations</strong>. I could have just written all my stuff on LinkedIn on other social media, but then you don&rsquo;t own any of the content. What happens if you get banned for some reason? Or hacked? All your work is gone, which is why I chose my own website written in markdown files stored locally on my disk and hosted on GitHub.</p>
<p>From the beginning I made sure to use a system where readers can filter on tags if they are looking for specific content. And honestly, who reads my stuff anyway? I know of one person who regularly reads my stuff (Hi, F!), but my blog is mostly a relaxing creative activity. I like scrolling through it and seeing the thoughts I captured, and to see it grow over time. And it helps me tremendously with learning information, because writing about topics is a great way to test whether I really understand the matter.</p>
<p>Including my notes on other topics such as health and exercise will make my blog less focused and centralized around DevOps and tech, but it will reveal more about me as a person, and it will be fun to look back in the future and see my progress in these other areas as well. And I think that summaries of the research I do on these topics can actually be of use to others.</p>
<p>So I&rsquo;ve decided to remove all limitations on topics for my blog and to just write about everything that I feel like publishing and sharing with the world.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
