<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Health on Mischa van den Burg</title>
    <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/health/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Health on Mischa van den Burg</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Apps with web interfaces win any day, switching to MyFitnessPal</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/myfitnesspal-web-interface/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/myfitnesspal-web-interface/</guid>
      <description>Recently I was comparing apps for navigation (TopoGPS and Outdooractive). Both apps are great, but the main perk of Outdooractive is that it has a web interface. You can plan routes from your computer and access them on the iPhone app, but TopoGPS is on the iPhone only.
The app I probably have the most interaction with during the day is my calorie tracking app. I&amp;rsquo;ve been using YAZIO for about two years and it has been satisfactory, but there were a few small annoyances to the app and I was never completely satisfied with.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Recently I was comparing apps for navigation (TopoGPS and Outdooractive). Both apps are great, but the main perk of Outdooractive is that it has a web interface. You can plan routes from your computer and access them on the iPhone app, but TopoGPS is on the iPhone only.</p>
<p>The app I probably have the most interaction with during the day is my calorie tracking app. I&rsquo;ve been using YAZIO for about two years and it has been satisfactory, but there were a few small annoyances to the app and I was never completely satisfied with.</p>
<p>A missing web interface being one of them. I&rsquo;d love to be able to sit behind my 4K screen and plan out the week&rsquo;s nutrition from there instead of using the clunky copy function on my phone.</p>
<p>Enter MyFitnessPal. It has a web interface. It has charts and graphs. Me happy.</p>
<p>Why didn&rsquo;t I chose this app when I began using an app for my phone? I remember trying it out, but I was unhappy with it somehow. I remember something about the food database not containing the foods I was eating at the time. I&rsquo;ve been doing some testing and up until now I haven&rsquo;t had to add any foods.</p>
<p>I have a year&rsquo;s subscription on YAZIO until March so it is a bit of a waste, but I&rsquo;m already sold on the web interface of MFP. I have one free month of premium and I&rsquo;ll make the decision then.</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202310011810</p>
<p>[[Health]]</p>
<p>[[diet]]</p>
<p>[[vegan]]</p>
<p>[[weight-loss]]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Running Record! Ran 12km today</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/running-record-12km/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/running-record-12km/</guid>
      <description>New week, new record! For the first time in my life I ran 12 kilometers, and immediately another 10k PR!
This morning it was time for my long run, and while I was drinking my coffee I decided to watch a running technique video again to see what I could improve. Lately I have mainly focused on my heart rate and steps per minute, but today I focused more on maintaining a better posture by sticking out my chest a bit more and leaning forward a bit more.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>New week, new record! For the first time in my life I ran 12 kilometers, and immediately another 10k PR!</p>
<p>This morning it was time for my long run, and while I was drinking my coffee I decided to watch a running technique video again to see what I could improve. Lately I have mainly focused on my heart rate and steps per minute, but today I focused more on maintaining a better posture by sticking out my chest a bit more and leaning forward a bit more. The result was that I suddenly ran much faster and more relaxed without this resulting in a higher HR, and my steps per minute were also fine afterwards with 171SPM. These days I usually run around 6:30 but I’m really surprised that I was able to set both a distance record and a higher average speed without having to make any effort except constantly maintaining a better posture. “Running Tall” was the mantra that I kept coming back to when I noticed that I started to sink back.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/12km1.png" type="" alt=""  /></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/12km2.png" type="" alt=""  /></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/12km3.png" type="" alt=""  /></p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202307221107</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcast Notes: Interview With Eliud Kipchoge, The Fastest Marathon Runner In The World</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/podcast-kipchoge-marathon-running/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/podcast-kipchoge-marathon-running/</guid>
      <description>What I Learned from Kipchoge, the Fastest Marathon Runner in the World Kipchoge is not only a world-class athlete, but also a source of inspiration and wisdom for anyone who wants to improve their life. I recently listened to an interview with him on YouTube, and I was amazed by his insights on running, success, pain, discipline and happiness. Here are some of the key takeaways and a summary of what he shared.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="what-i-learned-from-kipchoge-the-fastest-marathon-runner-in-the-world">What I Learned from Kipchoge, the Fastest Marathon Runner in the World</h1>
<p>Kipchoge is not only a world-class athlete, but also a source of inspiration and wisdom for anyone who wants to improve their life. I recently listened to an interview with him on YouTube, and I was amazed by his insights on running, success, pain, discipline and happiness. Here are some of the key takeaways and a summary of what he shared.</p>
<h2 id="preparation-and-planning-is-the-key">Preparation and Planning is the Key</h2>
<p>Kipchoge believes that success does not come by chance, but by pure and clean planning in preparation. He follows a strict program and sticks to it to the letter. He writes down everything in his journal every day, and documents his progress and challenges. He also avoids distractions and focuses on his priorities.</p>
<p>I really appreciate his emphasis on planning everything out meticulously. You should approach your training with a clear goal and intention and make a plan to reach that goal. I also identify with his habit of writing everything down, of course. This is what I&rsquo;ve been practicing myself for several years now, and it is nice to see yet another highly successful person who also shares this habit.</p>
<h2 id="morning-routine">Morning Routine</h2>
<p>Kipchoge has a morning routine which is very similar to my own. He wakes up at 5:45 and is out running by 6:10. When he comes back he has a shower and has breakfast. Only when that is finished will he look at his phone and check his messages and emails.</p>
<p>I also run first thing in the morning. I really enjoy to have it done for the day, and I prefer to exercise on an empty stomach. I think I will try Kipchoge&rsquo;s routine of not looking at the phone until the morning rituals are finished. I tend to check the news and read messages before I go out on my run, and then I use the run to prepare for the day. I&rsquo;ll try to get out with a &ldquo;clean mind&rdquo; and see what happens this week.</p>
<h2 id="movement-leads-to-a-long-and-happy-life">Movement Leads to a Long and Happy Life</h2>
<p>Kipchoge sees running as the best movement and the key to life. He says that life is about movement, and if you move, that&rsquo;s how you have a good life. He runs every day, even when he does not feel like it, because he knows that running is not only good for his body, but also for his mind. He runs in a group of people, and enjoys the social aspect of running. He says that running in a group helps him to talk, exchange ideas and learn from others. He also encourages running as a family lifestyle, and says that running should be fun and enjoyable.</p>
<h2 id="pain-is-part-of-success">Pain is Part of Success</h2>
<p>Kipchoge smiles when he runs, even when he is feeling pain. He says that when he smiles while running, he is actually enjoying the pain. He explains that pain is where success is, and those who know how to handle pain will be successful and move up to another level. Kipchoge also says that training is not the same as competing, and that training happens at a slower pace where you can follow the pace of the group. But when he competes, he pushes himself to the limit and embraces the pain.</p>
<h2 id="vitamin-n">Vitamin N</h2>
<p>Kipchoge shares a simple but powerful advice: inject yourself with vitamin N. What is vitamin N? It stands for NO! Kipchoge says that you need to learn to say no to things that are not aligned with your goals and values. You also need to set your priorities right and avoid complaining. These three things will help you develop self-discipline and achieve your dreams.</p>
<h2 id="listening-to-podcasts">Listening to Podcasts</h2>
<p>When I started running I listened to music, but after I could run for more than 20 minutes, I started to see my runs as a form of active meditation. I deliberately avoid listening to music and podcasts so I can focus completely on the running experience and use the breath, body and movement as meditation objects. However, Kipchoge says that it is all right to listen to music or podcasts during easy runs. They will make the time pass by very quickly.</p>
<p>I hope you enjoyed this blog post and learned something from Kipchoge&rsquo;s wisdom. If you want to listen to the full interview, you can find it here:</p>


    
    <div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
      <iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/X4la2sHwZB0?autoplay=0&controls=1&end=0&loop=0&mute=0&start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video"
      ></iframe>
    </div>

<p>Links:</p>
<p>202307221407</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=X4la2sHwZB0">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=X4la2sHwZB0</a></p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202307221907</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcast Notes - Optimal Water Intake</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/optimal-hydration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/optimal-hydration/</guid>
      <description>Hydration Notes from Huberman Podcast For the first 10 hours of the day, consume 236ml for every hour awake
During exercise, follow Galpin equation: 2ml per kg of bodyweight every 15-20 minutes on average.
This does not mean you need to stop exercising and drink this amount. You can also consume it in a larger amount afterwards. It is recommended to drink during exercise though.
Use the normal recommendation to hydrate before exercise, this establishes a good baseline for heading into exercise.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="hydration-notes-from-huberman-podcast">Hydration Notes from Huberman Podcast</h1>
<p>For the first 10 hours of the day, consume 236ml for every hour awake</p>
<p>During exercise, follow Galpin equation: 2ml per kg of bodyweight every 15-20 minutes on average.</p>
<p>This does not mean you need to stop exercising and drink this amount. You can also consume it in a larger amount afterwards. It is recommended to drink during exercise though.</p>
<p>Use the normal recommendation to hydrate before exercise, this establishes a good baseline for heading into exercise.</p>
<h2 id="is-this-amount-of-water-on-top-of-the-baseline-hydration">Is this amount of water on top of the baseline hydration?</h2>
<p>If you exercise about an hour you can replace the number with the number from the Galpin equation.</p>
<p>In my case, 1 hour of exercise = 77 * 2 = 154ml every 20 minutes</p>
<p>154 * 3 = 462ml for 1 hour of exercise</p>
<h2 id="caffeine">Caffeine</h2>
<p>Offset caffeine drinks with a 2:1 water ratio.</p>
<p>So 1 240ml cup of coffee should be followed by 480ml of water.</p>
<h2 id="reducing-nightly-urination">Reducing Nightly Urination</h2>
<p>Urine secretion / filtration in the kidneys is highly dependent on the circadian rhythm.</p>
<p>It is normal to wake up once or twice to urinate during the night.</p>
<p>To reduce nighttime waking for urination:</p>
<ul>
<li>Ensure sufficient hydration during the day so you are not thirsty in the evening</li>
<li>Reduce fluid intake at night (provided you hydrated sufficiently during the day)</li>
<li>Consume no more than 180-240ml between 10 hours after waking and bedtime</li>
</ul>
<p>This means, waking up at 6am, only drink 1 cup of tea after 4pm.</p>
<p>But I drink 500ml at dinner time, so I should probably never drink after dinner from here on out, or just one cup of tea.</p>
<p>How quickly you secrete fluid is also partially determined by how quickly you drink that fluid. Gulping down a lot of fluid wil lead to quicker secretion.</p>
<h1 id="my-typical-day">My Typical Day</h1>
<p>1 hour exercise = 500ml</p>
<p>2 cups of coffee 500ml</p>
<p>10 hours = 2,4l</p>
<p>So I should be drinking about 3,25L in total a day!</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202305301905</p>
<p><a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/gb/podcast/huberman-lab/id1545953110?i=1000602925839">https://podcasts.apple.com/gb/podcast/huberman-lab/id1545953110?i=1000602925839</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovered MAF and Low Heart Rate Training</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/discovered-maf-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/discovered-maf-training/</guid>
      <description>Although I was already doing something very similar, yesterday I discovered MAF training through this video:
This video is super inspiring because he actually runs a 3 hour marathon while recording!
I was already doing base training for my running which I discovered through the r/running Reddit. Here you focus on time instead of distance and do many runs on low intensity throughout the week, and one long run where you go 5 minutes more every week.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Although I was already doing something very similar, yesterday I discovered MAF training through this video:</p>


    
    <div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
      <iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/P_VNQ6UIbS8?autoplay=0&controls=1&end=0&loop=0&mute=0&start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video"
      ></iframe>
    </div>

<p>This video is super inspiring because he actually runs a 3 hour marathon while recording!</p>
<p>I was already doing <a href="/zet/base-training-running/">base training for my running</a> which I discovered through the r/running Reddit. Here you focus on time instead of distance and do many runs on low intensity throughout the week, and one long run where you go 5 minutes more every week.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m now in week 6 of my base training schedule and I&rsquo;m progressing nicely. My long run went from 50 minutes to 86 minutes, and my weekly total distance has increased from 20,6km to 32,8km!</p>
<h1 id="maf-training">MAF Training</h1>
<p>MAF stands for Maximum Aerobic Function and was developed by Dr. Phil Maffetone.</p>
<p>It uses <a href="https://philmaffetone.com/180-formula/">the 180 formula</a> to calculate the maximum heart rate you should hit during your run. What wasn&rsquo;t obvious from all the other videos I watched, was that this maximum heart rate actually establishes a zone you should be training in.</p>
<p>I discovered this in Dr. Maffetone&rsquo;s Book:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Once a maximum aerobic heart rate is found, a training range from this heart rate to 10 beats below could be used as a training range. For example, if an athlete’s maximum aerobic heart rate is determined to be 155, that person’s aerobic training zone would be 145 to 155 bpm. However, the more training at 155, the quicker an optimal aerobic base will be developed.</p>
</blockquote>
<h1 id="current-situation">Current Situation</h1>
<p>I hadn&rsquo;t been paying much attention to my heart rate up until this point. I just used the guideline of &ldquo;conversational pace&rdquo;, and that runs should feel easy and enjoyable. However, I knew I was going to need metrics one day, so I diligently tracked my workouts using my iWatch SE from day 1.</p>
<p>Here are my current heart rate stats and zones:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/zones.jpg" type="" alt=""  /></p>
<p>Going through my recent runs, my average heart rate has been around 100-115bpm. For example:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/heart.png" type="" alt=""  /></p>
<h1 id="time-to-start-nerding-on-some-numbers">Time To Start Nerding On Some Numbers</h1>
<p>Using the 180 formula, I calculated that I should use 180 - 33 - 5 = 142 as a maximum heart rate for my endurance training, which gives me a training zone of 132-142bpm. This is about 15 beats higher than I was used to! And if you look at the zones that Apple calculated for me, you&rsquo;ll see that this almost perfectly matches my calculated Zone 2.</p>
<p>After I calculated my new target, I tried it out immediately this morning. Here is the result:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/firstmaf.jpg" type="" alt=""  /></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/firstmaf2.jpg" type="" alt=""  /></p>


<div class="strava-embed-placeholder" data-embed-type="activity" data-embed-id="9143184934"></div><script src="https://strava-embeds.com/embed.js"></script>


<p>This definitely felt very different! After some experimentation and keeping an eye on my heart rate rising and falling, I managed to find a pattern that kept it around 135bpm. It felt much more like running instead of jogging. And I was surprised that even though I was running quite a bit faster than I was used to, I could still maintain a conversation if I wanted to, so I was still at a conversational pace. I had just estimated my conversational pace a lot lower than I was capable of. This shows you the power of using metrics for training! It definitely pushed me to go a little harder, a little faster, even though I&rsquo;m stil doing &ldquo;easy running&rdquo;.</p>
<p>Towards the end my legs started to hurt quite a bit more than usual, it felt much more like a workout, even though I was not totally exhausted in the end. The previous run I shared had a pace of 7.41/km and this one was on 6.42/km, which is a lot faster.</p>
<p>I have come to a point where all these numbers are starting to make sense to me now and I can start tracking them. Especially the heart rate has been a real eye opener. Now I have a perfect gauge to use while training: something that will let me know whether I should put in some more effort or slow down.</p>
<p>Already I&rsquo;m getting so much joy of seeing the progress I&rsquo;ve made from week 1 to 6, and seeing the numbers increase. I&rsquo;m really falling in love with this sport in so many ways, it&rsquo;s perfect for a nerd like me!</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202305261305</p>
<p><a href="https://philmaffetone.com/180-formula/">https://philmaffetone.com/180-formula/</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=e5wgoTuJuF8">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=e5wgoTuJuF8</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Went on My First Camping Trip After Moving Back to NL From Norway</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/first-camping-trip-in-netherlands/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/first-camping-trip-in-netherlands/</guid>
      <description>It was a nice week. I had an extra day off on Asenscion day and I decided to go for a camping trip for the first time after I moved back to the Netherlands.
It was a great experience, and I wrote a couple of Tumblr posts with photos:
https://www.tumblr.com/mischavandenburg/718093517925367808/first-trip-in-the-netherlands-part-1?source=share
https://www.tumblr.com/mischavandenburg/718098930739593216/part-2?source=share
Links: 202305232005
[[outdoors]]</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It was a nice week. I had an extra day off on Asenscion day and I decided to go for a camping trip for the first time after I moved back to the Netherlands.</p>
<p>It was a great experience, and I wrote a couple of Tumblr posts with photos:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.tumblr.com/mischavandenburg/718093517925367808/first-trip-in-the-netherlands-part-1?source=share">https://www.tumblr.com/mischavandenburg/718093517925367808/first-trip-in-the-netherlands-part-1?source=share</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.tumblr.com/mischavandenburg/718098930739593216/part-2?source=share">https://www.tumblr.com/mischavandenburg/718098930739593216/part-2?source=share</a></p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202305232005</p>
<p>[[outdoors]]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8 Simple Japanese Habits</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/8-simple-japanese-habits/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/8-simple-japanese-habits/</guid>
      <description>Through YouTube I&amp;rsquo;ve been exposed to quite a bit of Japanese culture and I love many aspects of it. I love this list of habits, and I was surprised to see how many of them I already incorporate.
Clean the Toilet Many successful businessmen clean the toilet every day. It humbles you. Ajahn Chah also talks about this a lot. Check out &amp;ldquo;Toilets on the Path&amp;rdquo;. I&amp;rsquo;m also very focused on cleanliness and especially emphasize keeping my toilet clean.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[

    
    <div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
      <iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/04wZNnjdURE?autoplay=0&controls=1&end=0&loop=0&mute=0&start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video"
      ></iframe>
    </div>

<p>Through YouTube I&rsquo;ve been exposed to quite a bit of Japanese culture and I love many aspects of it. I love this list of habits, and I was surprised to see how many of them I already incorporate.</p>
<ol>
<li>Clean the Toilet</li>
</ol>
<p>Many successful businessmen clean the toilet every day. It humbles you. Ajahn Chah also talks about this a lot. Check out &ldquo;Toilets on the Path&rdquo;. I&rsquo;m also very focused on cleanliness and especially emphasize keeping my toilet clean. But I like the idea of cleaning it every day and I&rsquo;m going to give it a try.</p>
<ol start="2">
<li>Put your shoes away neatly</li>
</ol>
<p>Just look at how clean that looks in the video! Fortunately I also have a habit of putting them neatly on a rack I have.</p>
<ol start="3">
<li>Improve your posture</li>
</ol>
<p>Investing in my Herman Miller chair has been a huge improvement to my life, and combined with yoga my posture has improved a lot over the past few months. I walk more upright and find myself correcting posture more often than before.</p>
<ol start="4">
<li>Thanking for meals</li>
</ol>
<p>Being grateful for all people who were involved in making that meal. The farmers, the cooks, everybody.</p>
<p>Being grateful for life.</p>
<p>I can definitely improve on this and appreciate my food more.</p>
<ol start="5">
<li>Put the chair back after you use it</li>
</ol>
<p>Japanese people are very concerned with other people&rsquo;s feelings. Putting a chair back in a restaurant you will make the restaurant staff happy, for example. I&rsquo;m usually quite considerate about these things and generally want to make the world a better place. I have a habit of thinking, &ldquo;how can I make this person&rsquo;s day a little better?&rdquo;</p>
<ol start="6">
<li>Appreciate the things you already have</li>
</ol>
<p>Don&rsquo;t look at the things you don&rsquo;t have, but look at what you already have.</p>
<ol start="7">
<li>Okage Samade</li>
</ol>
<p>A phrase that means something to the effect of &ldquo;I am good because of all the people that suppport me&rdquo;. Used when someone asks &ldquo;How are you?&rdquo;</p>
<ol start="8">
<li>Going to bed early and waking up early.</li>
</ol>
<p>This is absolutely true. I get up at 6 every day. At 10pm I usually start winding down for bed and lights are off at 23:00. I&rsquo;ve also gone through long periods of getting up at 4 or 3am, and I felt great doing so. I&rsquo;m currenlty using 6am because I sometimes have social engagements that prevent me from going to bed very early.</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202305162205</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=04wZNnjdURE">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=04wZNnjdURE</a></p>
<p>[[My Ikigai]]</p>
<p>[[invest-in-experiences-for-happiness]]</p>
<p>[[buddhist-practice]]</p>
<p>[[happiness]]</p>
<p>[[miniamlism]]</p>
<p>[[stoicism]]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invest In Experiences For Happiness</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/invest-in-experiences-for-happiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/invest-in-experiences-for-happiness/</guid>
      <description>Happiness, Hedonic Adjustment, Experiences This was a very good video. I can honestly say that I am very happy and content, and I lead a very fulfilling life. I do not usually watch this kind of &amp;ldquo;happiness&amp;rdquo; content because I&amp;rsquo;m already happy. But this video did give me some very important insights which have influenced the way I approach money and happiness.
Memories as Dividends The main takeaway for me is to prioritize creating memories by investing in experiences.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[

    
    <div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
      <iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/840iXuXwE4Y?autoplay=0&controls=1&end=0&loop=0&mute=0&start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video"
      ></iframe>
    </div>

<h1 id="happiness-hedonic-adjustment-experiences">Happiness, Hedonic Adjustment, Experiences</h1>
<p>This was a very good video. I can honestly say that I am very happy and content, and I lead a very fulfilling life. I do not usually watch this kind of &ldquo;happiness&rdquo; content because I&rsquo;m already happy. But this video did give me some very important insights which have influenced the way I approach money and happiness.</p>
<h1 id="memories-as-dividends">Memories as Dividends</h1>
<p>The main takeaway for me is to prioritize creating memories by investing in experiences. The author phrases it very well here:</p>
<p>&ldquo;When you buy a shiny new car, every time you use it that shine wears of just a little bit. You hedonically adjust. With a memory, every time you think about it, you experience joy. Your brain cements the pathway to that memory, and you relive it in your brain, experiencing feelings of happines or nostalgia.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Hedonic adjustment happens when you become used to the things you like, and you need to have bigger and better things in order to get the same satisfaction. The Stoics, among others, counteracted this with forced deprivation: eating plain bread for a few days will make you appreciate your customary food.</p>
<p>Another very clever point which Damien makes is to see money spent on experiences as dividends:</p>
<p>&ldquo;Experiences and memories in this way are like investments in happiness, because we can call on them to release the happiness hormones in our brains that make us feel good.&rdquo;</p>
<p>They can be seen as happiness dividends. You get the initial experience and you get to re-live it again and again. And the best thing is that you don&rsquo;t hedonically adjust to these memories.</p>
<p>This definitely made me re-think my approach to fincancial happiness and independence. I am definitely going to prioritize experiences a lot more in the future.</p>
<h1 id="other-takeaways">Other Takeaways</h1>
<ul>
<li>Variety and anticipation of events or smaller purchases provides a large portion of the happiness, rather than the purchase itself</li>
<li>Make many smaller purchases rather than one big purchase</li>
<li>Take short weekend holidays rather than a big expensive 4 week holiday</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="norway">Norway</h1>
<p>A case in point is my upcoming trip to Norway. Ever since I decided on the date for the trip, I noticed my energy has increased because I&rsquo;m excited about the trip. I&rsquo;m getting a lot of joy out of the anticipation: I&rsquo;m reading up on areas to visit, going through all of my outdoor gear, and getting out into nature more because I want to connect to that Norwegian part of me. This is all rooted very deeply within me because I lived there for 9 years, and the anticipation of returning to Norway for a short time gives me so much joy.</p>
<p>By taking time off and purchasing the necesseties for my trip, I&rsquo;m investing in experiences that will create memories which in turn will provide me more happiness in the future as dividends.</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202305152005</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=840iXuXwE4Y">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=840iXuXwE4Y</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Ran 10k For The First Time Today</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/running-first-10k/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/running-first-10k/</guid>
      <description>I ran 10k for the first time in my life today.
I ran to the beach and back in Heemskerk on hardened forest roads, listening to the birds and feeling the spring sun on my face. I felt great and had a smile on my face most of the time. Lots of interesting thoughts popping up in the mind as I run and reflect. Hardly noticed that 77 minutes went by because I was having such a good time.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I ran 10k for the first time in my life today.</p>
<p>I ran <a href="https://www.tumblr.com/mischavandenburg/717301155801235456/went-to-heemskerk-today-broke-my-running-record?source=share">to the beach and back in Heemskerk</a> on hardened forest roads, listening to the birds and feeling the spring sun on my face. I felt great and had a smile on my face most of the time. Lots of interesting thoughts popping up in the mind as I run and reflect. Hardly noticed that 77 minutes went by because I was having such a good time.</p>
<p>
  <img loading="lazy" src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/c2a5ec4a82684e3419ae336dbe388e6f/0c473022c40cc8ca-36/s1280x1920/8f0a174f159bd1445c7529cabed3a415d31f7147.jpg" alt=""  /></p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202305141605</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Having Fun While Running And Exploring</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/running-exploring-fun/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/running-exploring-fun/</guid>
      <description>If you would have told me 5 years, 3 years, 1 year, or even 3 months ago, that one day I would be 50 minutes into a run with a big beaming smile on my face, I would have never believed you, but today it happened.
My base building schedule is giving me good results. I did this week&amp;rsquo;s long run this morning and it was 7 minutes longer than last week&amp;rsquo;s long run.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you would have told me 5 years, 3 years, 1 year, or even 3 months ago, that one day I would be 50 minutes into a run with a big beaming smile on my face, I would have never believed you, but today it happened.</p>
<p>My base building schedule is giving me good results. I did this week&rsquo;s long run this morning and it was 7 minutes longer than last week&rsquo;s long run. I ran 8.5 kilometres in 67 minutes.</p>
<p>And the best thing was: I was smiling. I was having fun. Running on an easy pace has been such a game changer for me. Sure, I&rsquo;m probably the slowest runner on earth. It&rsquo;s more like jogging, just a little bit faster than my speed when I do a brisk walk. But I&rsquo;m running. I&rsquo;m building a base, I&rsquo;m doing the first steps, and from here I can grow.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m also discovering another fun element to the sport: exploration. I moved to my current city less than a year ago and it is unexplored territory. I&rsquo;m now creating a network of nice runs and circuits for myself and I&rsquo;m discovering places I would never have discovered otherwise. Now that I&rsquo;m able to run longer distances, I can start exploring more. Just running on one direction for half and hour and seeing where I end up. Then I look for a nice way back, and this way I&rsquo;ve discoverd a few nice rounds already.</p>
<p>Today the sun was shining, it was 17 degrees, I did the longest run I&rsquo;ve ever done, and when I came back I felt good: energized, happy and satisfied. The endorphins where rushing through my body. Not exactly a &ldquo;runner&rsquo;s high&rdquo;, I think, but definitely a sense of calm and achievement.</p>
<p>Last week my knee started to hurt during my 60 minute run, but this week I had no pain at all. My body is adjusting.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m coming to a point where I&rsquo;m starting to fall in love with running. I just pray I won&rsquo;t run into injuries!</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202305071305</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Power of Writing</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/power-of-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/power-of-writing/</guid>
      <description>Ah, writing. It&amp;rsquo;s one of the skills that I&amp;rsquo;ve consistently been praised for throughout my life. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty good at it, and I think that&amp;rsquo;s because I enjoy it. It led me to getting an academic degree in English Literature and Culture, simply because I was following the things I was naturally good at.
However, just like any other skill, you can only become better at it through consistent practice. This morning I read a wonderful little blog post on writing regularly, and I was touched by his words:</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ah, writing. It&rsquo;s one of the skills that I&rsquo;ve consistently been praised for throughout my life. I&rsquo;m pretty good at it, and I think that&rsquo;s because I enjoy it. It led me to getting an academic degree in English Literature and Culture, simply because I was following the things I was naturally good at.</p>
<p>However, just like any other skill, you can only become better at it through consistent practice. This morning I read a wonderful little blog post <a href="https://herman.bearblog.dev/on-writing-regularly/">on writing regularly</a>, and I was touched by his words:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Similarly, some people believe that the art of writing is a skill that can be summoned on a whim, like a genie emerging from a lamp with a flourish of creative brilliance. In my experience, however, writing is more akin to the labour of a blacksmith, hamming words into shape through the heat and sweat of regular practise.</p>
</blockquote>
<h1 id="daily-practice">Daily Practice</h1>
<p>One way to gain more experience is to start keeping a daily journal. I&rsquo;ve always kept some notebook or other, jotting down thoughts and ideas as they came along sporadically. But it was only in July 2020 that I started <a href="https://www.artofmanliness.com/character/behavior/30-days-to-a-better-man-day-8-start-a-journal/">to keep a daily journal</a> and writing regularly. I started out writing by hand. I was in at an interesting place in life: I was spending two years in a Buddhist monastery, and after settling down for a couple of months, the intensive meditation practice was releasing all sorts of things in the mind and body, and I started to write them all down. I&rsquo;m still convinced that starting this habit has been one of the most important and beneficial decisions of my life.</p>
<p>It is so simple, but extremely effective. And you don&rsquo;t have to be doing anything special, or be in a special place. Just keeping a daily journal where you note down the things you did that day in a small pocket book is enough to get the habit going. Soon you will find that you will get the urge to write more. After several years of daily journaling, sometimes all I write is &ldquo;It&rsquo;s been a pretty good day&rdquo;. And that&rsquo;s it for that day. Sometimes I write several pages worth of thoughts, ideas and these longer writings often have powerful effects.</p>
<h1 id="the-power-of-writing">The Power Of Writing</h1>
<p>Sometimes I&rsquo;ll be struggling with something, and I&rsquo;ll be at a loss of what to do. The thoughts just keep whirling about aimlessly and no solution to the particular problem at hand seems to emerge from the chaos. Whenever I am in such a situation, I sit down, close my eyes, observe what is going on, and I start to write. I write it all down. The thoughts, the associations that these thoughts generate, and the effects they are having. I write down exactly how I feel. Attaching words to the feelings that I&rsquo;m experiencing mentally and physically. &ldquo;I feel a contraction in my lower abdomen&rdquo;. &ldquo;I&rsquo;m angry, and it manifests as a hot feeling on my forehead&rdquo;. And that&rsquo;s when the magic happens: something that I&rsquo;ve come to identify as &ldquo;The Power Of Writing&rdquo;.</p>
<p>Somehow the act of writing everything down will create structure in the chaos, and the solution to my problem wil emerge, often from very unexpected angles. Is it the fact that it is structured on paper? Or the fact that the visual representation of the contents of my mind enables me to apply structure to them? Is it the fact that I am moving my hands, adding bodily movement to my cognitive efforts?</p>
<p>I don&rsquo;t have the exact answer, but all I know is that it works for me. Almost every time. And often when I don&rsquo;t expect it at all. I&rsquo;ll just be sitting and writing in my journal, writing down a particular challenge that I&rsquo;m facing that day. And somehow some solution appears out of the blue. Whenever this happens, I always smile and write down: &ldquo;The Power of Writing&rdquo;.</p>
<h1 id="mindfulness">Mindfulness</h1>
<p>Even though I might not know the exact answer, I&rsquo;m certain that it is very closely related to mindfulness. Becoming more mindful through meditation and present moment awareness is the key to happiness in my opnion. I developed a mindfulness practice out of writing by creating this ritual where I sit down and identify what is going on and writing it down. In essence, I&rsquo;m forcing myself to be mindful, and to attach words to my mental and bodily experience. I&rsquo;m getting out of my own way and letting my mind solve the challenge all by itself.</p>
<p>You know what? It&rsquo;s happening right now! The Power of Writing. I hadn&rsquo;t been able to clearly capture in words what the mechanism behind the Power of Writing was, but as I was writing this article, it became obvious to me that it must be mindfulness underlying it all. So I&rsquo;m just going to leave it as it is. This is a perfect example of what you will find in my private zettelkasten. I wrote all of this in one sitting, with minimal editing. Just stream of conciousness, writing it down. And I finished with a wonderful realization.</p>
<p>I feel grateful, satsified and happy. There is also a pleasant tingling at the top of my neck, and an energy rising up through my feet. I hope that this might help someone else one day, and inspire someone to pick up the habit of writing.</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202305012005</p>
<p><a href="https://herman.bearblog.dev/on-writing-regularly/">https://herman.bearblog.dev/on-writing-regularly/</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcast Notes: Dopamine and Motivation - Huberman</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/dopamine-and-motivation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/dopamine-and-motivation/</guid>
      <description>Dopamine Listened to an interesting podcast on Dopamine by Andrew Huberman. I always enjoy his content because he is completely driven by science, not by personal opinion. He is truly objective as far as I can tell.
Dopamine is often misunderstood. It is not necessarily associated with good feelings after you pursue an activity. It is more related to motivation to engage in certain behaviours.
Rewards Scientists did an experiment where they observed children of kindergarten age, and later reproduced this in adults.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="dopamine">Dopamine</h1>
<p>Listened to <a href="https://hubermanlab.com/leverage-dopamine-to-overcome-procrastination-and-optimize-effort/">an interesting podcast on Dopamine</a> by Andrew Huberman. I always enjoy his content because he is completely driven by science, not by personal opinion. He is truly objective as far as I can tell.</p>
<p>Dopamine is often misunderstood. It is not necessarily associated with good feelings after you pursue an activity. It is more related to motivation to engage in certain behaviours.</p>
<h1 id="rewards">Rewards</h1>
<p>Scientists did an experiment where they observed children of kindergarten age, and later reproduced this in adults. The children were monitored during school days, where they had blocks of structured time and free time. During structured time their activities were managed. They had to sing or write, for example. Then they had blocks of free time where they could do whatever activity they liked.</p>
<p>They observed what activity the children liked to do in their free time, and then started to reward these children for their work. For example, if the children liked to draw in their free time, the researches started giving them gold stars and other praise for their work.</p>
<p>Then the researches removed the reward for the activity, and interestingly, the children and adults started showing less interest and enjoyment in the activity because they were lacking the reward.Note that this is the activity that they liked to do in their free time prior to the experiment.</p>
<p>This all has to do with the nature of dopamine, dopamine baselines and peaks.</p>
<p>Huberman explains this with a metaphor of a pool. In the pool you have waves, and the waves have peaks and troughs. At the peaks, your dopamine is high, but they are inevitably followed by troughs: dips in dopamine, which lead to low energy and low motivation.</p>
<p>Then there is the baseline of dopamine: the amount of water in the pool. The baseline is the relative point to which the peaks and throughs are determined.</p>
<p>So it is important that you don&rsquo;t reward yourself for activities that you are doing. Don&rsquo;t reward yourself too much when you achieve a fitness or study goal. You will feel good after the event, but you will end up in a through. Being in the trough means feeling demotivated, leading to procrastination.</p>
<h1 id="getting-out-of-the-trough">Getting Out Of The Trough</h1>
<p>The good news is that the system will reset itself after experiencing highs or lows due to rewards.Getting out of the trough happens automatically, but you can influence the rate at which you climb out of it.</p>
<p>Let&rsquo;s say you are not motivated to study. You&rsquo;ll need to do something which is more painful. Something that&rsquo;s even harder to do. Whatever feels harder to do in the moment than the activity that you <em>should</em> be doing. Do something that makes you feel uncomfortable.</p>
<h2 id="tactics">Tactics</h2>
<ul>
<li>exercise for 1 minute</li>
<li>do something that really sucks
<ul>
<li>cold water</li>
<li>anything that makes you cringe</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>leverage something that&rsquo;s painful</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="the-holy-grail-of-motivation">The Holy Grail Of Motivation</h1>
<p>The holy grail of motivation: not needing any external reward, but enjoying the activity itself that is leading you towards your goal. For example, enjoying running training in pursuit of a marathon goal. Enjoying coding and doing coding exercises in pursuit of becoming a software engineer.</p>
<p>I feel very fortunate that I succeeded at turning my passion into my career. The journey itself is fun. I enjoy coding, and that activity is taking me closer towards the goal of becoming a good software engineer and the ability to contribute to open source.</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202303311903</p>
<p><a href="https://hubermanlab.com/leverage-dopamine-to-overcome-procrastination-and-optimize-effort/">https://hubermanlab.com/leverage-dopamine-to-overcome-procrastination-and-optimize-effort/</a></p>
<p>[[My Ikigai]]</p>
<p>[[coding]]</p>
<p>[[devops]]</p>
<p>[[Career]]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exercise Stimulates Creativity And Motivation</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/exercise-stimulates-creativity-and-motivation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/exercise-stimulates-creativity-and-motivation/</guid>
      <description>I noticed multiple times now that during my workouts my mind is generating lots of new ideas for coding projects or blog posts. It is a well known fact that walking stimulates areas in the brain that which will in turn stimulate creativity. But I&amp;rsquo;m noticing that it starts to happen with strength workouts as well.
Although I don&amp;rsquo;t struggle with the motivation to get myself to the gym, I sometimes feel &amp;ldquo;guilty&amp;rdquo; for not spending that time on coding or studying.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I noticed multiple times now that during my workouts my mind is generating lots of new ideas for coding projects or blog posts. It is a well known fact that walking stimulates areas in the brain that which will in turn stimulate creativity. But I&rsquo;m noticing that it starts to happen with strength workouts as well.</p>
<p>Although I don&rsquo;t struggle with the motivation to get myself to the gym, I sometimes feel &ldquo;guilty&rdquo; for not spending that time on coding or studying. I&rsquo;m realizing now that this is a very irrational train of thought.</p>
<p>Exercise actually stimulates my creativity and will help generating new ideas or help me understand concepts better in the unconscious. It is also massively beneficial for health and general well being. When general well-being is enhanced I&rsquo;ll also be able to focus better and absorb information more quickly.</p>
<p>I should re-frame my thinking and actually put exercise as priority number 1. Exercise time is never wasted time. It indirectly contributes to my productivity and coding endeavours as well.</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202304011104</p>
<p>[[exercise]]</p>
<p>[[Health]]</p>
<p>[[focus]]</p>
<p>[[productivity]]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I ran 5K for the first time in my life!</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/ran-5km/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/ran-5km/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I reached a significant milestone. I ran my first 5K!
I&amp;rsquo;ve always been on the heavy side. I did a lot of weightlifting from age 18 to around 27 and I was always rather bulky, but very strong. This meant I was very good at working in the woods or helping people move house, but I&amp;rsquo;ve never been able to do any running or endurance because my knees would start protesting very quickly.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday I reached a significant milestone. I ran my first 5K!</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve always been on the heavy side. I did a lot of weightlifting from age 18 to around 27 and I was always rather bulky, but very strong. This meant I was very good at working in the woods or helping people move house, but I&rsquo;ve never been able to do any running or endurance because my knees would start protesting very quickly. However, I always admired endurance athletes and I had the desire to be able to run more than a few minutes without feeling the urge to die on the spot.</p>
<p>Over the past 1,5 years I lost 20kg (~44 pounds) so I decided to give it yet another try.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve never been this lightweight so I decided to give running another try. I started small with only 10 minutes but over the course of two months I built it up gradually.</p>
<p>Last week I ran 4km and it felt pretty good, so I just decided to push a little bit more and try for my goal of 5k, and it went well! It feels like quite an accomplishment to me.</p>
<p>Now that I lost all this weight running actually feels good, and it is liberating to discover a whole new area of exercise that I haven&rsquo;t explored yet: endurance. Looking back to my progress over a couple of months, I&rsquo;m curious how far I&rsquo;ll come and what my limits are.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
