<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Writing on Mischa van den Burg</title>
    <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writing on Mischa van den Burg</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Decided to split up into a technical and personal blog after all</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/splitting-to-personal-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/splitting-to-personal-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been struggling with this ever since I started blogging 2 years ago (can&amp;rsquo;t believe it&amp;rsquo;s already been that long). But I&amp;rsquo;ve finally made the decision: I&amp;rsquo;m keeping this blog at mischavandenburg.com as a tech and career focused blog where I share technical knowledge and notes, and I&amp;rsquo;m starting a new personal blog at &lt;a href=&#34;https://mischavandenburg.blog&#34;&gt;mischavandenburg.blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have fallen in love with blogging. Documenting my own life in writing has become a very therapeutic and valuable experience to me. Even if nobody reads what I put out into the world, it is incredibly satisfying to scroll through your own blog and go back in time to see what I was learning or doing or feeling at that time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve been struggling with this ever since I started blogging 2 years ago (can&rsquo;t believe it&rsquo;s already been that long). But I&rsquo;ve finally made the decision: I&rsquo;m keeping this blog at mischavandenburg.com as a tech and career focused blog where I share technical knowledge and notes, and I&rsquo;m starting a new personal blog at <a href="https://mischavandenburg.blog">mischavandenburg.blog</a>.</p>
<p>I have fallen in love with blogging. Documenting my own life in writing has become a very therapeutic and valuable experience to me. Even if nobody reads what I put out into the world, it is incredibly satisfying to scroll through your own blog and go back in time to see what I was learning or doing or feeling at that time.</p>
<p>Blogging is an expression of creativity to me. My fingers move on the keyboard and an article appears. I&rsquo;m creating text. I&rsquo;m not a visual person, unfortunately. I don&rsquo;t see images when I think and I&rsquo;m rather bad at drawing or arranging things in a pleasing way. Throughout my life I have expressed my creativity in music, but I consciously haven&rsquo;t engaged in making music in the past few years because it takes up so much time in practice. But I have found a very rewarding way of expressing myself in writing by blogging.</p>
<p>However, I feel that I am constraining myself on this blog because it is is linked to my LinkedIn account and I keep posting to LinkedIn from here. Even though I have nothing to hide, I&rsquo;m pouring my thoughts out on the internet after all, I do feel that LinkedIn is best kept as a professional platform where people can expect consistency and a focus on technical topics, even when they navigate away from there to my own blog.</p>
<p>But I have so much more to give. I want to write about topics that deeply interest me: meditation, Buddhism, running, plant-based diet, healthy living, longevity, mental health, addiction. I feel the urge to pour out these thoughts freely in a place I can call my home on the web, without feeling any restraint or concern. That&rsquo;s why I gave my new blog the headline <strong>&ldquo;A place where I can truly be free&rdquo;.</strong></p>
<p>Another reason why I&rsquo;m splitting it off is because I intend to use this blog in the process of becoming a Microsoft MVP. The achievement of that goal was not in my mind when I started blogging about personal topics on this blog, but now I think it will be best to keep this blog clean and technical in order to present a clear image in the MVP approval process.</p>
<p>I don&rsquo;t care about SEO or ads or the amount of views this blog gets. It&rsquo;s not about SEO optimization or having to have a niche. I&rsquo;m more concerned with giving any readers a good experience as possible.</p>
<p>So here we go. This blog has a (re)new(ed) technical focus, and I&rsquo;m going to keep sharing my notes, learnings, AKS and Azure updates and other discoveries I make along the way. But I&rsquo;ll also be migrating away the personal posts on running, weeknotes and other posts away from this blog.</p>
<p>If you are interested in my personal ramblings though, make sure to check out my new personal blog here:</p>
<p><a href="https://mischavandenburg.blog">https://mischavandenburg.blog</a></p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202312171212</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link: Rediscovering The Small Web</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/rediscovering-the-small-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/rediscovering-the-small-web/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A great essay about small personal websites coded in HTML. Brings me back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/&#34;&gt;https://neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;202312150812&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A great essay about small personal websites coded in HTML. Brings me back.</p>
<p><a href="https://neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/">https://neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/</a></p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202312150812</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link: On Writing For Yourself In Public</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/link-on-writing-for-yourself-in-public/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/link-on-writing-for-yourself-in-public/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nice article that explains why blogging is a satisfying activity. I&amp;rsquo;ve written the exact same reasons of why I blog on my about page where I wrote that it is very satisfying to scroll through your own feed and see what you have been up to. My blog is a time machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://brainbaking.com/post/2023/11/on-writing-for-yourself-in-public/&#34;&gt;https://brainbaking.com/post/2023/11/on-writing-for-yourself-in-public/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;202311150711&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nice article that explains why blogging is a satisfying activity. I&rsquo;ve written the exact same reasons of why I blog on my about page where I wrote that it is very satisfying to scroll through your own feed and see what you have been up to. My blog is a time machine.</p>
<p><a href="https://brainbaking.com/post/2023/11/on-writing-for-yourself-in-public/">https://brainbaking.com/post/2023/11/on-writing-for-yourself-in-public/</a></p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202311150711</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m not journaling as often as I used to</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/not-journaling-as-often/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/not-journaling-as-often/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I notice that I&amp;rsquo;m not writing in my journal every day like I used to. I always wrote down what I did, what I felt, what my plans and ambitions were, every single day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During my holiday I started writing by hand in a notebook again which was really nice. It felt good to feel the pencil scratching on the paper again and to practice my cursive writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After I came back I first tried to keep journaling by hand again, but after a few days the journal remained untouched. I figured I would go back to my usual digital journaling again by writing daily notes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I notice that I&rsquo;m not writing in my journal every day like I used to. I always wrote down what I did, what I felt, what my plans and ambitions were, every single day.</p>
<p>During my holiday I started writing by hand in a notebook again which was really nice. It felt good to feel the pencil scratching on the paper again and to practice my cursive writing.</p>
<p>After I came back I first tried to keep journaling by hand again, but after a few days the journal remained untouched. I figured I would go back to my usual digital journaling again by writing daily notes.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m a litlte intruiged. I do feel very relaxed and at ease, perhaps I do not need to write so much at this time? Writing down frustrations and feelings definitely has been a certain way of processing them.</p>
<p>And perhaps my routine is reaching such a degree of stability that it is simply not worth the effort of writing it all down all the time.</p>
<p>Rather than writing in my personal notes, I do have the intention to write more zets in my public zettelkasten on all the topics that interest me currently. Micronotes.</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202309282109</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Have A Personal Website?</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/why-personal-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/why-personal-website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Why bother with a personal website? Why not just write blog posts on LinkedIn?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to own my data. I want to have complete freedom. I want to write whatever I want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://matthiasott.com/notes/simple-truths-about-personal-websites&#34;&gt;This post captures it beautifully.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;202305171305&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://matthiasott.com/notes/simple-truths-about-personal-websites&#34;&gt;https://matthiasott.com/notes/simple-truths-about-personal-websites&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Why bother with a personal website? Why not just write blog posts on LinkedIn?</p>
<p>I want to own my data. I want to have complete freedom. I want to write whatever I want.</p>
<p><a href="https://matthiasott.com/notes/simple-truths-about-personal-websites">This post captures it beautifully.</a></p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202305171305</p>
<p><a href="https://matthiasott.com/notes/simple-truths-about-personal-websites">https://matthiasott.com/notes/simple-truths-about-personal-websites</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Started Using Tumblr for Travel Blogging</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/started-using-tumblr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/started-using-tumblr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the spring finally being fully released on the Netherlands, my wanderlust has awakened again after lying dormant for two years. In my 9 years in Norway I became a seasoned outdoorsman spending much time roaming the mountains and forests and always spending days or weeks out in the wild with my tent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I moved back to the Netherlands this has been put on hold for a couple of years while I focused on changing my career on IT. Now that the career is rolling along nicely by the looks of it, I&amp;rsquo;m super excited to start exploring the Netherlands and see what the outdoors life is like in an area where the nature is significantly less wild and abundant.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With the spring finally being fully released on the Netherlands, my wanderlust has awakened again after lying dormant for two years. In my 9 years in Norway I became a seasoned outdoorsman spending much time roaming the mountains and forests and always spending days or weeks out in the wild with my tent.</p>
<p>When I moved back to the Netherlands this has been put on hold for a couple of years while I focused on changing my career on IT. Now that the career is rolling along nicely by the looks of it, I&rsquo;m super excited to start exploring the Netherlands and see what the outdoors life is like in an area where the nature is significantly less wild and abundant.</p>
<p>I needed a solution to post pictures quickly and easily because I want to start logging my trips as well. My hugo setup is great for text and techincal content but I need something where I can easily post straight from my phone and Tumblr seems like the best option. I&rsquo;ll also be posting more on Instagram from here on out.</p>
<p>Here is my first post:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.tumblr.com/mischavandenburg/717301155801235456/went-to-heemskerk-today-broke-my-running-record?source=share">https://www.tumblr.com/mischavandenburg/717301155801235456/went-to-heemskerk-today-broke-my-running-record?source=share</a></p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202305141505</p>
<p><a href="https://www.tumblr.com/mischavandenburg">https://www.tumblr.com/mischavandenburg</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I&#39;m Posting More on Social Media</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/why-post-on-social-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/why-post-on-social-media/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My recent &lt;a href=&#34;https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/everything-nothing-blog/&#34;&gt;post on E/N blogging&lt;/a&gt; led to a realization: posting on social media will be something I do for myself, instead of doing it for others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Facebook came out when I was 16 I posted quite a lot on social media. 5 years later I found it very embarassing to read back through those posts and I deleted everything, and since then I have been been holding back on social media posting and deleting my accounts several times.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>My recent <a href="/zet/everything-nothing-blog/">post on E/N blogging</a> led to a realization: posting on social media will be something I do for myself, instead of doing it for others.</p>
<p>When Facebook came out when I was 16 I posted quite a lot on social media. 5 years later I found it very embarassing to read back through those posts and I deleted everything, and since then I have been been holding back on social media posting and deleting my accounts several times.</p>
<p>In the meantime I also used social media as a marketing tool, creating very specific accounts tailored to a particular niche of content to drive traffic to websites. This approach to social media broke my relationship with it, and it became something you do to gain a certain response from others. I think this is the case for many people. Whether it is getting as much as possible likes, or getting people to click on an affiliate link, your content is always shaped by your anticipation of the audience&rsquo;s reaction.</p>
<p>Starting this blog has been a breakthrough for me. Especially when I gave up on my tech niche and just started writing about everything that interests me, it became a huge enrichment to my life, and I&rsquo;m going to extend this to social media as well.</p>
<p>The thing is, I&rsquo;ve always been very bad at taking pictures and storing them. I have tons of great experiences and memories stored in my mind, but I sometimes wish that I took more pictures of these adventures. Because I was lucky enough to have grown up in an an age without smartphones, there still is an inherent reluctance towards that whole culture. There is an irritation when I see people flipping out their phones when their meals get served in a restaurant, and I feel socially awkward to take my phone out in public to take pictures of things.</p>
<p>Now I&rsquo;m changing this: I&rsquo;m going to take more pictures of the things I experience and post them on social media. Not because I want to impress others, but because I want to record the things I&rsquo;m doing so I can enjoy them again at a later time. I arrived at this desire because I find it very enjoyable to scroll through my own blog and see the progression I&rsquo;ve made over time, and the things I decided to share. And I want to extend this experience to pictures as well. So I&rsquo;m going to post more on Instagram and Tumblr and write short travel logs of the places I visit and the things I experience, so I can revisit them later and find pleasure therein.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m basically using these services to my own needs and completely disregard any audience. But if anybody finds enjoyment in seeing the things I put online, that would be a great thing.</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202305141505</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Blog Is Turning Into And Everything / Nothing Website And It Feels Good</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/everything-nothing-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/everything-nothing-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Read an interesting post this morning about &lt;a href=&#34;http://sawv.org/en.html&#34;&gt;E/N websites.&lt;/a&gt; Apparently a phenomenon from the early days of the web, E/N websites meant everything to the publisher, but maybe nothing to the rest of the world. The term may have been the predecessor of the term &amp;ldquo;weblog&amp;rdquo; which was shortened to blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;E/N description: The website&amp;rsquo;s author covers a myriad of topics. It&amp;rsquo;s not narrowly focused. The author writes about everything or at least everything that&amp;rsquo;s important to the author. The site might contain something useful for anyone who visits. The content means everything to the publisher, but it could mean nothing to the rest of the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Read an interesting post this morning about <a href="http://sawv.org/en.html">E/N websites.</a> Apparently a phenomenon from the early days of the web, E/N websites meant everything to the publisher, but maybe nothing to the rest of the world. The term may have been the predecessor of the term &ldquo;weblog&rdquo; which was shortened to blog.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>E/N description: The website&rsquo;s author covers a myriad of topics. It&rsquo;s not narrowly focused. The author writes about everything or at least everything that&rsquo;s important to the author. The site might contain something useful for anyone who visits. The content means everything to the publisher, but it could mean nothing to the rest of the world.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In <a href="/zet/articles/write-about-health-personal/">this post from March</a> I declared that I would write more about my personal life and expanding the range of topics that I would publish on my blog / zettelkasten. And it has a great decision so far.</p>
<p>I thoroughly enjoy the sense of freedom it has given me. Rather than constraining myself to one subject area, I feel free to write about anything that currently interests me. Writing about these topics stimulates further research and more intentional content consumption.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m sharing more and more personal content, and this is the type of content one might expect to be seen on a social media platform. I don&rsquo;t use social media much, and decided to carve out my own space on the internet and write there instead. I will always be the owner of this content, and I can write about whatever I want and change the appearance and presentation.</p>
<p>I can&rsquo;t explain why, but there is something very satisfying about scrolling through my <a href="/archives/">archives</a> and seeing the things that caught my interest during those particular months, knowing that it is publically available and that others might be piqued by the keywords as well.</p>
<p>Discovering <a href="https://roytang.net/">Roy Tang&rsquo;s website</a> was also very inspirational. I picked up the idea of sharing my week notes and logging the content consumption from his blog. Reading Hacker News regularly has exposed me to several personal blogs which I&rsquo;ve added to my RSS feeds, and I enjoy reading about their interests and getting inspiration from what they decide to publish on their blogs.</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202305090805</p>
<p><a href="https://roytang.net/">https://roytang.net/</a></p>
<p><a href="http://sawv.org/en.html">http://sawv.org/en.html</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video: How I Write &amp; Publish My Blog Using Neovim &amp; Hugo From The Command Line</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/blogging-from-command-line/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/blogging-from-command-line/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/bzkrmkGDQJA?autoplay=0&amp;controls=1&amp;end=0&amp;loop=0&amp;mute=0&amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;
      &gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I show my workflow to publish my Hugo blog from the command line using neovim and bash&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[

    
    <div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
      <iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bzkrmkGDQJA?autoplay=0&controls=1&end=0&loop=0&mute=0&start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video"
      ></iframe>
    </div>

<p>I show my workflow to publish my Hugo blog from the command line using neovim and bash</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202305091705</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Power of Writing</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/power-of-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/power-of-writing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ah, writing. It&amp;rsquo;s one of the skills that I&amp;rsquo;ve consistently been praised for throughout my life. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty good at it, and I think that&amp;rsquo;s because I enjoy it. It led me to getting an academic degree in English Literature and Culture, simply because I was following the things I was naturally good at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, just like any other skill, you can only become better at it through consistent practice. This morning I read a wonderful little blog post &lt;a href=&#34;https://herman.bearblog.dev/on-writing-regularly/&#34;&gt;on writing regularly&lt;/a&gt;, and I was touched by his words:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ah, writing. It&rsquo;s one of the skills that I&rsquo;ve consistently been praised for throughout my life. I&rsquo;m pretty good at it, and I think that&rsquo;s because I enjoy it. It led me to getting an academic degree in English Literature and Culture, simply because I was following the things I was naturally good at.</p>
<p>However, just like any other skill, you can only become better at it through consistent practice. This morning I read a wonderful little blog post <a href="https://herman.bearblog.dev/on-writing-regularly/">on writing regularly</a>, and I was touched by his words:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Similarly, some people believe that the art of writing is a skill that can be summoned on a whim, like a genie emerging from a lamp with a flourish of creative brilliance. In my experience, however, writing is more akin to the labour of a blacksmith, hamming words into shape through the heat and sweat of regular practise.</p>
</blockquote>
<h1 id="daily-practice">Daily Practice</h1>
<p>One way to gain more experience is to start keeping a daily journal. I&rsquo;ve always kept some notebook or other, jotting down thoughts and ideas as they came along sporadically. But it was only in July 2020 that I started <a href="https://www.artofmanliness.com/character/behavior/30-days-to-a-better-man-day-8-start-a-journal/">to keep a daily journal</a> and writing regularly. I started out writing by hand. I was in at an interesting place in life: I was spending two years in a Buddhist monastery, and after settling down for a couple of months, the intensive meditation practice was releasing all sorts of things in the mind and body, and I started to write them all down. I&rsquo;m still convinced that starting this habit has been one of the most important and beneficial decisions of my life.</p>
<p>It is so simple, but extremely effective. And you don&rsquo;t have to be doing anything special, or be in a special place. Just keeping a daily journal where you note down the things you did that day in a small pocket book is enough to get the habit going. Soon you will find that you will get the urge to write more. After several years of daily journaling, sometimes all I write is &ldquo;It&rsquo;s been a pretty good day&rdquo;. And that&rsquo;s it for that day. Sometimes I write several pages worth of thoughts, ideas and these longer writings often have powerful effects.</p>
<h1 id="the-power-of-writing">The Power Of Writing</h1>
<p>Sometimes I&rsquo;ll be struggling with something, and I&rsquo;ll be at a loss of what to do. The thoughts just keep whirling about aimlessly and no solution to the particular problem at hand seems to emerge from the chaos. Whenever I am in such a situation, I sit down, close my eyes, observe what is going on, and I start to write. I write it all down. The thoughts, the associations that these thoughts generate, and the effects they are having. I write down exactly how I feel. Attaching words to the feelings that I&rsquo;m experiencing mentally and physically. &ldquo;I feel a contraction in my lower abdomen&rdquo;. &ldquo;I&rsquo;m angry, and it manifests as a hot feeling on my forehead&rdquo;. And that&rsquo;s when the magic happens: something that I&rsquo;ve come to identify as &ldquo;The Power Of Writing&rdquo;.</p>
<p>Somehow the act of writing everything down will create structure in the chaos, and the solution to my problem wil emerge, often from very unexpected angles. Is it the fact that it is structured on paper? Or the fact that the visual representation of the contents of my mind enables me to apply structure to them? Is it the fact that I am moving my hands, adding bodily movement to my cognitive efforts?</p>
<p>I don&rsquo;t have the exact answer, but all I know is that it works for me. Almost every time. And often when I don&rsquo;t expect it at all. I&rsquo;ll just be sitting and writing in my journal, writing down a particular challenge that I&rsquo;m facing that day. And somehow some solution appears out of the blue. Whenever this happens, I always smile and write down: &ldquo;The Power of Writing&rdquo;.</p>
<h1 id="mindfulness">Mindfulness</h1>
<p>Even though I might not know the exact answer, I&rsquo;m certain that it is very closely related to mindfulness. Becoming more mindful through meditation and present moment awareness is the key to happiness in my opnion. I developed a mindfulness practice out of writing by creating this ritual where I sit down and identify what is going on and writing it down. In essence, I&rsquo;m forcing myself to be mindful, and to attach words to my mental and bodily experience. I&rsquo;m getting out of my own way and letting my mind solve the challenge all by itself.</p>
<p>You know what? It&rsquo;s happening right now! The Power of Writing. I hadn&rsquo;t been able to clearly capture in words what the mechanism behind the Power of Writing was, but as I was writing this article, it became obvious to me that it must be mindfulness underlying it all. So I&rsquo;m just going to leave it as it is. This is a perfect example of what you will find in my private zettelkasten. I wrote all of this in one sitting, with minimal editing. Just stream of conciousness, writing it down. And I finished with a wonderful realization.</p>
<p>I feel grateful, satsified and happy. There is also a pleasant tingling at the top of my neck, and an energy rising up through my feet. I hope that this might help someone else one day, and inspire someone to pick up the habit of writing.</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202305012005</p>
<p><a href="https://herman.bearblog.dev/on-writing-regularly/">https://herman.bearblog.dev/on-writing-regularly/</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Converting markdown to PDF on MacOS</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/pandoc-markdown-pdf-macos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/pandoc-markdown-pdf-macos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It happens that I want to share my notes with friends that just simply want a pdf instead of a markdown file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning I figured out a quick way to convert markdown to pdf on a M2 MacBook running MacOS Ventura.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need the pandoc and wkhtmltopdf packages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;brew install pandoc wkhtmltopdf 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;To convert:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;pandoc 00-zettelkasten/Fundamentals&lt;span class=&#34;se&#34;&gt;\ &lt;/span&gt;of&lt;span class=&#34;se&#34;&gt;\ &lt;/span&gt;Bicep.md --pdf-engine&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;wkhtmltopdf  -o /tmp/test.pdf
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pr</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It happens that I want to share my notes with friends that just simply want a pdf instead of a markdown file.</p>
<p>This morning I figured out a quick way to convert markdown to pdf on a M2 MacBook running MacOS Ventura.</p>
<p>You need the pandoc and wkhtmltopdf packages.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash"><span class="line"><span class="cl">brew install pandoc wkhtmltopdf 
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>To convert:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash"><span class="line"><span class="cl">pandoc 00-zettelkasten/Fundamentals<span class="se">\ </span>of<span class="se">\ </span>Bicep.md --pdf-engine<span class="o">=</span>wkhtmltopdf  -o /tmp/test.pdf
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>This will output a pdf to my /tmp/ directory and it looks pretty good.</p>
<p>To convert all markdown files in a directory you can use a wildcard:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash"><span class="line"><span class="cl">pandoc 00-zettelkasten/*.md --pdf-engine<span class="o">=</span>wkhtmltopdf  -o /tmp/test.pdf
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>Fun fact: converting my entire zettelkasten took a few seconds and generated a document of 80 pages with a font size of 10. Pretty fun to see it in a more regular format instead of the terminal.</p>
<h1 id="pandoc">pandoc</h1>
<p>Switched to pandoc for my vim markdown plugin and I&rsquo;m starting to like it a lot. I struggled a bit to get a working setup because of all the folding etc. But I figured it out and found out that rwxrob also hates folding haha.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3NiBr3j-vMw">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3NiBr3j-vMw</a>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Efk2M77naFU&amp;list=TLPQMjQwMzIwMjPleFLT9W4o_Q&amp;index=3">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Efk2M77naFU&amp;list=TLPQMjQwMzIwMjPleFLT9W4o_Q&amp;index=3</a>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3NiBr3j-vMw&amp;list=TLPQMjQwMzIwMjPleFLT9W4o_Q&amp;index=1">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3NiBr3j-vMw&amp;list=TLPQMjQwMzIwMjPleFLT9W4o_Q&amp;index=1</a></p>
<p>search rwxrobs channel for markdown</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying out pandoc for vim</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/trying-out-pandoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/trying-out-pandoc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I do all of my writing in markdown. I keep my diaries in my Second Brain, I constantly write notes on the topics I&amp;rsquo;m studying, and my entire blog is written in markdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the writing is done in Obsidian but I&amp;rsquo;m moving away from Obsidian step by step. I&amp;rsquo;ll still keep my second brain compatible with it, but I want to be able to do all of my writing in (neo)vim.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I do all of my writing in markdown. I keep my diaries in my Second Brain, I constantly write notes on the topics I&rsquo;m studying, and my entire blog is written in markdown.</p>
<p>Some of the writing is done in Obsidian but I&rsquo;m moving away from Obsidian step by step. I&rsquo;ll still keep my second brain compatible with it, but I want to be able to do all of my writing in (neo)vim.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve been using nvim-markdown for a while now and I was quite happy with it, but it was bothering me that <strong>bold text</strong> was not rendered in my editor.</p>
<p>Pandoc had been on my radar for a while because it uses the Commonmark <a href="https://spec.commonmark.org/">markdown spec</a> and it can be used to convert to many different documentation types. It&rsquo;s an interesting thought to keep my entire collection of notes and writings compatible with something that can be converted into anything.</p>
<p>I noticed rwxrob uses pandoc as one of his few vim plugins.</p>
<p>It took me an hour to make it compatible with neovim and to disable the spelling and folding. I couldn&rsquo;t just set the provided variables because they are still in vimscript and I haven&rsquo;t figured out how to set them yet because they use a hashtag in their name #</p>
<p>So far I like it, but there are a few things that I miss from my nvim-markdown</p>
<ul>
<li>automatic bulleted list</li>
<li>nested bulleted lists
<ul>
<li>with nvim-markdown these lists would continue</li>
<li>Here I have to indent each line myself and add a bullet</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>navigation between headers
<ul>
<li>I didn&rsquo;t use this much to be honest, but I haven&rsquo;t figured it out in pandoc yet. Maybe it is possible?</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>I find myself using bullete lists and nested lists a lot in my notes, but I wonder if it is better to step away from those and make more use of markdown headings.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
