<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Notetaking on Mischa van den Burg</title>
    <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/notetaking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Notetaking on Mischa van den Burg</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/notetaking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Power of Writing</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/power-of-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/power-of-writing/</guid>
      <description>Ah, writing. It&amp;rsquo;s one of the skills that I&amp;rsquo;ve consistently been praised for throughout my life. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty good at it, and I think that&amp;rsquo;s because I enjoy it. It led me to getting an academic degree in English Literature and Culture, simply because I was following the things I was naturally good at.
However, just like any other skill, you can only become better at it through consistent practice. This morning I read a wonderful little blog post on writing regularly, and I was touched by his words:</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ah, writing. It&rsquo;s one of the skills that I&rsquo;ve consistently been praised for throughout my life. I&rsquo;m pretty good at it, and I think that&rsquo;s because I enjoy it. It led me to getting an academic degree in English Literature and Culture, simply because I was following the things I was naturally good at.</p>
<p>However, just like any other skill, you can only become better at it through consistent practice. This morning I read a wonderful little blog post <a href="https://herman.bearblog.dev/on-writing-regularly/">on writing regularly</a>, and I was touched by his words:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Similarly, some people believe that the art of writing is a skill that can be summoned on a whim, like a genie emerging from a lamp with a flourish of creative brilliance. In my experience, however, writing is more akin to the labour of a blacksmith, hamming words into shape through the heat and sweat of regular practise.</p>
</blockquote>
<h1 id="daily-practice">Daily Practice</h1>
<p>One way to gain more experience is to start keeping a daily journal. I&rsquo;ve always kept some notebook or other, jotting down thoughts and ideas as they came along sporadically. But it was only in July 2020 that I started <a href="https://www.artofmanliness.com/character/behavior/30-days-to-a-better-man-day-8-start-a-journal/">to keep a daily journal</a> and writing regularly. I started out writing by hand. I was in at an interesting place in life: I was spending two years in a Buddhist monastery, and after settling down for a couple of months, the intensive meditation practice was releasing all sorts of things in the mind and body, and I started to write them all down. I&rsquo;m still convinced that starting this habit has been one of the most important and beneficial decisions of my life.</p>
<p>It is so simple, but extremely effective. And you don&rsquo;t have to be doing anything special, or be in a special place. Just keeping a daily journal where you note down the things you did that day in a small pocket book is enough to get the habit going. Soon you will find that you will get the urge to write more. After several years of daily journaling, sometimes all I write is &ldquo;It&rsquo;s been a pretty good day&rdquo;. And that&rsquo;s it for that day. Sometimes I write several pages worth of thoughts, ideas and these longer writings often have powerful effects.</p>
<h1 id="the-power-of-writing">The Power Of Writing</h1>
<p>Sometimes I&rsquo;ll be struggling with something, and I&rsquo;ll be at a loss of what to do. The thoughts just keep whirling about aimlessly and no solution to the particular problem at hand seems to emerge from the chaos. Whenever I am in such a situation, I sit down, close my eyes, observe what is going on, and I start to write. I write it all down. The thoughts, the associations that these thoughts generate, and the effects they are having. I write down exactly how I feel. Attaching words to the feelings that I&rsquo;m experiencing mentally and physically. &ldquo;I feel a contraction in my lower abdomen&rdquo;. &ldquo;I&rsquo;m angry, and it manifests as a hot feeling on my forehead&rdquo;. And that&rsquo;s when the magic happens: something that I&rsquo;ve come to identify as &ldquo;The Power Of Writing&rdquo;.</p>
<p>Somehow the act of writing everything down will create structure in the chaos, and the solution to my problem wil emerge, often from very unexpected angles. Is it the fact that it is structured on paper? Or the fact that the visual representation of the contents of my mind enables me to apply structure to them? Is it the fact that I am moving my hands, adding bodily movement to my cognitive efforts?</p>
<p>I don&rsquo;t have the exact answer, but all I know is that it works for me. Almost every time. And often when I don&rsquo;t expect it at all. I&rsquo;ll just be sitting and writing in my journal, writing down a particular challenge that I&rsquo;m facing that day. And somehow some solution appears out of the blue. Whenever this happens, I always smile and write down: &ldquo;The Power of Writing&rdquo;.</p>
<h1 id="mindfulness">Mindfulness</h1>
<p>Even though I might not know the exact answer, I&rsquo;m certain that it is very closely related to mindfulness. Becoming more mindful through meditation and present moment awareness is the key to happiness in my opnion. I developed a mindfulness practice out of writing by creating this ritual where I sit down and identify what is going on and writing it down. In essence, I&rsquo;m forcing myself to be mindful, and to attach words to my mental and bodily experience. I&rsquo;m getting out of my own way and letting my mind solve the challenge all by itself.</p>
<p>You know what? It&rsquo;s happening right now! The Power of Writing. I hadn&rsquo;t been able to clearly capture in words what the mechanism behind the Power of Writing was, but as I was writing this article, it became obvious to me that it must be mindfulness underlying it all. So I&rsquo;m just going to leave it as it is. This is a perfect example of what you will find in my private zettelkasten. I wrote all of this in one sitting, with minimal editing. Just stream of conciousness, writing it down. And I finished with a wonderful realization.</p>
<p>I feel grateful, satsified and happy. There is also a pleasant tingling at the top of my neck, and an energy rising up through my feet. I hope that this might help someone else one day, and inspire someone to pick up the habit of writing.</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202305012005</p>
<p><a href="https://herman.bearblog.dev/on-writing-regularly/">https://herman.bearblog.dev/on-writing-regularly/</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Converting markdown to PDF on MacOS</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/pandoc-markdown-pdf-macos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/pandoc-markdown-pdf-macos/</guid>
      <description>It happens that I want to share my notes with friends that just simply want a pdf instead of a markdown file.
This morning I figured out a quick way to convert markdown to pdf on a M2 MacBook running MacOS Ventura.
You need the pandoc and wkhtmltopdf packages.
brew install pandoc wkhtmltopdf To convert:
pandoc 00-zettelkasten/Fundamentals\ of\ Bicep.md --pdf-engine=wkhtmltopdf -o /tmp/test.pdf This will output a pdf to my /tmp/ directory and it looks pretty good.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It happens that I want to share my notes with friends that just simply want a pdf instead of a markdown file.</p>
<p>This morning I figured out a quick way to convert markdown to pdf on a M2 MacBook running MacOS Ventura.</p>
<p>You need the pandoc and wkhtmltopdf packages.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash"><span class="line"><span class="cl">brew install pandoc wkhtmltopdf 
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>To convert:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash"><span class="line"><span class="cl">pandoc 00-zettelkasten/Fundamentals<span class="se">\ </span>of<span class="se">\ </span>Bicep.md --pdf-engine<span class="o">=</span>wkhtmltopdf  -o /tmp/test.pdf
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>This will output a pdf to my /tmp/ directory and it looks pretty good.</p>
<p>To convert all markdown files in a directory you can use a wildcard:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash"><span class="line"><span class="cl">pandoc 00-zettelkasten/*.md --pdf-engine<span class="o">=</span>wkhtmltopdf  -o /tmp/test.pdf
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>Fun fact: converting my entire zettelkasten took a few seconds and generated a document of 80 pages with a font size of 10. Pretty fun to see it in a more regular format instead of the terminal.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying out pandoc for vim</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/trying-out-pandoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/trying-out-pandoc/</guid>
      <description>I do all of my writing in markdown. I keep my diaries in my Second Brain, I constantly write notes on the topics I&amp;rsquo;m studying, and my entire blog is written in markdown.
Some of the writing is done in Obsidian but I&amp;rsquo;m moving away from Obsidian step by step. I&amp;rsquo;ll still keep my second brain compatible with it, but I want to be able to do all of my writing in (neo)vim.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I do all of my writing in markdown. I keep my diaries in my Second Brain, I constantly write notes on the topics I&rsquo;m studying, and my entire blog is written in markdown.</p>
<p>Some of the writing is done in Obsidian but I&rsquo;m moving away from Obsidian step by step. I&rsquo;ll still keep my second brain compatible with it, but I want to be able to do all of my writing in (neo)vim.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve been using nvim-markdown for a while now and I was quite happy with it, but it was bothering me that <strong>bold text</strong> was not rendered in my editor.</p>
<p>Pandoc had been on my radar for a while because it uses the Commonmark <a href="https://spec.commonmark.org/">markdown spec</a> and it can be used to convert to many different documentation types. It&rsquo;s an interesting thought to keep my entire collection of notes and writings compatible with something that can be converted into anything.</p>
<p>I noticed rwxrob uses pandoc as one of his few vim plugins.</p>
<p>It took me an hour to make it compatible with neovim and to disable the spelling and folding. I couldn&rsquo;t just set the provided variables because they are still in vimscript and I haven&rsquo;t figured out how to set them yet because they use a hashtag in their name #</p>
<p>So far I like it, but there are a few things that I miss from my nvim-markdown</p>
<ul>
<li>automatic bulleted list</li>
<li>nested bulleted lists
<ul>
<li>with nvim-markdown these lists would continue</li>
<li>Here I have to indent each line myself and add a bullet</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>navigation between headers
<ul>
<li>I didn&rsquo;t use this much to be honest, but I haven&rsquo;t figured it out in pandoc yet. Maybe it is possible?</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>I find myself using bullete lists and nested lists a lot in my notes, but I wonder if it is better to step away from those and make more use of markdown headings.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
