<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Cloud-Native on Mischa van den Burg</title>
    <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/cloud-native/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cloud-Native on Mischa van den Burg</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/cloud-native/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Talk: Avoiding Microservice Megadisasters by Jimmy Bogard</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/talk-avoiding-microservice-disasters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/talk-avoiding-microservice-disasters/</guid>
      <description>Watched this very insightful talk on microservice architecture.
Some things I learned:
microservices should be autonomous: they should have minimal dependencies on other microservices if they have dependencies they should only be 1 layer deep a microservice should not be calling another microservice which calls another microservice dependencies can be reversed by pushing data towards the service for example: a pricing database can be dumped and pushed to a catalog service once a day data duplication is not a sin Another powerful point he made is that the architecture is a reflection from the organization&amp;rsquo;s structure.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Watched this very insightful talk on microservice architecture.</p>
<p>Some things I learned:</p>
<ul>
<li>microservices should be <strong>autonomous</strong>: they should have minimal dependencies on other microservices</li>
<li>if they have dependencies they should only be 1 layer deep
<ul>
<li>a microservice should not be calling another microservice which calls another microservice</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>dependencies can be reversed by pushing data towards the service
<ul>
<li>for example: a pricing database can be dumped and pushed to a catalog service once a day</li>
<li>data duplication is not a sin</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Another powerful point he made is that the architecture is a reflection from the organization&rsquo;s structure. He explained that the company was organized in teams and that managers of teams were promoted based on the amount of people they managed. This meant that managers were making up services which needed people to build them, which led to a proliferation of services and dependencies.</p>
<p>In order to have a correct software strucutre, the organization must be organized correctly first.</p>

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/gfh-VCTwMw8" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202312231912</p>
<p><a href="https://youtu.be/gfh-VCTwMw8?si=QqHcbG_5ezx5qJX2">https://youtu.be/gfh-VCTwMw8?si=QqHcbG_5ezx5qJX2</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ensure Cgroupsv2 compatiblity when containerizing old apps</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/ensure-cgroupsv2-compatibility/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/ensure-cgroupsv2-compatibility/</guid>
      <description>Are you currently working with containerizing older Java or .NET applications? From Kubernetes 1.29, the default cgroups implementation on Azure Linux AKS nodes will be cgroupsv2. Older versions of Java, .NET and NodeJS do not support memory querying v2 memory constraints and this will lead to out of memory (OOM) issues for workloads.
Please make sure that your older containerized applications are compatible with cgroupsv2 or you might be in quite some pain in the future.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Are you currently working with containerizing older Java or .NET applications? From Kubernetes 1.29, the default cgroups implementation on Azure Linux AKS nodes will be cgroupsv2. Older versions of Java, .NET and NodeJS do not support memory querying v2 memory constraints and this will lead to out of memory (OOM) issues for workloads.</p>
<p>Please make sure that your older containerized applications are compatible with cgroupsv2 or you might be in quite some pain in the future.</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/Azure/AKS/releases/tag/2023-11-28">https://github.com/Azure/AKS/releases/tag/2023-11-28</a></p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202312120812</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Can Abort Operations on AKS Clusters Now</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/aks-abort-operation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/aks-abort-operation/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s now possible to abort long running operations on AKS clusters. It was released as Generally Available.
For example:
az aks operation-abort --name myAKSCluster --resource-group myResourceGroup
Links: 202304270704
https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/generally-available-operation-abort-in-aks/
https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/aks/manage-abort-operations?tabs=azure-cli</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s now possible to abort long running operations on AKS clusters. It was released as Generally Available.</p>
<p>For example:</p>
<p><code>az aks operation-abort --name myAKSCluster --resource-group myResourceGroup</code></p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202304270704</p>
<p><a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/generally-available-operation-abort-in-aks/">https://azure.microsoft.com/en-us/updates/generally-available-operation-abort-in-aks/</a></p>
<p><a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/aks/manage-abort-operations?tabs=azure-cli">https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/aks/manage-abort-operations?tabs=azure-cli</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outlining My First Go Project</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/go-twitter-cli-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/go-twitter-cli-project/</guid>
      <description>When learning a programming language it is important to start building things quickly and to begin applying the theory. I have a tendency to dive into the books and lose myself in the theory, where I should be getting hands on experience.
Over the past few months I&amp;rsquo;ve generated a bunch of ideas for projects that I want to write, and I selected my first project today.
https://github.com/mischavandenburg/twitter-cli
https://twitter.com/mischa_vdburg
Twitter CLI Programs should solve a problem.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When learning a programming language it is important to start building things quickly and to begin applying the theory. I have a tendency to dive into the books and lose myself in the theory, where I should be getting hands on experience.</p>
<p>Over the past few months I&rsquo;ve generated a bunch of ideas for projects that I want to write, and I selected my first project today.</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/mischavandenburg/twitter-cli">https://github.com/mischavandenburg/twitter-cli</a></p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/mischa_vdburg">https://twitter.com/mischa_vdburg</a></p>
<h1 id="twitter-cli">Twitter CLI</h1>
<p>Programs should solve a problem. My problem has to do with Twitter. I recently created a Twitter account, and I want to make a tweet whenever I publish something new on my website. I&rsquo;m currently doing this by hand, and that needs to stop, obviously.</p>
<p>There are bots out there for this, but I want to build it myself. I&rsquo;ve created the following user stories for my project.</p>
<h2 id="user-story-1">User Story 1</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>As a user, I need a command that I can run from a bash shell that will post the standard input to my Twitter account</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="user-story-2">User Story 2</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>As a user, I need a command that I can run from a bash shell that will take the latest post from the RSS feed generated by my blog and post it to Twitter</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="concepts">Concepts</h2>
<p>By writing this program I&rsquo;ll need to figure out the following problems in Go:</p>
<ul>
<li>Taking input from the command line</li>
<li>Authenticating to the Twitter API</li>
<li>Making a POST request to the Twitter API</li>
<li>Curling an RSS feed</li>
<li>Looping over / reading XML / HTML data</li>
<li>Transforming that data to a suitable format to post to Twitter</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="expansion">Expansion</h1>
<p>This will be a good start for my project and will keep me busy for a while. When I solved the previous problems I can use the result and expand further. Some thoughts about further expansion:</p>
<h2 id="rss-feeds">RSS Feeds</h2>
<p>I can use the skills I learn to start crawling Reddit feeds and filter them for keywords. I can automatically generate a curated selection from Reddit which will be easier to consume and will save me time by only serving me content that I might think is interesting to me, based on keywords.</p>
<h2 id="database">Database</h2>
<p>I want to learn more about using databases on Kubernetes and how to interact with databases using Go. For this I&rsquo;d like to store my RSS feed into a database and keep track of information in the database. I could track whether an article has been posted to Twitter and when.</p>
<h2 id="bot">Bot</h2>
<p>Rather than posting my latest blog post to Twitter by manually running a command, I should have a bot scanning my blog and posting to Twitter when it detects a new article. Or I could trigger the bot whenever I make a push to my blog repo.</p>
<p>In any case, I want to have an application running on a server. I&rsquo;m making plans to start up a proper home lab and this will be a perfect use case to start running on my home Kubernetes cluster.</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202304081304</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/mischavandenburg/twitter-cli">https://github.com/mischavandenburg/twitter-cli</a></p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/mischa_vdburg">https://twitter.com/mischa_vdburg</a></p>
<p>[[go]]</p>
<p>[[go-twitter-cli-project]]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes Resource Management for Pods and Containers - CPU and Memory</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/kubernetes-resource-management-pods-containers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/kubernetes-resource-management-pods-containers/</guid>
      <description>Pods have containers, and limits can be set on those containers.
Requests used by the kube-scheduler to determine where the Pod will be placed containers can use more than requested resources if it is available on node If a limit is specified, but no request, Kubernetes will use the limit value as the request value.
Limits containers may never use more than the set limit
enforced by kubelet and container</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pods have containers, and limits can be set on those containers.</p>
<h1 id="requests">Requests</h1>
<ul>
<li>used by the kube-scheduler to determine where the Pod will be placed</li>
<li>containers can use more than requested resources if it is available on node</li>
</ul>
<p>If a limit is specified, but no request, Kubernetes will use the limit value as the request value.</p>
<h1 id="limits">Limits</h1>
<ul>
<li>
<p>containers may never use more than the set limit</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>enforced by kubelet and container</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>host kernel will kill processes that attempt to allocate more than limit (OOM error)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>reactively: killed when exceeded</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>enforcement: system prevents container to ever exceed limit</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>If the node runs out of memory and the container exceeds its memory request, the pod will be evicted</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>container runtimes don&rsquo;t terminate Pods or containers for excessive CPU usage</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="pods">Pods</h1>
<p>The pod resource request and limit is the sum of the resource requests of the containers in the pod.</p>
<h1 id="cpu-units">CPU Units</h1>
<p>Defined as an absolute amount of resource. 1000m = 1 CPU.</p>
<p>This is always the same unit, regardless whether the host has 4 or 48 CPU&rsquo;s.</p>
<p>500m CPU = 0.5 CPU</p>
<h1 id="memory-units">Memory Units</h1>
<p>Can use P, T, G, M etc.</p>
<p>Note that &ldquo;m&rdquo; is not megabyte. 0.8m = 0.8 bytes.</p>
<p>Use mebibytes Mi or megabytes M.</p>
<h1 id="definiton-example">Definiton Example</h1>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"><code class="language-yaml" data-lang="yaml"><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="nt">spec</span><span class="p">:</span><span class="w">
</span></span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="w">  </span><span class="nt">containers</span><span class="p">:</span><span class="w">
</span></span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="w">  </span>- <span class="nt">name</span><span class="p">:</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="l">nginx</span><span class="w">
</span></span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="w">    </span><span class="nt">image</span><span class="p">:</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="l">nginx</span><span class="w">
</span></span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="w">    </span><span class="nt">resources</span><span class="p">:</span><span class="w">
</span></span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="w">      </span><span class="nt">requests</span><span class="p">:</span><span class="w">
</span></span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="w">        </span><span class="nt">memory</span><span class="p">:</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="l">100Mi</span><span class="w">
</span></span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="w">        </span><span class="nt">cpu</span><span class="p">:</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="l">250m</span><span class="w">
</span></span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="w">      </span><span class="nt">limits</span><span class="p">:</span><span class="w">
</span></span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="w">        </span><span class="nt">memory</span><span class="p">:</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="l">200Mi</span><span class="w">
</span></span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="w">        </span><span class="nt">cpu</span><span class="p">:</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="l">500m</span><span class="w">
</span></span></span></code></pre></div><h1 id="scheduling">Scheduling</h1>
<p>The scheduler ensures that the sum of requests of the pods on the node does not exceed the available resources.</p>
<p>Even if a node has low resource usage, it will not accept pods that have requests which exceed the available resources.</p>
<h1 id="nodes">Nodes</h1>
<p>use <code>k describe node</code> to see the resource status of the node.</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202303281903</p>
<p><a href="https://kubernetes.io/docs/concepts/configuration/manage-resources-containers/">https://kubernetes.io/docs/concepts/configuration/manage-resources-containers/</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Difference Between DevOps, Cloud and Cloud Native</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/cloud-cloudnative-devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/cloud-cloudnative-devops/</guid>
      <description>I found an excellent video by Rob Muhlenstein explaining the differences between Cloud, Cloud Native and DevOps. Here are the notes I wrote.
Cloud These are primarily cloud services. The external cloud.
&amp;ldquo;Something as a Service&amp;rdquo;.
Amazon Azure GCP Cloud Native This is Cloud Native: The CNCF Landscape
Cloud Native is the technology that makes the cloud possible, and all the technology dependent on those services.
Computing Edge Computing
High Performance Computing</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I found <a href="https://youtu.be/gyjRriOyw-k">an excellent video</a> by Rob Muhlenstein explaining the differences between Cloud, Cloud Native and DevOps. Here are the notes I wrote.</p>
<h1 id="cloud">Cloud</h1>
<p>These are primarily <em>cloud services</em>. The external cloud.</p>
<p>&ldquo;Something as a Service&rdquo;.</p>
<ul>
<li>Amazon</li>
<li>Azure</li>
<li>GCP</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="cloud-native">Cloud Native</h1>
<p>This is Cloud Native: <a href="https://landscape.cncf.io/">The CNCF Landscape</a></p>
<p>Cloud Native is the technology that makes the cloud possible, and all the technology dependent on those services.</p>
<h2 id="computing">Computing</h2>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Edge Computing</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>High Performance Computing</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Encapsulates all of the technologies that are involved with containerization of work, jobs and nodes</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Deployment of compute resources as nodes</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>This is why Google&rsquo;s Borg was called Borg</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Computers are drones of a larger collective</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Every node puts all the resources into the collective.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>The collective is all the nodes combined, and Kubernetes is the Borg that orchestrates everything. It sees available resources and allocates the work that needs to be done.</p>
<p>Borg is the internal system developed at Google to run their infrastructure. You can read about it in the <a href="https://sre.google/books/">Site Reliability Engineering</a> books and I highly recommend them.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Kubernetes is /proc for the cloud</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Rob Muhlenstein</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="most-important-technologies">Most Important Technologies</h2>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Docker, Dockerfiles</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Kubernetes</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Helm</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Harbor</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Different registries, harbor, quay</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>It is a lot of Python and POSIX shell</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Go for infrastructure application development</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Kubernetes and Helm have won the game</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="containers-size-matters">Containers: Size Matters</h2>
<ul>
<li>Size matters (again) in the cloud</li>
<li>The smaller your container the better, because it takes less resources and less costs</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="devops">DevOps</h1>
<p>DevOps is not the same as Cloud Native. It is one piece of it, a specific set of practices and actions that can be done within Cloud Native.</p>
<ul>
<li>How you write software and release it</li>
<li>CI/CD</li>
<li>Focused on getting the software out</li>
<li>GitLab has become the one stop shop</li>
<li>Purpose is to write software and get it published fast</li>
<li>GitOps</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="summary">Summary</h1>
<p>In summary, &ldquo;cloud&rdquo; stands for the services offered by cloud providers such as AWS, Azure and GCP. Cloud Native stands for all of the technology that makes these cloud services possible. DevOps is part of Cloud Native, but definitely not the same thing. DevOps is concerned with how software is written and released.</p>
<h1 id="links">Links:</h1>
<p>202303262003</p>
<p><a href="https://youtu.be/gyjRriOyw-k">https://youtu.be/gyjRriOyw-k</a></p>
<p><a href="https://landscape.cncf.io/">https://landscape.cncf.io/</a></p>
<p><a href="https://sre.google/books/">https://sre.google/books/</a></p>
<p>[[rwxrob]]</p>
<p>[[devops]]</p>
<p>[[kubernetes]]</p>
<p>[[cloud-native]]</p>
<p>[[cncf]]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
