<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Productivity on Mischa van den Burg</title>
    <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/productivity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Productivity on Mischa van den Burg</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/productivity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Azure Exams Are Open Book Exams From Now On</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/azure-exams-open-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/azure-exams-open-book/</guid>
      <description>From here on out you can access Microsoft Learn during the exams. This is great news! This is much more like the actual experience of an engineer&amp;rsquo;s daily activities. It is arguably more important to look up things efficiently rather than memorizing everything for a test and forgetting it a few weeks later.
Links: 202308231608
https://youtu.be/iPiq3YuhnHc</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>From here on out you can access Microsoft Learn during the exams. This is great news! This is much more like the actual experience of an engineer&rsquo;s daily activities. It is arguably more important to look up things efficiently rather than memorizing everything for a test and forgetting it a few weeks later.</p>

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/iPiq3YuhnHc" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202308231608</p>
<p><a href="https://youtu.be/iPiq3YuhnHc">https://youtu.be/iPiq3YuhnHc</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Power of Writing</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/power-of-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/power-of-writing/</guid>
      <description>Ah, writing. It&amp;rsquo;s one of the skills that I&amp;rsquo;ve consistently been praised for throughout my life. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty good at it, and I think that&amp;rsquo;s because I enjoy it. It led me to getting an academic degree in English Literature and Culture, simply because I was following the things I was naturally good at.
However, just like any other skill, you can only become better at it through consistent practice. This morning I read a wonderful little blog post on writing regularly, and I was touched by his words:</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ah, writing. It&rsquo;s one of the skills that I&rsquo;ve consistently been praised for throughout my life. I&rsquo;m pretty good at it, and I think that&rsquo;s because I enjoy it. It led me to getting an academic degree in English Literature and Culture, simply because I was following the things I was naturally good at.</p>
<p>However, just like any other skill, you can only become better at it through consistent practice. This morning I read a wonderful little blog post <a href="https://herman.bearblog.dev/on-writing-regularly/">on writing regularly</a>, and I was touched by his words:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Similarly, some people believe that the art of writing is a skill that can be summoned on a whim, like a genie emerging from a lamp with a flourish of creative brilliance. In my experience, however, writing is more akin to the labour of a blacksmith, hamming words into shape through the heat and sweat of regular practise.</p>
</blockquote>
<h1 id="daily-practice">Daily Practice</h1>
<p>One way to gain more experience is to start keeping a daily journal. I&rsquo;ve always kept some notebook or other, jotting down thoughts and ideas as they came along sporadically. But it was only in July 2020 that I started <a href="https://www.artofmanliness.com/character/behavior/30-days-to-a-better-man-day-8-start-a-journal/">to keep a daily journal</a> and writing regularly. I started out writing by hand. I was in at an interesting place in life: I was spending two years in a Buddhist monastery, and after settling down for a couple of months, the intensive meditation practice was releasing all sorts of things in the mind and body, and I started to write them all down. I&rsquo;m still convinced that starting this habit has been one of the most important and beneficial decisions of my life.</p>
<p>It is so simple, but extremely effective. And you don&rsquo;t have to be doing anything special, or be in a special place. Just keeping a daily journal where you note down the things you did that day in a small pocket book is enough to get the habit going. Soon you will find that you will get the urge to write more. After several years of daily journaling, sometimes all I write is &ldquo;It&rsquo;s been a pretty good day&rdquo;. And that&rsquo;s it for that day. Sometimes I write several pages worth of thoughts, ideas and these longer writings often have powerful effects.</p>
<h1 id="the-power-of-writing">The Power Of Writing</h1>
<p>Sometimes I&rsquo;ll be struggling with something, and I&rsquo;ll be at a loss of what to do. The thoughts just keep whirling about aimlessly and no solution to the particular problem at hand seems to emerge from the chaos. Whenever I am in such a situation, I sit down, close my eyes, observe what is going on, and I start to write. I write it all down. The thoughts, the associations that these thoughts generate, and the effects they are having. I write down exactly how I feel. Attaching words to the feelings that I&rsquo;m experiencing mentally and physically. &ldquo;I feel a contraction in my lower abdomen&rdquo;. &ldquo;I&rsquo;m angry, and it manifests as a hot feeling on my forehead&rdquo;. And that&rsquo;s when the magic happens: something that I&rsquo;ve come to identify as &ldquo;The Power Of Writing&rdquo;.</p>
<p>Somehow the act of writing everything down will create structure in the chaos, and the solution to my problem wil emerge, often from very unexpected angles. Is it the fact that it is structured on paper? Or the fact that the visual representation of the contents of my mind enables me to apply structure to them? Is it the fact that I am moving my hands, adding bodily movement to my cognitive efforts?</p>
<p>I don&rsquo;t have the exact answer, but all I know is that it works for me. Almost every time. And often when I don&rsquo;t expect it at all. I&rsquo;ll just be sitting and writing in my journal, writing down a particular challenge that I&rsquo;m facing that day. And somehow some solution appears out of the blue. Whenever this happens, I always smile and write down: &ldquo;The Power of Writing&rdquo;.</p>
<h1 id="mindfulness">Mindfulness</h1>
<p>Even though I might not know the exact answer, I&rsquo;m certain that it is very closely related to mindfulness. Becoming more mindful through meditation and present moment awareness is the key to happiness in my opnion. I developed a mindfulness practice out of writing by creating this ritual where I sit down and identify what is going on and writing it down. In essence, I&rsquo;m forcing myself to be mindful, and to attach words to my mental and bodily experience. I&rsquo;m getting out of my own way and letting my mind solve the challenge all by itself.</p>
<p>You know what? It&rsquo;s happening right now! The Power of Writing. I hadn&rsquo;t been able to clearly capture in words what the mechanism behind the Power of Writing was, but as I was writing this article, it became obvious to me that it must be mindfulness underlying it all. So I&rsquo;m just going to leave it as it is. This is a perfect example of what you will find in my private zettelkasten. I wrote all of this in one sitting, with minimal editing. Just stream of conciousness, writing it down. And I finished with a wonderful realization.</p>
<p>I feel grateful, satsified and happy. There is also a pleasant tingling at the top of my neck, and an energy rising up through my feet. I hope that this might help someone else one day, and inspire someone to pick up the habit of writing.</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202305012005</p>
<p><a href="https://herman.bearblog.dev/on-writing-regularly/">https://herman.bearblog.dev/on-writing-regularly/</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Check The Weather From The Command Line</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/check-weather-terminal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/check-weather-terminal/</guid>
      <description>For the past few months I&amp;rsquo;ve been using this neat API to check the weather from the command line. It&amp;rsquo;s very simple to use. Simply run:
curl wttr.in
This will show the weather based on your location, but you can also give a particular location and format.
curl wttr.in/Amsterdam
Links: 202304271504
https://github.com/chubin/wttr.in</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For the past few months I&rsquo;ve been using this neat API to check the weather from the command line. It&rsquo;s very simple to use. Simply run:</p>
<p><code>curl wttr.in</code></p>
<p>This will show the weather based on your location, but you can also give a particular location and format.</p>
<p><code>curl wttr.in/Amsterdam</code></p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202304271504</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/chubin/wttr.in">https://github.com/chubin/wttr.in</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video: How To Read The News From The Command Line</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/reading-news-from-command-line/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/reading-news-from-command-line/</guid>
      <description>I use RSS feeds to read the news, and I use Newsboat as a RSS reader.
To in stall on MacOS: brew install newsboat
Integrate in already existing terminal workflow Free from distraction Control how content is rendered Carefully curate which content you consume Build your own &amp;ldquo;Social Media feed&amp;rdquo; No advertisements or suggested articles Newsboat uses RSS feeds which are generated by websites Links: 202304271004
https://newsboat.org/</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/08SxwJ7ZVyo" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<p>I use RSS feeds to read the news, and I use Newsboat as a RSS reader.</p>
<p>To in stall on MacOS: <code>brew install newsboat</code></p>
<ul>
<li>Integrate in already existing terminal workflow</li>
<li>Free from distraction</li>
<li>Control how content is rendered</li>
<li>Carefully curate which content you consume</li>
<li>Build your own &ldquo;Social Media feed&rdquo;</li>
<li>No advertisements or suggested articles</li>
<li>Newsboat uses RSS feeds which are generated by websites</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202304271004</p>
<p><a href="https://newsboat.org/">https://newsboat.org/</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcast Notes: Dopamine and Motivation - Huberman</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/dopamine-and-motivation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/dopamine-and-motivation/</guid>
      <description>Dopamine Listened to an interesting podcast on Dopamine by Andrew Huberman. I always enjoy his content because he is completely driven by science, not by personal opinion. He is truly objective as far as I can tell.
Dopamine is often misunderstood. It is not necessarily associated with good feelings after you pursue an activity. It is more related to motivation to engage in certain behaviours.
Rewards Scientists did an experiment where they observed children of kindergarten age, and later reproduced this in adults.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="dopamine">Dopamine</h1>
<p>Listened to <a href="https://hubermanlab.com/leverage-dopamine-to-overcome-procrastination-and-optimize-effort/">an interesting podcast on Dopamine</a> by Andrew Huberman. I always enjoy his content because he is completely driven by science, not by personal opinion. He is truly objective as far as I can tell.</p>
<p>Dopamine is often misunderstood. It is not necessarily associated with good feelings after you pursue an activity. It is more related to motivation to engage in certain behaviours.</p>
<h1 id="rewards">Rewards</h1>
<p>Scientists did an experiment where they observed children of kindergarten age, and later reproduced this in adults. The children were monitored during school days, where they had blocks of structured time and free time. During structured time their activities were managed. They had to sing or write, for example. Then they had blocks of free time where they could do whatever activity they liked.</p>
<p>They observed what activity the children liked to do in their free time, and then started to reward these children for their work. For example, if the children liked to draw in their free time, the researches started giving them gold stars and other praise for their work.</p>
<p>Then the researches removed the reward for the activity, and interestingly, the children and adults started showing less interest and enjoyment in the activity because they were lacking the reward.Note that this is the activity that they liked to do in their free time prior to the experiment.</p>
<p>This all has to do with the nature of dopamine, dopamine baselines and peaks.</p>
<p>Huberman explains this with a metaphor of a pool. In the pool you have waves, and the waves have peaks and troughs. At the peaks, your dopamine is high, but they are inevitably followed by troughs: dips in dopamine, which lead to low energy and low motivation.</p>
<p>Then there is the baseline of dopamine: the amount of water in the pool. The baseline is the relative point to which the peaks and throughs are determined.</p>
<p>So it is important that you don&rsquo;t reward yourself for activities that you are doing. Don&rsquo;t reward yourself too much when you achieve a fitness or study goal. You will feel good after the event, but you will end up in a through. Being in the trough means feeling demotivated, leading to procrastination.</p>
<h1 id="getting-out-of-the-trough">Getting Out Of The Trough</h1>
<p>The good news is that the system will reset itself after experiencing highs or lows due to rewards.Getting out of the trough happens automatically, but you can influence the rate at which you climb out of it.</p>
<p>Let&rsquo;s say you are not motivated to study. You&rsquo;ll need to do something which is more painful. Something that&rsquo;s even harder to do. Whatever feels harder to do in the moment than the activity that you <em>should</em> be doing. Do something that makes you feel uncomfortable.</p>
<h2 id="tactics">Tactics</h2>
<ul>
<li>exercise for 1 minute</li>
<li>do something that really sucks
<ul>
<li>cold water</li>
<li>anything that makes you cringe</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>leverage something that&rsquo;s painful</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="the-holy-grail-of-motivation">The Holy Grail Of Motivation</h1>
<p>The holy grail of motivation: not needing any external reward, but enjoying the activity itself that is leading you towards your goal. For example, enjoying running training in pursuit of a marathon goal. Enjoying coding and doing coding exercises in pursuit of becoming a software engineer.</p>
<p>I feel very fortunate that I succeeded at turning my passion into my career. The journey itself is fun. I enjoy coding, and that activity is taking me closer towards the goal of becoming a good software engineer and the ability to contribute to open source.</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202303311903</p>
<p><a href="https://hubermanlab.com/leverage-dopamine-to-overcome-procrastination-and-optimize-effort/">https://hubermanlab.com/leverage-dopamine-to-overcome-procrastination-and-optimize-effort/</a></p>
<p>[[my ikigai and flow]]</p>
<p>[[coding]]</p>
<p>[[devops]]</p>
<p>[[career]]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exercise Stimulates Creativity And Motivation</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/exercise-stimulates-creativity-and-motivation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/exercise-stimulates-creativity-and-motivation/</guid>
      <description>I noticed multiple times now that during my workouts my mind is generating lots of new ideas for coding projects or blog posts. It is a well known fact that walking stimulates areas in the brain that which will in turn stimulate creativity. But I&amp;rsquo;m noticing that it starts to happen with strength workouts as well.
Although I don&amp;rsquo;t struggle with the motivation to get myself to the gym, I sometimes feel &amp;ldquo;guilty&amp;rdquo; for not spending that time on coding or studying.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I noticed multiple times now that during my workouts my mind is generating lots of new ideas for coding projects or blog posts. It is a well known fact that walking stimulates areas in the brain that which will in turn stimulate creativity. But I&rsquo;m noticing that it starts to happen with strength workouts as well.</p>
<p>Although I don&rsquo;t struggle with the motivation to get myself to the gym, I sometimes feel &ldquo;guilty&rdquo; for not spending that time on coding or studying. I&rsquo;m realizing now that this is a very irrational train of thought.</p>
<p>Exercise actually stimulates my creativity and will help generating new ideas or help me understand concepts better in the unconscious. It is also massively beneficial for health and general well being. When general well-being is enhanced I&rsquo;ll also be able to focus better and absorb information more quickly.</p>
<p>I should re-frame my thinking and actually put exercise as priority number 1. Exercise time is never wasted time. It indirectly contributes to my productivity and coding endeavours as well.</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202304011104</p>
<p>[[exercise]]</p>
<p>[[health]]</p>
<p>[[focus]]</p>
<p>[[productivity]]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Neovim Zettelkasten: How I Take Notes in Markdown Using Vim and Bash</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/neovim-zettelkasten/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/neovim-zettelkasten/</guid>
      <description>I used to make all my notes on paper, but I decided to switch to a digital note-taking system about two years ago.
Digital note-taking provides the following advantages:
Searchability Collected in one place Can be converted to different output formats Easier to share with others Does not take up physical space No risk of losing your notes in case of fire or other disaster I&amp;rsquo;ve gone through several iterations of my note-taking systems.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I used to make all my notes on paper, but I decided to switch to a digital note-taking system about two years ago.</p>
<p>Digital note-taking provides the following advantages:</p>
<ul>
<li>Searchability</li>
<li>Collected in one place</li>
<li>Can be converted to different output formats</li>
<li>Easier to share with others</li>
<li>Does not take up physical space</li>
<li>No risk of losing your notes in case of fire or other disaster</li>
</ul>
<p>I&rsquo;ve gone through several iterations of my note-taking systems. I started on Google Docs, moved on to Notion and eventually landed on Obsidian. However, as I became more proficient with UNIX systems and vim, I realized I did not need all of that distracting functionality, and I switched over to using Neovim and a few bash scripts. I occasionally open up Obsidian to look at my graph view or to make use of the Anki plugin, but I enjoy the trimmed-down version that I built myself. I don&rsquo;t need to leave the command line to read my notes or to create a new one.</p>
<p>In this article I&rsquo;ll show you the system I&rsquo;m currently using for note-taking. My note-taking system is part of a larger system which I call my &ldquo;Second Brain&rdquo;, <a href="https://fortelabs.com/blog/basboverview/">a term coined by Tiago Forte.</a> This is an overarching system I&rsquo;ve build to manage my time, projects, tasks and bookmarks. Explaining this entire system is beyond the scope of this article, but I plan to write about my Second Brain in the future as well.</p>
<p>My system is based on the Zettelkasten method, but I&rsquo;ve adjusted it to my own needs. After a few years of experimentation I feel that my system has reached a &ldquo;mature&rdquo; state, but it will always remain continuosly under development, also because my needs may change.</p>
<h1 id="what-is-a-zettelkasten">What is a Zettelkasten?</h1>
<p>Zettelkasten is a system of note taking and personal knowledge management. <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zettelkasten">Zettelkasten</a> means &ldquo;slip box&rdquo; in German. Traditionally it is a physical box of slips of paper or index cards containing smaller notes. Each of these cards have a unique identifier, and these identifiers are used to create links between the cards.</p>
<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Niklas_Luhmann">Niklas Luhmann</a>, who was one of the most prolific scholars in history, used it extensively. He wrote 70 books and nearly 400 academic articles, and he credited the Zettelkasten with making his productivity possible. It contained around 90,000 index cards.</p>
<p>I first came across this concept by reading the book <a href="https://www.soenkeahrens.de/en/takesmartnotes">How to take Smart Notes</a> by Sönke Ahrens.</p>
<h1 id="why-take-notes">Why Take Notes?</h1>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Your professional success and quality of life depend directly on your ability to manage information effectively.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Tiago Forte, Building A Second Brain</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In the modern age we consume very large amounts of information, much more than we can remember. It is therefore very important to manage your intake of information, but also the retention of that information. I find that taking notes on the topics that may be of interest to me at any given time helps me understand the subject much better, because it forces me to clearly formulate my thoughts and convert them to written form.</p>
<p>Over time a large collection is built up which can be used to generate new ideas.</p>
<h1 id="what-do-i-take-notes-on">What Do I Take Notes On?</h1>
<p>Firstly, I keep a daily journal where I write down my thoughts, my feelings and the activities that I undertake. Some days may be several pages worth, and other days will be only &ldquo;Had a nice day today&rdquo;. But I make a point to write something down every day.</p>
<p>Secondly, I write about the topics I study. I&rsquo;m always learning something new. I&rsquo;m a DevOps Cloud Engineer, and new developments are made constantly in the Cloud Native landscape. There is always more to learn.</p>
<p>My notes are not only work related. I also keep notes of the research I do for all of my interests, such as health, longevity, exercise, diet, literature, yoga and meditation. I made a habit out of always writing a note when I read a book, watch a documentary or listen to a podcast. These notes can be a short summary, a few thoughts that come to mind, or a few bullet points that capture the main takeaways.</p>
<p>These activities are usually accompanied by taking notes:</p>
<ul>
<li>Reading books</li>
<li>Watching video courses</li>
<li>Watching educational YouTube videos</li>
<li>Researching hobbies and interests</li>
<li>Coding</li>
<li>Reflection</li>
<li>Interesting conversations</li>
<li>Listening to podcasts</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="an-overview-of-my-system">An Overview of My System</h1>
<p>My system is a modified Zettelkasten system that incorporates daily notes for journaling. The Zettelkasten method emphasizes small atomic notes containing only your own thoughts and links to other notes. However, I choose to also make longer notes. For example, when I did the <a href="https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/articles/fundamentals-of-bicep">Fundamentals of Bicep</a> course, I made one large note that contains all of the information I wished to remember or refer to later. In this particular use case, I think it&rsquo;s much better to keep everything collected in one note, rather than breaking this note up in smaller notes on parameters and variables, for example.</p>
<p>Another area where I diverge from the traditional Zettelkasten is categorization of notes. Traditionally the Zettelkasten is one big repository of notes, but I like to keep them loosely collected. When I create a new note, my system places that note in an inbox directory. Once a week I go through my inbox and revisit all of my notes. Sometimes I will throw some notes away because I don&rsquo;t think they&rsquo;re necessary after all. When I decide to keep it, I put it in a directory that I find suitable. I have a directory structure based on the <a href="https://fortelabs.com/blog/para/">PARA method</a>, but I also have a large Zettelkasten directory where I put anything that does not necessary belong to a category. I mostly keep some notes collected in a directory because I expect to use them as a collection at some point, or because I want to run scripts on the files.</p>
<p>Every day a daily note is created that contains a few checkboxes for habit tracking and sometimes I&rsquo;ll include an inspirational quote in my template for a while.</p>
<p>This is what a daily note looks like in my editor:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/dailynote.png" type="" alt=""  /></p>
<h1 id="local-text-files">Local Text Files</h1>
<p>I think it is important to use locally stored markdown text files. This is mainly why I moved away from Notion. My notes are stored on my local machine rather than with a third party. This gives me complete control over my data.</p>
<p>Because my notes are stored as markdown files, I can use various tools to write or edit my  notes. Moreover, storing my notes as local files allows me to run scripts on my notes and customize my workflow to my heart&rsquo;s content. This can be especially useful for automating tasks, streamlining my work, or making bulk updates.</p>
<p>I have my collection backed up in several places and on GitHub.</p>
<p>I recommend <a href="https://rwx.gg/lang/md/">this article</a> about the benefits and merits of using markdown for note-taking.</p>
<h1 id="vim-my-preferred-text-editor">Vim, My Preferred Text Editor</h1>
<p>I use Vim, or technically, Neovim for all of my text editing. It took a while to get used to, but my productivity related to text editing has increased significantly. I also find it very enjoyable to work on the command line, not having to leave my tmux window to manage my entire Zettelkasten or keep my journal.</p>
<p>My <a href="https://github.com/mischavandenburg/dotfiles">vim configuration</a> is always subject to constant change, but I only use three plugins that are related to my note-taking and Zettelkasten.</p>
<h2 id="1-telescope">1. Telescope</h2>
<p>I cannot live without <a href="https://github.com/nvim-telescope/telescope.nvim">this plugin</a> any longer. It is a fuzzy searcher integrated into my editor. I can search for files but also search within the files using ripgrep, and preview the files as I&rsquo;m searching.</p>
<p>Heres what a search for Neovim looks like:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/telescope.png" type="" alt=""  /></p>
<p>I can navigate through all the search results blazingly fast using only the keyboard, and I can preview the files by scrolling up and down in the window on the right hand side.</p>
<h2 id="2-marksman-lsp">2. Marksman LSP</h2>
<p>Marksman is a markdown language server which helps me format my documents and to create links between notes.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/marksman.png" type="" alt=""  /></p>
<p>When I start to make a link it will search through my entire Zettelkasten and look for matches based on the filename or markdown headers. Here it shows me suggestions related to markdown.</p>
<h2 id="3-pandoc">3. Pandoc</h2>
<p>According to Wikipedia, &ldquo;Pandoc is a free-software document converter, widely used as a writing tool (especially by scholars) and as a basis for publishing workflows.&rdquo;</p>
<p>I use the Pandoc plugin for vim to export my notes to different formats when I need to.</p>
<p>However, the thing I like most about it is that it renders my notes very nicely as I&rsquo;m writing them. I really like how headings look, and that it will <strong>make text bold</strong> while editing, which did not work when I used nvim-markdown.</p>
<h1 id="bash">Bash</h1>
<p>To facilitate my workflow I wrote a few bash scripts.</p>
<p>When I want to take a note, I run the <code>zet</code> command from the command line. This command is a bash script I wrote which creates a file in my inbox, adds a template to it, and opens the file in Neovim. I can either provide a filename to it as an argument or it will ask me to provide one.</p>
<p>I have another script named <code>blog</code> which I use to create notes that I intend on publishing on my website. These files are stored in a different location and use a different template. The blog script also has a <code>pub</code> function that will publish the script directly to my website in a few seconds after I&rsquo;m done writing.</p>
<p>These scripts can be found in my <a href="https://github.com/mischavandenburg/dotfiles/tree/main/scripts">dotfiles repo</a>.</p>
<h1 id="identifiers-and-filenames">Identifiers and Filenames</h1>
<p>The Zettelkasten method assigns unique identifiers to notes. I generate a unique identifier from the current date and time, but I never really use these identifiers. However, since I&rsquo;ve been doing this consistently from the beginning, I&rsquo;ll keep generating them to make my system future proof. Who knows, maybe they will become useful someday when I suddenly find a use case for it.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve seen other people use unique identifiers in filenames as well, but this is a big no for me. I want to be able to discern what the contents might be from the filename whenever I&rsquo;m navigating around my directory structure. Using the filename as the note identifier is a much better solution in my opinion. There is a small chance that you will choose a filename that already exists, but you can easily add a number to it or change a word and you have solved that problem.</p>
<p>Moreover, I use the marksman LSP server to create links between my notes in Neovim. The LSP server is based on headings and filenames, so I&rsquo;m really glad that I chose to use filenames such as &ldquo;fundamentals-of-bicep.md&rdquo; right from the beginning.</p>
<h1 id="tags-and-links">Tags and Links</h1>
<p>If you are as deep into note-taking systems as I am, you might have come across the problem of using tags versus using links for your note-taking system.</p>
<p>I primarily use <code>[[markdown links]]</code> to create links in my notes. This is also why you will sometimes see these things in my public zettelkasten. The links between notes are rendered beatifully by Obsidian in the graph view. This is also why I&rsquo;ll always try to keep my system compatible with Obsidian, even though I&rsquo;ve moved away from the application almost entirely.</p>
<p>Here is a graph view of my Zettelkasten:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/graph-view.png" type="" alt=""  /></p>
<p>For the notes in my Zettelkasten which are intended to be published on my website, I use tags in the YAML frontmatter. These are used by my static website generator, Hugo, to create tag pages on my website which I think will be useful to my readers.</p>
<p>Here is an example of the YAML front matter of one of these notes:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"><code class="language-yaml" data-lang="yaml"><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="nn">---</span><span class="w">
</span></span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="w"></span><span class="nt">title</span><span class="p">:</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="s2">&#34;I&#39;m In Love with my Work: Lessons from a Japanese Sushi Master&#34;</span><span class="w">
</span></span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="w"></span><span class="nt">date</span><span class="p">:</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="ld">2022-10-08</span><span class="w">
</span></span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="w"></span><span class="nt">tags</span><span class="p">:</span><span class="w">
</span></span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="w"></span>- <span class="l">Career</span><span class="w">
</span></span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="w"></span>- <span class="l">Personal</span><span class="w">
</span></span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="w"></span>- <span class="l">Article</span><span class="w">
</span></span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="w"></span><span class="nn">---</span><span class="w">
</span></span></span></code></pre></div><h1 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h1>
<p>That&rsquo;s about it. My system is a minimalistic set of tools utilized for maximum productivity. It&rsquo;s Neovim with a few plugins and a couple of helper scripts I wrote in bash that store markdown files in a directory structure that I find meaningful. After using many different applications and solutions, I&rsquo;m extremely satisfied with the system I built for  myself which is very basic, free from distractions and tailored to my own needs.</p>
<p>When I want to reflect on a certain topic or to write an article, I go through my collection of notes and link them together. Very often I find that the creation of these links will stimulate even more new connections and associations, and I end up with new ideas and more topics of study I want to explore and write about. I use my Zettelkasten as a vehicle for reflection, learning and creativity.</p>
<p>I love the simplicity of my system. It enables me to capture notes very quickly while I&rsquo;m working or studying with very little effort. By storing my note collection on my iCloud drive and in GitHub, they can be accessed from all of my devices across all different operating systems.</p>
<p>I hope that this article may give you some inspiration to start building your own note collection. You don&rsquo;t need to build your own system like I have done, any app that satisfies your needs can be used. Keeping notes on the things I encounter in life is one of the most enriching habits I&rsquo;ve acquired. It will be interesting to see how large my collection grows over the years!</p>
<h1 id="links">Links:</h1>
<p>202303270703</p>
<p><a href="https://fortelabs.com/blog/basboverview/">https://fortelabs.com/blog/basboverview/</a></p>
<p><a href="https://fortelabs.com/blog/para/">https://fortelabs.com/blog/para/</a></p>
<p><a href="https://rwx.gg/lang/md/">https://rwx.gg/lang/md/</a></p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/mischavandenburg/dotfiles/tree/main/scripts">https://github.com/mischavandenburg/dotfiles/tree/main/scripts</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Run Newsboat in Zenmode</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/newsboat-in-zenmode/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/newsboat-in-zenmode/</guid>
      <description>To read the news free from distractions and ads I use Newsboat as a reader for RSS feeds.
However, one thing that annoyed me was that it would span across my entire screen in the terminal. When you read blogs or news pages in the browser, you&amp;rsquo;ll notice that the text is always located in a middle column of the window, so you don&amp;rsquo;t have to move your neck while reading.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>To read the news free from distractions and ads I use Newsboat as a reader for RSS feeds.</p>
<p>However, one thing that annoyed me was that it would span across my entire screen in the terminal. When you read blogs or news pages in the browser, you&rsquo;ll notice that the text is always located in a middle column of the window, so you don&rsquo;t have to move your neck while reading. At least, this is the case with well designed websites that serve text content.</p>
<p>Vim has a plugin that achieves this and I use it extensively. It is called Zenmode. In Neovim I use a similar plugin called No Neckpain.</p>
<p>To achieve a similar configuration for Newsboat I used tmux. I wrote the following bash script:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash"><span class="line"><span class="cl">
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="c1">#!/bin/bash</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="c1"># nb opens a new pane and runs newsboat in it. I want to read from a centered column in my screen.</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">tmux split-pane -h <span class="se">\;</span> resize-pane -x 130<span class="se">\;</span> send -t <span class="m">2</span> <span class="s2">&#34;newsboat&#34;</span> Enter<span class="se">\;</span> send -t <span class="m">1</span> <span class="s2">&#34;clear&#34;</span> Enter
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>Note that this needs to be run from within an existing tmux window with no split panes.</p>
<p>It splits the current window in to two panes, resizes the new pane to a width of 130 pixels and sends the &ldquo;newsboat&rdquo; command to the new pane, and the &ldquo;clear&rdquo; command to the old (left) pane to keep it nice and clean.</p>
<p>In my <code>~/.newsboat/config</code> file I added the following setting:</p>
<p><code>text-width 72</code></p>
<p>This will limit the text on the right hand side of the screen.</p>
<p>The end result looks like this:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/newsboat-zen.png" type="" alt="Newsboat Zenmode"  /></p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202303260903</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/folke/zen-mode.nvim">https://github.com/folke/zen-mode.nvim</a></p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/shortcuts/no-neck-pain.nvim">https://github.com/shortcuts/no-neck-pain.nvim</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying out pandoc for vim</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/trying-out-pandoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/trying-out-pandoc/</guid>
      <description>I do all of my writing in markdown. I keep my diaries in my Second Brain, I constantly write notes on the topics I&amp;rsquo;m studying, and my entire blog is written in markdown.
Some of the writing is done in Obsidian but I&amp;rsquo;m moving away from Obsidian step by step. I&amp;rsquo;ll still keep my second brain compatible with it, but I want to be able to do all of my writing in (neo)vim.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I do all of my writing in markdown. I keep my diaries in my Second Brain, I constantly write notes on the topics I&rsquo;m studying, and my entire blog is written in markdown.</p>
<p>Some of the writing is done in Obsidian but I&rsquo;m moving away from Obsidian step by step. I&rsquo;ll still keep my second brain compatible with it, but I want to be able to do all of my writing in (neo)vim.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve been using nvim-markdown for a while now and I was quite happy with it, but it was bothering me that <strong>bold text</strong> was not rendered in my editor.</p>
<p>Pandoc had been on my radar for a while because it uses the Commonmark <a href="https://spec.commonmark.org/">markdown spec</a> and it can be used to convert to many different documentation types. It&rsquo;s an interesting thought to keep my entire collection of notes and writings compatible with something that can be converted into anything.</p>
<p>I noticed rwxrob uses pandoc as one of his few vim plugins.</p>
<p>It took me an hour to make it compatible with neovim and to disable the spelling and folding. I couldn&rsquo;t just set the provided variables because they are still in vimscript and I haven&rsquo;t figured out how to set them yet because they use a hashtag in their name #</p>
<p>So far I like it, but there are a few things that I miss from my nvim-markdown</p>
<ul>
<li>automatic bulleted list</li>
<li>nested bulleted lists
<ul>
<li>with nvim-markdown these lists would continue</li>
<li>Here I have to indent each line myself and add a bullet</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>navigation between headers
<ul>
<li>I didn&rsquo;t use this much to be honest, but I haven&rsquo;t figured it out in pandoc yet. Maybe it is possible?</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>I find myself using bullete lists and nested lists a lot in my notes, but I wonder if it is better to step away from those and make more use of markdown headings.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running Docker and Kubernetes on Mac M2</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/docker-kubernetes-on-mac-m2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/docker-kubernetes-on-mac-m2/</guid>
      <description>The past few days I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying out a few options to run Docker containers and a Kubernetes clusters on my new MacBook Pro M2.
Unfortunately you can&amp;rsquo;t just run brew install docker and expect it to work. Additionally, Docker desktop requires that you purchase a license if you use it for work purposes.
Minikube works fine as well, but the networking driver for qemu is not fully supported yet, and I haven&amp;rsquo;t tried any of the other alternatives because I found something better.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The past few days I&rsquo;ve been trying out a few options to run Docker containers and a Kubernetes clusters on my new MacBook Pro M2.</p>
<p>Unfortunately you can&rsquo;t just run <code>brew install docker</code> and expect it to work. Additionally, Docker desktop requires that you purchase a license if you use it for work purposes.</p>
<p>Minikube works fine as well, but the networking driver for qemu is not fully supported yet, and I haven&rsquo;t tried any of the other alternatives because I found something better.</p>
<p>Rancher Desktop provides everything that you need. It sets up a local VM where it will run a Kubernetes cluster using k3s. It will configure the containerd container engine for you which you can interact with using <code>nerdctl</code>.</p>
<p>To install:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash"><span class="line"><span class="cl">brew install rancher
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="c1">#after installing rancher, start it up and wait for it to boot the VM.</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="nb">alias</span> <span class="nv">docker</span><span class="o">=</span>nerdctl
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">docker run hello-world
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>And you&rsquo;re good to go. Rancher will add the rancher-desktop to your kube context.</p>
<p>To test your Kubernetes cluster:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash"><span class="line"><span class="cl">k get pods
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">k get nodes
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="c1"># test running a pod</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">k run nginx --image<span class="o">=</span>nginx
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">k expose pod nginx --port<span class="o">=</span><span class="m">80</span> --type<span class="o">=</span>NodePort
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="c1"># inspect your services and look for 80:31066/TCP under PORT(S)</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">k get svc
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">curl localhost:31066
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>Or visit localhost:31066 in your browser. Replace 31066 with the port you found listed under your services.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Controlling Apple Music with hotkeys from anywhere on MacOS</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/apple-music-hotkeys/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/apple-music-hotkeys/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a little obsessed with controlling everything with my keyboard. That&amp;rsquo;s why I loved AwesomeWM so much on my Arch Linux setup, I hardly used my mouse anymore.
One thing I loved about my setup was the ability to control my music from the keyboard from anywhere. This is a feature I picked up from the awesome-copycats theme for AwesomeWM. This was one of the first things I missed when I made my switch to MacOS.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m a little obsessed with controlling everything with my keyboard. That&rsquo;s why I loved AwesomeWM so much on my Arch Linux setup, I hardly used my mouse anymore.</p>
<p>One thing I loved about my setup was the ability to control my music from the keyboard from anywhere. This is a feature I picked up from the awesome-copycats theme for AwesomeWM. This was one of the first things I missed when I made my switch to MacOS.</p>
<p>I started using Apple Music as my music app but it does not have any global hotkeys, and it makes you use a widget with the mouse.</p>
<h1 id="skhd">skhd</h1>
<p>I solved the problem using <a href="https://github.com/koekeishiya/skhd">skhd</a>. This is a free hotkey daemon for MacOS. To install:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash"><span class="line"><span class="cl">brew install koekeishiya/formulae/skhd
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">brew services start skhd
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>Then I added the following to my skhd config file:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash"><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="c1"># Control apple music globally</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="c1"># Based on Aesome-copycats theme for AesomeWM</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">ctrl + cmd + fn - up : osascript -e <span class="s1">&#39;tell app &#34;Music&#34; to playpause&#39;</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">ctrl + cmd + fn - left : osascript -e <span class="s1">&#39;tell app &#34;Music&#34; to back track&#39;</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">ctrl + cmd + fn - right : osascript -e <span class="s1">&#39;tell app &#34;Music&#34; to play next track&#39;</span>
</span></span></code></pre></div><h1 id="links">links</h1>
<p><a href="https://github.com/koekeishiya/skhd">https://github.com/koekeishiya/skhd</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Laptop: Moving to MacOS</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/move-to-macos/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/move-to-macos/</guid>
      <description>My new employer kindly sponsored me with a new 16-inch MacBook Pro M2. I chose 32GB Ram and the base model with 12 CPU and 19 GPU cores and 1TB of hard disk. These specifications will suit my needs well.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been daily driving Linux for a year now, and it has been such an incredible journey. Building my own Arch Linux system taught me much about Linux and what it means to maintain a system yourself.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>My new employer kindly sponsored me with a new 16-inch MacBook Pro M2. I chose 32GB Ram and the base model with 12 CPU and 19 GPU cores and 1TB of hard disk. These specifications will suit my needs well.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve been daily driving Linux for a year now, and it has been such an incredible journey. Building my own Arch Linux system taught me much about Linux and what it means to maintain a system yourself. I will undoubtedly miss my custom AwesomeWM configuration and the freedom that Arch provides.</p>
<p>Technically I could have chosen a Windows laptop and installed Linux on it. But I went for a Mac for the following reasons:</p>
<ul>
<li>Compatibility. I&rsquo;ll be doing contracts for various customers, so I&rsquo;ll likely run into environments where I&rsquo;ll need to use some software, such as a VPN that is not supported on Linux. MacOS will always be compatible everywhere.</li>
<li>Portability. I&rsquo;ll probably be going to the office multiple times a week, and using a MacBook as a daily driver will allow me to take my full setup with me everywhere. I also plan to spend some time abroad, and using a MacBook as a daily driver will allow me to work remotely for extended periods.</li>
<li>Stability. Even though my Linux systems never really broke on me, there is always a possibility. I don&rsquo;t have to worry about that with MacOS.</li>
</ul>
<p>Even though I&rsquo;ll be switching to my MacBook as my primary workstation, I will continue using Linux for my hobby projects and home lab. So there will be plenty of opportunity to keep growing in that area in the future.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I passed the AZ-400 DevOps Expert today</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/passed-az-400/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/passed-az-400/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m typing this 30 minutes after I passed my AZ-400 exam. I&amp;rsquo;m sitting in a lovely cafe on Leidseplein in Amsterdam and feel relieved. Another significant certification bites the dust. This one took about 70 hours of study.
I started preparing immediately after passing my AZ-104 exam, which was a good move. The AZ-400 requires you to know many details about Azure services and how to access them. For example, Shared Access Signatures are only used for accessing storage accounts, but they came up quite often as alternative answers to the questions.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m typing this 30 minutes after I passed my AZ-400 exam. I&rsquo;m sitting in a lovely cafe on Leidseplein in Amsterdam and feel relieved. Another significant certification bites the dust. This one took about 70 hours of study.</p>
<p>I started preparing immediately after passing my AZ-104 exam, which was a good move. The AZ-400 requires you to know many details about Azure services and how to access them. For example, Shared Access Signatures are only used for accessing storage accounts, but they came up quite often as alternative answers to the questions.</p>
<p>The exam itself was difficult, but the AZ-104 was harder. The AZ-104 exam was more challenging because the questions were complicated and required you to simultaneously balance many different factors in the mind. The AZ-400 was difficult because the answer alternatives that are provided are incredibly similar to each other, and they make you very insecure about what the right choice might be. As a result, I changed my answers many times.</p>
<p>I will do another study guide for this certification soon and publish my notes and Anki deck too. Now it&rsquo;s time to celebrate and relax a little.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Pomodoro technique has won me over</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/pomodoro/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/pomodoro/</guid>
      <description>I did a lot of studying last year, and I achieved a few tough certifications. I&amp;rsquo;ve always been good at studying and never struggled with getting decent grades in university. As a result, I never felt the need to use particular techniques to pass my tests. However, now that I need to do my studies combined with a full-time job, I did some optimization and looked into study techniques.
One technique I&amp;rsquo;ve become very fond of is the Pomodoro Technique.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I did a lot of studying last year, and I achieved a few tough certifications. I&rsquo;ve always been good at studying and never struggled with getting decent grades in university. As a result, I never felt the need to use particular techniques to pass my tests. However, now that I need to do my studies combined with a full-time job, I did some optimization and looked into study techniques.</p>
<p>One technique I&rsquo;ve become very fond of is the Pomodoro Technique. I don&rsquo;t have any problems focusing for long periods, but I still decided to try it. I use the standard 25-minute study with a 5-minute break routine, and after four cycles, I take a 30-minute break.</p>
<p>The Pomodoro technique has been a way to force myself to take breaks, which I wasn&rsquo;t used to. I used to chip away at a specific task for hours. However, I discovered that when I take a break, walk around for five minutes, and apply myself to the task again, my mind is in a fresh state and much more receptive to the information. Perhaps the time I spend studying after a break is actually more productive because the mind had a little rest.</p>
<p>The technique also pushed my limits a bit more. I study more hours a day, considering that I also work full time. There is this moment where I want to quit studying, but I ask myself, &ldquo;do I have another Pomodoro in me?&rdquo;</p>
<p>Now that I&rsquo;ve gotten used to breaking things up into 25-minute chunks of time, I started using the Pomodoro technique for other areas in life as well, such as blog writing or coding projects.</p>
<p>You can use any tool you like to start using the Pomodoro technique and pick any break schedule that suits you. I&rsquo;ll link some resources below. All you need is some sort of timer. You can use a timer on your computer or a physical timer. I use the Forest app on my iPhone because it integrates with the iOs &ldquo;do not disturb&rdquo; and &ldquo;focus&rdquo; modes, so  I don&rsquo;t get any distracting notifications when I&rsquo;m on a Pomodoro.</p>
<p><a href="https://science.nichd.nih.gov/confluence/display/newsletter/2020/05/07/The+Pomodoro+Technique%3A+An+Effective+Time+Management+Tool">https://science.nichd.nih.gov/confluence/display/newsletter/2020/05/07/The+Pomodoro+Technique%3A+An+Effective+Time+Management+Tool</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5WRO79zuJ4U">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5WRO79zuJ4U</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fall in love with sed.</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/fall-in-love-with-sed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/fall-in-love-with-sed/</guid>
      <description>Sed, it&amp;rsquo;s so powerful. I remember I struggled with finding practical uses for it when I did my LPIC-1 certification. But now I find myself using it several times a week. It is so powerful to edit multiple files at a time. I use it for work, but also for making changes to my entire second brain in Obsidian with one command.
Today I needed to update my /articles/ links to /zet/articles/ links because I&amp;rsquo;m restructuring my website.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sed, it&rsquo;s so powerful. I remember I struggled with finding practical uses for it when I did my LPIC-1 certification. But now I find myself using it several times a week. It is so powerful to edit multiple files at a time. I use it for work, but also for making changes to my entire second brain in Obsidian with one command.</p>
<p>Today I needed to update my /articles/ links to /zet/articles/ links because I&rsquo;m restructuring my website. Here is the sed expression that is executed for every markdown file that is found by fd:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash"><span class="line"><span class="cl">sed -i <span class="s1">&#39;s/\/articles\//\/zet\/articles\//g&#39;</span> <span class="k">$(</span>fd .md<span class="k">)</span>
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>The result:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash"><span class="line"><span class="cl">diff --git a/content/zet/move-to-zet.md b/content/zet/move-to-zet.md
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">index 1e37283..3b817e3 <span class="m">100644</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">--- a/content/zet/move-to-zet.md
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">+++ b/content/zet/move-to-zet.md
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">@@ -6,7 +6,7 @@ tags:
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"> 
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"> ---
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">-I<span class="s1">&#39;ve transitioned my note taking system towards a Zettelkasten system. I still use directories for folders and make copious links, but more
</span></span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="s1">often than not I put them in the larger generic 00-zettelkasten directory in my [Obsidian](/articles/obsidian-introduction/) vault.
</span></span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="s1">+I&#39;</span>ve transitioned my note taking system towards a Zettelkasten system. I still use directories <span class="k">for</span> folders and make copious links, but more
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">often than not I put them in the larger generic 00-zettelkasten directory in my <span class="o">[</span>Obsidian<span class="o">](</span>/zet/articles/obsidian-introduction/<span class="o">)</span> vault.
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>These sites are super useful to help you formulate your expressions:</p>
<p><a href="https://sed.js.org/">https://sed.js.org/</a></p>
<p><a href="https://regex101.com/">https://regex101.com/</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How This Blog is Created, Written and Hosted</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/articles/how-this-blog-is-created/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/articles/how-this-blog-is-created/</guid>
      <description>As I alluded to in my article about Obsidian, I am very fond of editing my text in neovim. Naturally, if you want to edit in neovim, you need to have your text as local files. I keep all of my personal notes in markdown.
Previously I was using WordPress, but the editing and writing experience became torture which I could not endure any longer. I looked for a different solution that would allow me to edit my files locally instead of in the browser.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As I alluded to in my <a href="/zet/articles/obsidian-introduction">article about Obsidian,</a> I am very fond of editing my text in neovim. Naturally, if you want to edit in neovim, you need to have your text as local files. I keep all of my personal notes in markdown.</p>
<p>Previously I was using WordPress, but the editing and writing experience became torture which I could not endure any longer. I looked for a different solution that would allow me to edit my files locally instead of in the browser.</p>
<p>I discovered <a href="https://gohugo.io/">Hugo</a> and I fell in love with it immediately.</p>
<p>Hugo is a static site generator based on markdown files. My entire blog is written in markdown files which are stored <a href="https://github.com/mischavandenburg/blog">in a GitHub repo.</a>. I write my blog posts in vim and when I&rsquo;m done I use Hugo to generate the updated website.</p>
<p>The result is what you see in the &ldquo;public&rdquo; directory in the GitHub repo. This public directory is pushed to a different repo which is hooked up to my hosting provider. My hosting provider uses Plesk, and with Plesk I have the option to connect the GitHub repo to the web server with a webhook. When I push to my hosting repo, the contents are gathered by the webserver and served as public web content.</p>
<p>My complete writing and publishing workflow looks like this:</p>
<ol>
<li>Create a new markdown file</li>
<li>Write the note or article</li>
<li>Save the file and run the &ldquo;hugo&rdquo; command to regenerate the website</li>
<li>Run the &ldquo;publish&rdquo; script. This is a custom script I wrote that takes the contents of the &ldquo;public&rdquo; directory to my hosting repo</li>
<li>Push the newly generated website to the hosting repo</li>
<li>And we&rsquo;re live! 🚀 🎉</li>
</ol>
<p>It is such a smooth and convenient process. I can literally have a new note published to the interet within a few minutes, and it is all done from the command line using my favorite tools.</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/mischavandenburg/blog">Blog GitHub repo</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Obsidian: A Note Taking App For DevOps Engineers</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/articles/obsidian-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 19:05:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/articles/obsidian-introduction/</guid>
      <description>As a DevOps or Cloud engineer, you work with many different technologies daily. Therefore, a good engineer needs a solid foundation in Linux, a lot of knowledge about your cloud solution, networking, CI/CD, at least one programming language, and many other topics.
Not only are there many of these categories, but within these categories, there are several alternatives. For example, in the category of infrastructure management, there is Ansible, Puppet, or Chef, each with its particular approach and configuration methods.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As a DevOps or Cloud engineer, you work with many different technologies daily. Therefore, a good engineer needs a solid foundation in Linux, a lot of knowledge about your cloud solution, networking, CI/CD, at least one programming language, and many other topics.</p>
<p>Not only are there many of these categories, but within these categories, there are several alternatives. For example, in the category of infrastructure management, there is Ansible, Puppet, or Chef, each with its particular approach and configuration methods.</p>
<p>It can be challenging to keep everything memorized at all times. However, when I started my journey to become a DevOps engineer, I kept meticulous notes of everything I learned, and this practice has been highly beneficial so far. This blog is a result of the notes I keep every day.</p>
<p>Note-taking is an essential part of the DevOps engineer&rsquo;s toolkit. It allows you to stay organized, track changes, document processes, and keep track of important information. Using a powerful note-taking app like Obsidian can streamline your note-taking process and work more efficiently.</p>
<h1 id="obsidian-for-devops-engineers">Obsidian for DevOps engineers</h1>
<p>Having a reliable and efficient system in place for managing your notes and documentation is crucial. That&rsquo;s where <a href="https://obsidian.md/">Obsidian</a> comes in. Obsidian is a powerful note-taking app that can help you organize and manage your notes more efficiently.</p>
<p>One of the main features of Obsidian is its use of &ldquo;vaults.&rdquo; A vault is a folder containing your notes as markdown text files. Your notes are stored on your machine rather than in the cloud. This gives you complete control over your data. You always have access to your local text files and can interact with them or back them up as you see fit.</p>
<p>Because your notes are stored as markdown files, you can use different tools to write or edit your notes. I mostly use neovim for editing, but I use the Obsidian application for making new links and visualization. Moreover, storing your notes as files allows you to run python scripts on your notes and customize your workflow as needed. This can be especially useful for automating tasks, streamlining your work, or making bulk updates.</p>
<h1 id="links-and-graph-view">Links and graph view</h1>
<p>In addition to its local storage capabilities, Obsidian also offers several other valuable features for DevOps engineers. For example, you can use the &ldquo;graph view&rdquo; to visualize your notes and see how they&rsquo;re related to one another. This can be particularly useful for understanding complex systems and tracking changes over time.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/graph-view.png" type="" alt=""  /></p>
<p>These relations between notes are created by &ldquo;[[markdown links]]&rdquo;. When a note receives many links, its dot size will increase on the graph view, and in this manner, it is easy to see which notes or topics are significant in your vault and play an important role in your life.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/local-graph.png" type="" alt=""  /></p>
<p>This is the local graph view, showing all the linked notes to my Linux note.</p>
<h1 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h1>
<p>Many note-taking apps, such as Evernote, Notion, or Roam research, are available. I tried a few of these, but Obsidian was the best solution for me. Mainly because your notes are stored as markdown files on your machine and because they offer a syncing service with end-to-end encryption. Their graph view provides an interesting way to navigate your notes and discover unexpected connections.</p>
<p>Give it a try. It&rsquo;s free.</p>
<p><a href="https://obsidian.md/">Obsidian website</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
