<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Gaming on Mischa van den Burg</title>
    <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/gaming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gaming on Mischa van den Burg</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/gaming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My Plan For The D2R Ladder Reset</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/d2r-ladder-reset-may-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/d2r-ladder-reset-may-2023/</guid>
      <description>Diablo 2: one of those games in life I keep returning to. Started playing it when I was 12, and I know it inside out. Roughly once every 1,5 years I&amp;rsquo;ll have a phase where I want to play some.
I&amp;rsquo;m in such a phase right now. I haven&amp;rsquo;t been gaming since the Victoria 3 release, and frankly, I don&amp;rsquo;t have much time to spend either. Something will be sacrificed. Currently this will be study time.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Diablo 2: one of those games in life I keep returning to. Started playing it when I was 12, and I know it inside out. Roughly once every 1,5 years I&rsquo;ll have a phase where I want to play some.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m in such a phase right now. I haven&rsquo;t been gaming since the Victoria 3 release, and frankly, I don&rsquo;t have much time to spend either. Something will be sacrificed. Currently this will be study time. I&rsquo;ve been studying for several hours a day for nearly two years, but with my current increased focus on health and weight loss, I feel I need a break and allow myself some leasure.</p>
<p>Diablo 2 Resurrected will reset tomorrow and I&rsquo;ve been doing a little bit of research to get up to speed on the new Terror Zones and possible character builds. I think it&rsquo;s so lovely that Blizzard came out with Diablo 2 Resurrected 1,5 years ago, and that they&rsquo;re still adding new content to a nearly 20 year old game.</p>
<h1 id="terror-zones">Terror Zones</h1>
<p>An interesting addition to the game which will change end game levelling. From what I&rsquo;ve read, they are suited to farm solo from level 92 or so. Up until then Dia/Baal runs are still most efficient.</p>
<h1 id="builds">Builds</h1>
<p>One of the new interesting build possibilities in D2R is the Fire Druid. When D2R was launched I played an Trap assassin and a barbarian, so it will be fun to try something new. I haven&rsquo;t built a druid in many years, so I look forward to that.</p>
<p>I also considered doing a war cry barbarian, javazon or summon necromancer. But the fire druid appeals most to me currently.</p>
<h1 id="ladder">Ladder</h1>
<p>My plan is to just build one character, and I think I&rsquo;ll keep doing that in the future. When I feel like joining a ladder reset I&rsquo;ll just do one character, play it through the game, do some end game farming, and by then I&rsquo;ll probably be finished with Diablo for a while again.</p>
<h1 id="druid-strategy">Druid Strategy</h1>
<p>I&rsquo;ll be playing through the game in public games. Like every reset there will be a flood of cold sorceresses, so my fire damage will be a good addition to any party. From what I&rsquo;ve seen, the fire druid does a ton of damage with hardly any gear, so I probably won&rsquo;t have to much low level farming. I&rsquo;ll just focus on playing through the game asap and do any farming in hell difficulty.</p>
<h2 id="stats">Stats</h2>
<p>Str for gear, rest vita.</p>
<h2 id="skills">Skills</h2>
<p>1 point Oak Sage, and take some summons to get to grizzly. Aim for grizzly by nightmare. But don&rsquo;t prioritize. I&rsquo;ll be playing with parties, so probably not much need for summons, and I&rsquo;ll probably have to re-cast them all the time anyway which might actually be annoying. Maybe better to just focus on the fire skills.</p>
<p>Figure out which attack skill I like. Fissure can be fine through all of nightmare.</p>
<p>Alzorath&rsquo;s maxing path:</p>
<p>Fissure
Armageddon
Molten Boulder
Volcano
Firestorm</p>
<p>Cyclone armor: wait until you have a lot of + skills. So don&rsquo;t bother</p>
<h3 id="use-quick-cast">Use quick cast</h3>
<p>The quick cast feature is something new to me. As an old school player I was resistant to this feature. But from what I&rsquo;ve seen, it seems very effective with the fire skills.</p>
<h2 id="gear">Gear</h2>
<p>Tal Eth Stealth breast plate.</p>
<p>Ort Sol Lore. Save a 2soc druid helm for this</p>
<p>Buy 2soc staff tir ral at Akara asap.</p>
<p>Dual spirits</p>
<p>Magefist</p>
<h3 id="later-gear">Later gear</h3>
<p>Rain Armor
Ort Mal Ith</p>
<p>Ravenlore</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>2023050414055</p>
<p>Alzorath video guide:
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xPrpXS1OJ7M">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xPrpXS1OJ7M</a></p>
<p><a href="https://maxroll.gg/d2/guides/druid-leveling">https://maxroll.gg/d2/guides/druid-leveling</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
