<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Buddhism on Mischa van den Burg</title>
    <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/buddhism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Buddhism on Mischa van den Burg</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/buddhism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Importance Of Rest And Meditation When Making Changes To Routine</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/importance-rest-changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/importance-rest-changes/</guid>
      <description>Over the past two months I&amp;rsquo;ve increased the amount of exercise quite a lot. Over the past year or so I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing Brazilian Jiu Jitsu 1-2x a week and going for a 30-90 minute walk every day.
After I started running in February I have quit BJJ and changed to running 5-6 times a week, 30-60 minutes of Ashtangha Yoga almost every day and two calisthenics workouts a week. For my calisthenics I use rings and I do squats in the gym .</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Over the past two months I&rsquo;ve increased the amount of exercise quite a lot. Over the past year or so I&rsquo;ve been doing Brazilian Jiu Jitsu 1-2x a week and going for a 30-90 minute walk every day.</p>
<p>After I started running in February I have quit BJJ and changed to running 5-6 times a week, 30-60 minutes of Ashtangha Yoga almost every day and two calisthenics workouts a week. For my calisthenics I use rings and I do squats in the gym .</p>
<p>In addition, I reduced my calories to 1700 calories a day spread over two meals, doing 20 hours of fasting a day. I have also eliminated all sugar from my diet.</p>
<p>The reason I needed to do this is because my weight loss has plateaued for several months and I have at least 3kg more fat to lose until I reach my goal of 10% body fat.</p>
<p>Most people know me as someone who is very productive and frugal with his time, and that&rsquo;s true. I&rsquo;m always studying, writing, creating or learning in my free time. There is little to no time for girls and video games, I&rsquo;m on my purpose.</p>
<p>Yet I am also aware of the need of rest and relaxation. I haven&rsquo;t written much about it on my blog, and this will probably change in the time to come, but I am an established meditator and have a very solid mindfulness practice. I&rsquo;ll notice very quickly when I get out of balance and fortunately my practice has provided me with the wisdom to know what to do to bring things back into balance again.</p>
<p>Having introduced an increased amount of exercise and mental stress due to caloric restriction, I saw I needed to take a few steps back and allow my body and mind to adjust to these changes. I was already on caloric restriction and fasting 18 hours a day, but still I noticed I needed time to adjust.</p>
<p>To adjust I allowed myself to take a break from evening tech study and homelabbing and read some fiction instead, and I increased my meditation practice. Stilling the mind with breath meditation is helping me to deal with very intense food cravings. Quitting sugar is definitely no walk in the park.</p>
<p>I have made these kinds of changes many times before, and I know that after a while my body and mind are used to it and I can go back to my old routine again. Having a daily meditation practice gives me the tools to check in with myself. I am very grateful to myself that I put in the hard work over the past 6 years to get an established daily practice. I am also extremely grateful to my teacher and the Buddhist community who supported me while I spent time in a monastery in Norway.</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202304242004</p>
<p>[[buddhist-practice]]</p>
<p>[[meditation]]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
