<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Diet on Mischa van den Burg</title>
    <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/diet/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Diet on Mischa van den Burg</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/diet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Apps with web interfaces win any day, switching to MyFitnessPal</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/myfitnesspal-web-interface/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/myfitnesspal-web-interface/</guid>
      <description>Recently I was comparing apps for navigation (TopoGPS and Outdooractive). Both apps are great, but the main perk of Outdooractive is that it has a web interface. You can plan routes from your computer and access them on the iPhone app, but TopoGPS is on the iPhone only.
The app I probably have the most interaction with during the day is my calorie tracking app. I&amp;rsquo;ve been using YAZIO for about two years and it has been satisfactory, but there were a few small annoyances to the app and I was never completely satisfied with.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Recently I was comparing apps for navigation (TopoGPS and Outdooractive). Both apps are great, but the main perk of Outdooractive is that it has a web interface. You can plan routes from your computer and access them on the iPhone app, but TopoGPS is on the iPhone only.</p>
<p>The app I probably have the most interaction with during the day is my calorie tracking app. I&rsquo;ve been using YAZIO for about two years and it has been satisfactory, but there were a few small annoyances to the app and I was never completely satisfied with.</p>
<p>A missing web interface being one of them. I&rsquo;d love to be able to sit behind my 4K screen and plan out the week&rsquo;s nutrition from there instead of using the clunky copy function on my phone.</p>
<p>Enter MyFitnessPal. It has a web interface. It has charts and graphs. Me happy.</p>
<p>Why didn&rsquo;t I chose this app when I began using an app for my phone? I remember trying it out, but I was unhappy with it somehow. I remember something about the food database not containing the foods I was eating at the time. I&rsquo;ve been doing some testing and up until now I haven&rsquo;t had to add any foods.</p>
<p>I have a year&rsquo;s subscription on YAZIO until March so it is a bit of a waste, but I&rsquo;m already sold on the web interface of MFP. I have one free month of premium and I&rsquo;ll make the decision then.</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202310011810</p>
<p>[[health]]</p>
<p>[[diet]]</p>
<p>[[vegan]]</p>
<p>[[weight-loss]]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kipchoge&#39;s Diet And Calories: What Does The Fastest Marathon Runner In The World Eat?</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/kipchoge-marathon-diet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/kipchoge-marathon-diet/</guid>
      <description>Kipchoge is a Kenyan long-distance runner who competes in the marathon and is regarded as the greatest marathon runner of all time. He follows a simple diet that consists mainly of rice, potatoes, porridge, beans, and ugali, a dense maize-flour porridge. He also eats homemade bread, local fruits and vegetables, some meat, and Kenyan tea with extra sugar. He drinks a lot of water (three litres) each day and avoids indulgent foods like steak, poultry, sausages, or French fries.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kipchoge is a Kenyan long-distance runner who competes in the marathon and is regarded as the greatest marathon runner of all time. He follows a simple diet that consists mainly of <strong>rice, potatoes, porridge, beans, and ugali</strong>, a dense maize-flour porridge. He also eats homemade bread, local fruits and vegetables, some meat, and Kenyan tea with extra sugar. He drinks a lot of water (three litres) each day and avoids indulgent foods like steak, poultry, sausages, or French fries. He sometimes takes mursik, a fermented milk, to aid digestion. Before his historic sub-two-hour marathon run in 2019, he had oatmeal for breakfast.</p>
<p>His diet is mostly plant-based and high in carbohydrates and low in fat. He eats at specific times during the day and sources most of his food locally from the Eldoret region, where he trains. He likes to have ugali with lean beef and some managu, an indigenous spinach-like vegetable, or with beans and potatoes. He also likes rice and red beans, or chapati, an unleavened flatbread. When he is travelling, he prefers pasta as his carbohydrate source.</p>
<p>He works closely with his longtime coach, Patrick Sang, who understands the importance of nutrition in achieving peak performance. His nutritionist Armand Bettonviel explained the importance of carbo-loading and why marathon runners need to avoid whole grain products. Kipchoge’s diet played a critical role in his record-breaking marathon runs, including his sub-two-hour marathon in Vienna in 2019, sponsored by INEOS, and his gold medal-winning performance at the 2016 Rio Olympics.</p>
<p>According to one source, Kipchoge eats around <strong>2,300 calories</strong> on a non-race day. This is far fewer than one might think for a marathon runner who trains at high intensity and volume. However, he also consumes over <strong>100 grams of carbohydrates per hour</strong> during his race, which is a very high amount. He uses a combination of drink mixes and gels that contain easily digestible carbohydrates and hydrogel technology. This helps him maximize his energy production and performance.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s interesting to see that he eats a mainly plant based diet but still includes beef. I&rsquo;m also surprised by the high amount of carbohydrates. I&rsquo;m currently experimenting with a lower carb diet so that my body will tend to run more on fat while I&rsquo;m running, but I&rsquo;m intruiged by the fact that the world&rsquo;s fastest marathon runner is basically fueled on carbohydrates. It&rsquo;s even more surprising that he only eats around 2300 calories a day.</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202307221607</p>
<p><a href="https://bing.com/search?q=kipchoge+diet">Eliud Kipchoge</a></p>
<p><a href="https://sportsleo.com/news/2022/02/what-eliud-kipchoge-diet-plan-looks-like/">What Eliud Kipchoge diet plan looks like - SportsLeo</a></p>
<p><a href="https://olympics.com/en/news/what-olympic-marathon-hero-eliud-kipchoge-eats">A champion&rsquo;s diet: What marathon legend Eliud Kipchoge eats - Olympics.com</a></p>
<p><a href="https://runnerclick.com/eliud-kipchoge-diet/">Eliud Kipchoge’s Diet: An ‘Eat Like a Champion’ Guide!</a></p>
<p><a href="https://runningmagazine.ca/health-nutrition/kipchoges-berlin-nutrition-plan/">Kipchoge&rsquo;s Berlin nutrition plan - Canadian Running Magazine</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
