<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Diet on Mischa van den Burg</title>
    <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/diet/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Diet on Mischa van den Burg</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/diet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Apps with web interfaces win any day, switching to MyFitnessPal</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/myfitnesspal-web-interface/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/myfitnesspal-web-interface/</guid>
      <description>Recently I was comparing apps for navigation (TopoGPS and Outdooractive). Both apps are great, but the main perk of Outdooractive is that it has a web interface. You can plan routes from your computer and access them on the iPhone app, but TopoGPS is on the iPhone only.
The app I probably have the most interaction with during the day is my calorie tracking app. I&amp;rsquo;ve been using YAZIO for about two years and it has been satisfactory, but there were a few small annoyances to the app and I was never completely satisfied with.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Recently I was comparing apps for navigation (TopoGPS and Outdooractive). Both apps are great, but the main perk of Outdooractive is that it has a web interface. You can plan routes from your computer and access them on the iPhone app, but TopoGPS is on the iPhone only.</p>
<p>The app I probably have the most interaction with during the day is my calorie tracking app. I&rsquo;ve been using YAZIO for about two years and it has been satisfactory, but there were a few small annoyances to the app and I was never completely satisfied with.</p>
<p>A missing web interface being one of them. I&rsquo;d love to be able to sit behind my 4K screen and plan out the week&rsquo;s nutrition from there instead of using the clunky copy function on my phone.</p>
<p>Enter MyFitnessPal. It has a web interface. It has charts and graphs. Me happy.</p>
<p>Why didn&rsquo;t I chose this app when I began using an app for my phone? I remember trying it out, but I was unhappy with it somehow. I remember something about the food database not containing the foods I was eating at the time. I&rsquo;ve been doing some testing and up until now I haven&rsquo;t had to add any foods.</p>
<p>I have a year&rsquo;s subscription on YAZIO until March so it is a bit of a waste, but I&rsquo;m already sold on the web interface of MFP. I have one free month of premium and I&rsquo;ll make the decision then.</p>
<h2 id="links">Links:</h2>
<p>202310011810</p>
<p>[[health]]</p>
<p>[[diet]]</p>
<p>[[vegan]]</p>
<p>[[weight-loss]]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
