<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Weeknotes on Mischa van den Burg</title>
    <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/weeknotes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Weeknotes on Mischa van den Burg</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mischavandenburg.com/tags/weeknotes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2023 Week 17</title>
      <link>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/2023-week17/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mischavandenburg.com/zet/2023-week17/</guid>
      <description>Week 17 Reflection It has been a good week. Thursday was a public holiday: King&amp;rsquo;s Day. I spent it working on my new setup for making YouTube videos and doing a few chores. I let the festivities pass me by. I am more of a recluse. When I was younger I sometimes went to Amsterdam and joined the festivities. But now I derive no pleasure from large crowds of people consuming a lot of alcohol any longer.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="week-17">Week 17</h1>
<h2 id="reflection">Reflection</h2>
<p>It has been a good week. Thursday was a public holiday: King&rsquo;s Day. I spent it working on my new setup for making YouTube videos and doing a few chores. I let the festivities pass me by. I am more of a recluse. When I was younger I sometimes went to Amsterdam and joined the festivities. But now I derive no pleasure from large crowds of people consuming a lot of alcohol any longer.</p>
<h2 id="exercise--weight-loss">Exercise &amp; Weight Loss</h2>
<p>I&rsquo;m making good progress on my current weight loss goal. Here are the results since I started my latest weight loss period:</p>
<h3 id="2023-04-16">2023-04-16</h3>
<p>Waist circumference: 83cm</p>
<p>78.6kg</p>
<p>17,5% Body Fat</p>
<h3 id="2023-04-23">2023-04-23</h3>
<p>82.3cm</p>
<p>78.2kg</p>
<p>16.9%</p>
<h3 id="2023-04-30">2023-04-30</h3>
<p>77.3kg</p>
<p>81cm</p>
<p>16,4%</p>
<p>The weight loss goal is currently taking up most of my head space. It takes a lot of effort to stay on track, fight off cravings and to consistently plan and weigh all of my food. However, 2 weeks into the regime, these actions are now slowly starting to become more habitual. Eventually this will become the new norm, and it will start happening automatically, costing less energy.</p>
<p>But I&rsquo;m very happy to see that I lost 1kg and 1cm from the waist.</p>
<h3 id="running">Running</h3>
<p>I completed week 2 of my base building schedule, and I&rsquo;m making progress.</p>
<h4 id="week-16---1">Week 16 - 1</h4>
<ul>
<li>Easy Run 1 Mon 30min</li>
<li>Easy Run 2 Wed 43min</li>
<li>Easy Run 3 Thu 36,5min</li>
<li>Easy Run 4 Sun 43min</li>
<li>Long Run   Fri 50min</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Total distance: 26.15km</li>
</ul>
<h4 id="week-17---2">Week 17 - 2</h4>
<ul>
<li>Easy Run 1 Mon 37min</li>
<li>Easy Run 2 Tue 40min</li>
<li>Easy Run 3 Wed 44min</li>
<li>Easy Run 4 Thu 36min</li>
<li>Long Run 5 Sat 60min</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Total distance: 28.09km</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="content-consumed">Content Consumed</h2>
<h3 id="reading">Reading</h3>
<p>I recently finished Can&rsquo;t Hurt Me by David Goggins which was very inspirational. Should write some notes on that soon.</p>
<p>Then I continued with Finding Ultra by Rich Roll. Enjoying it a lot so far.</p>
<p>I also started re-reading one of the best books on Buddhist practice in my opinion: <a href="https://www.forestdhamma.org/ebooks/english/pdf/Uncommon_Wisdom.pdf">Uncommon Wisdom</a> by Ajahn Pannavadho. I&rsquo;ve read this book 4 times already, but it is gold every single time.</p>
<p>I increased my meditation practice from 20 minutes to 40-90 minutes a day to help with food cravings and resting the mind. Ajahn Panna&rsquo;s emphasis on identifying discontentment and kilesas is a great aid in my practice currently.</p>
<h3 id="watching">Watching</h3>
<p>I saw <a href="https://youtu.be/OJ6n5wf84as">this video</a> a year ago and it (re-)kindled the desire to start running. I&rsquo;ve been watching it a few times for motivation and inspiration.</p>
<p>I also watched a few videos on Diablo 2 Resurrected to prepare for the upcoming ladder reset. I don&rsquo;t really have time to game, but the ladder reset is always a fun time because everybody is poor and there is a better community spirit going on. I decided to make a character and do a playthrough to wind down a bit from the weight loss efforts.</p>
<p>There have been many changes to the game and it is fun to catch up on Terror Zones and the new runewords, and the new builds they enable.</p>
<h3 id="listening">Listening</h3>
<p>I listened to <a href="https://www.artofmanliness.com/character/advice/podcast-887-the-golden-rules-of-success/">The Golden Rules of Success</a>, but not much to take away from there.</p>
<p>Otherwise I&rsquo;m in a Dhamma phase, with increased meditation, so I&rsquo;ve only been listening to Ajahn Amaro&rsquo;s daily reflections and the most recent talks by Ajahn Sumedho.</p>
<p><a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/nl/podcast/amaravati-podcast-latest-dhamma-talks/id336829720">https://podcasts.apple.com/nl/podcast/amaravati-podcast-latest-dhamma-talks/id336829720</a></p>
<h2 id="links">Links</h2>
<h1 id="next-week">Next Week</h1>
<p>The upcoming week has a few intersting events:</p>
<ul>
<li>Sabaton concert on Wednesday evening. Looking forward to that!</li>
<li>Diablo 2 Resurrected Ladder season 3 starts on Thursday</li>
<li>rwxrob&rsquo;s 2023 Beginner Boost starts on Thursday</li>
</ul>
<p>Other than that my main goals and intentions are:</p>
<ul>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> Sticking to the program</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> 5 runs: 4 short 1 long</li>
<li><input disabled="" type="checkbox"> Continue meditating 40-90 minutes a day</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="links-1">Links:</h2>
<p>202304301004</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
